最后生还者 第II章
原谅不可饶恕之事
如果有一天我失去了你
If I ever were to lose you
本测评视频包含游戏完整内容的剧透
请酌情观看
我肯定会失去自我
I'd surely lose myself
我在这里找到的一切
Everything I have found hear
感谢以下赞助者：
特别鸣谢：
都不是只靠我自己
I've not found by myself
尝试吧 或许你能做到
Try and sometimes you'll succeed
脚本与配音：
成就现在的我
To make this man of me
编辑：
我丢失的一切
All my stolen missing parts
空降坐标在视频详情栏
早已不再需要
I've no need for anymore
因为我相信
'Cause I believe
我深信因我可预见
And I believe 'cause I can see
我们未来的日子
Our future days
有你与我作伴
Days of you and me
最后生还者 第II章以乔尔讲述第一部作品的结尾开场
最后生还者 第II章（The Last of Us Part II）以下简称“TLOU2”
So TLOU2 opens with Joel, discussing the ending events of the first game.
镜头聚焦在吉他的指板上
The cameras focused on the thread board of the guitar,
上面有个非常明显的标识 这在后来非常重要
which has a very distinctive symbol on it, which will be important later.
我希望大家能把这个画面印在脑海中
I want you to take a mental picture of this scene
因为我们将在整个游戏结束后再次回到这里
because it's going to come back all the way at the end of the game.
在这段乔尔与汤米的对话中
During this conversation between Joel and Tommy,
乔尔解释了他选择去救艾莉而放弃全人类的决定
Joel explains his decision to save Ellie over humanity.
其实光是这一点 在初代游戏发布的时候就有不少争议
Now even this point was one of controversy when the game first launched.
在第一部作品的结尾
You see, at the end of the first game,
就有很多人在问火萤组织到底是否有能力研发疫苗
there was a serious question as to whether or not the Fireflies would be able to develop a vaccine at all.
这也是很多人认为乔尔的行为非常合理的原因之一
It was one of the reasons that a lot of people thought that Joel's actions were highly justified.
不只在于他拯救了艾莉 他的“女儿”一样的角色
Not just in that he was saving Ellie, his "daughter character",
更在于他不想牺牲艾莉的生命
but rather that he didn't want to sacrifice Ellie's life
去搏一个不太可能成功的概率
for the sake of a cause which likely wouldn't find success any ways.
毕竟在一代里 火萤组织还是挺废物的
After all, the Fireflies in the first game are pretty damn incompetent.
他们雇了一个编外人员
They hire somebody from outside their ranks to transport,
将可能是有史以来对人类最重要的人——艾莉
who is likely the most important human being who has ever lived in the form of Ellie
一路横跨美国送到了目的地 以希望自己能研发出疫苗
all the way across the country in order to hopefully develop a vaccine.
但当你在一代作品结尾到了目的地 在医院探索的时候
But when you get there and you explore the hospital at the end of the first game,
你会发现整个流程中的很多医生对这件事情能否成功都心里没底
you find out that a lot of the doctors involved in this procedure
are unsure as to whether or not it's even possible.
毕竟这间医院里的每个人都从来没有针对这样一种真菌研发疫苗的经验
After all, literally, every single person in this hospital
is completely inexperienced in developing a vaccine for a fungus such as this.
但火萤这边认为至少机会是有的
But the Fireflies argument is that at least there's a chance.
如果让艾莉跑了
If Ellie runs off,
火萤连她大脑里的任何抗体
and they don't even attempt to extract any of the antibodies
或者管他什么能让她在被感染者咬到后还能生还的东西都没提取过
or whatever the hell his inside of her brain that allows her to survive after having a bite.
那他们就永远不会造出疫苗了
Then they will never know whether or not a vaccine is possible.
但如果他们给艾莉开颅 并至少研发出某种疫苗
But if they crack her skull open and try and develop some sort of vaccine at the very least,
那机会就总是有的
then there's a chance.
然而在续作的开头
However, in the opening for this sequel,
我们看到乔尔很自信
we see that Joel is pretty confident
认为火萤组织在尝试研发疫苗 而且认为他们是有能力做到的
that they were trying to develop a vaccine and that they likely would have been able to,
但代价是艾莉的生命
but that it would have killed her.
但我认为是汤米的表情为玩家对乔尔的决定应该有的感觉定下了基调
But it's Tommy's expression that I think sets the tone
for how the player is supposed to feel about Joel's decision.
他惊呆了 但同时又不能责怪乔尔做出的选择
He's stunned, but at the same time he can't really blame Joel for the choice that he made.
毕竟在这段开场的过后
After all, later on, in this very intro sequence,
汤米对乔尔说他也会做出同样的事情
Tommy turns to Joel and tells him that he would have done the same thing.
总之 这样的游戏开场安排非常非常重要
Regardless, the choice to open the game in this way is very, very important.
顽皮狗的编剧们希望提醒玩家乔尔都做过哪些事
The writers over at Naughty Dog wanted to remind the player of what Joel had done
并以此为之后的所有叙事内容做好铺垫
and establish that as the fulcrum from which every narrative mechanism will hinge.
在这段对话过后 汤米还是不知该作何反应
After this conversation, Tommy still unsure of how to react,
只是告诉乔尔上马 回镇子里
simply tells Joel to hop on his horse and head back into town.
说明汤米花了一点时间才得出结论
It buys Tommy some time in order to form an opinion,
同时也给了玩家一点时间进入这个世界
and it also gives the player a chance to settle back into this world.
许多游戏会在续作中急于求成
It's really common for sequels to rush into things,
开篇给玩家灌输大量新鲜不同的内容
giving the player a chance to see something new and fresh and different
而这些内容可能只有在第一部作品的梦中才能见到
that they only could have dreamed of in the first game.
然而谢天谢地 顽皮狗没有这样做
However, and thankfully Naughty Dog doesn't do this.
他们把背景一步一步构建起来
They take their time during this intro to set things up,
我觉得这点做的非常好
and I think it works very, very well.
玩家骑马穿过一段美丽的场景前往杰克逊小镇
You ride through a beautiful landscape and come up on Jackson,
此时 玩家首次能够一览杰克逊小镇全貌
and it's at this time that we get our first look at a fully realized Jackson,
在一代结尾中我们只瞥见了小镇的一隅
the city that we saw peak of at the end of the first game,
其余只能靠自己想象
but that we could only imagine.
接下来就是顽皮狗表演的时间
And I've got to hand it to Naughty Dog.
这段开篇是我在所有游戏中见过的最写实的城市之一
This opening sequence has one of the most well realized cities I've ever seen in any video game ever.
真的太棒了
It truly is fantastic.
每个NPC 每个动画 每座建筑 每个雪中的脚印都细致入微 栩栩如生
Every NPC, every animation, every building, every step in the snow is detailed and realistic.
就其沉浸感而言
As far as immersion is concerned,
我认为这是有史以来做得最强的游戏之一
I think this is one of the most fantastically effective games that's ever been created.
当玩家进入小镇内部
After you reach the inside of the city,
两人下马 汤米提出要帮乔尔把马带回马厩
Tommy and Joel hop off of their horses and Tommy offers to stow Joel's horse for him,
并对乔尔承诺把这个真相带到坟墓里去
while also saying that he'll take the truth to his grave.
这暗示了很多内容
This implies a couple of things.
其一 他好像意思是要瞒着艾莉这件事情
For one, it might seem as though he's referring directly to Ellie
因为如果艾莉发现了这个真相 会带来相当多的麻烦
that if Ellie were to find out this truth, it would cause a lot of problems.
毕竟 从艾莉的角度来看
After all, as far as Ellie is concerned,
乔尔只是在她做完一堆测试之后就出来了
Joel simply took Ellie after a bunch of tests were run,
而自己也很明显无法提供任何对疫苗研发有用的帮助
and it was clear that she was not going to be able to provide any sort of help towards a vaccine at all.
在一代游戏结尾
At the end of the first game,
很明显艾莉也看出了乔尔在撒谎
it's pretty clear that Ellie sees through this lie that Joel is telling,
或者至少她认为这里面还有其他故事
or at the very least, she expects that there's more to this story.
但碍于两人关系 她还是相信了他
For the sake of their relationship, she simply goes along with it.
然而我认为这里还在暗示另一件事情
However, I think there's another implication to this as well,
即如果小镇中其他人知道乔尔所做的事
and that is that if other people in the camp were to find out what Joel had done,
那我认为他们不会像汤米那样理解乔尔的行为
I am not so sure that they would approve of it either.
诚然我们可以坐下来唠一天一宿说一代里的火萤组织有多废柴
Again, we can talk all day about how incompetent the Fireflies were in the first game.
而这也的确是个需要讨论的问题
And I think there's a real argument to be had there.
要让我把人类的命运托付给他们
I mean, if I had to entrust them with the fate of humanity,
那还不如指望小行星撞地球一了百了
I would hop on the next asteroid off the planet.
而其实我想说的是 顽皮狗在讲述一个故事
What I mean, though, is that Naughty Dog is trying to tell his story,
他们在引导玩家以他们想要的方式来看待乔尔这个角色
and they're framing the plot points the way that they want you the player to see them.
就故事情节而言
For the sake of this story,
我们需要知道火萤组织才是尝试拯救人类的角色
it's important to understand that the Fireflies were the ones that were trying to save humanity
他们才在疫苗研发的前沿 他们最有希望能够拯救无数的生命
and were apparently on the cusp of developing a vaccine to save countless millions of lives.
同时 仍然是就TLOU2的故事情节而言
And once again, for the sake of this story, that's been told in TLOU2,
乔尔才是告吹这件事的元凶
Joel is the one that undid that.
因为如果艾莉死在了手术刀下 那至少还会有出现疫苗的机会
Again, at the very least, if Ellie had gone under the knife, there would have been a chance for a vaccine.
乔尔杀死了要给艾莉做手术 尝试研发疫苗的医生
By killing the doctors that were about to operate on Ellie and potentially develop a vaccine,
表面上拯救了他的“女儿”一样的角色
he effectively saved his "daughter figure",
但却毁了整个人类的未来
but he damned all of humanity for the rest of time.
换句话说 他这是在丢西瓜捡芝麻
In other words, he strained at a gnat but swallowed a camel.
他用一个看似较小的恶换取一个大得多的恶
He traded what seemed to be a smaller evil for a much much larger evil,
他这样做是因为他的判断被自己的个人愿望和意志所蒙蔽
and he did this because his judgment was clouded by his own personal wants and wishes.
这并不是说在这个场景中 乔尔可能或者已经对这些感到后悔
This isn't to say that Joel would or does regret any of this in this particular sequence.
而是说游戏希望玩家从现在开始认真思考
But it is to say that the players should start seriously considering
乔尔的行为是否是合理的 甚至于这件事是否是正义的
whether or not Joel's actions were justified, or perhaps even whether or not they were right.
不过不用急
But don't worry,
顽皮狗会带你不断回忆艾莉在杰克逊小镇长大的经历 从而帮你思考这个问题
Naughty Dog is going to help you think about this by constantly bringing it up using flashbacks
as Ellie grew up in Jackson.
而且我保证在你知道答案之前
And I promise you before you know it,
你甚至会相信乔尔实际上是个反派
you might even be convinced that Joel is in fact a villain.
我不是希望玩家都去恨他或者想让他死
This isn't to say that Joel is unlikable character that you should hate him or wish that he were dead,
而是让大家知道 乔尔才是毁灭人类前途的人
but rather Joel is the one that damned humanity.
如果你跟别人说有人为了某一个人而毁灭整个人类的命运
If you tell any other story and there's a character which damns humanity for the sake of one single person,
那我们只是可能会说他是个坏人
we would say he's a bad guy.
或者甚至不一定是坏
Or perhaps we wouldn't even say bad guy,
也可能单纯说他是个不理智的 或者可能是被误解的 动机很复杂的人
we would simply say that he was a confused or perhaps mistaken individual,
whose motivations were complex.
重点在于 人不是非好即恶的
But the point is, it's not as simple as hero and villain.
事情不是非黑即白的
There is a lot of gray in between.
接下来这段开场情节是在乔尔刚到后不久 艾莉还很年轻
Now this intro sequence is just shortly after Joel's arrival, while Ellie is still young.
她住在房子后面的附属房里 房子大概是乔尔的
She's living out of grandmother's suite in the back of the house that is presumably owned by Joel.
女孩有自己的小天地是件很温馨的事情
It's super cute that she has her own space,
但这还是向我们透露了很多两人关系的信息
but it even now shows and tells a lot about their relationship.
诚然 乔尔这样一个中年大叔遇到了这个小女孩
Now granted, Joel is a middle aged man that found this little girl,
带她横穿了整个美国
and he took her halfway across the country,
把她从食人族里救出来
rescued her from a bunch of cannibals,
现在两人回到了乔尔弟弟和嫂子运营的小镇里
and now has her in a town that his brother runs with his wife.
可以认为艾莉住在乔尔家是还算合适的
It could be presumed that her staying in his house could be considered an appropriate.
但我觉得重点不在此
But I don't think that's the point here.
乔尔是艾莉的“父亲”角色 我觉得这没什么争议
Joel is Ellie's "father figure", and I don't think that's a controversial thing to say.
而艾莉希望和乔尔保持距离这件事则有很深的含义
The fact that Ellie wants space, physical space separated from him means a lot.
总之 玩家可以看到艾莉正在画画
Regardless, we see Ellie and she's drawing something
她画的东西会在游戏后来内容中反复出现
that will come back time and time again throughout the rest of the game.
艾莉实际上很有艺术天赋
She's actually pretty artsy and gifted, artistically,
从游戏全程都能随时翻看的笔记本中玩家就能发现这点
you'll see this in the note book that you'll be using throughout the course of the main game.
她经常把她看到的不同事物画下来
She often draws pictures of what she sees or sketches out different things
从而帮助自己回忆起那个地方
in order to remind her to return to that area
抑或是单纯地记录主线故事的事件
or simply to keep a journal of the events and happenings of the main story.
乔尔进来时她正在听音乐
She's listening to music when Joel comes in.
气氛可爱得有点尬 但又甜得掉牙
It's a really cute and awkward moment, but it's pretty damn sweet.
大家都能看出这里的气氛有些紧张
It doesn't take a body language expert to see that there's a lot of tension here.
乔尔站也不自在 坐也不自在 讲话有一搭没一搭地聊着艾莉的事情
Joel's unsure of how to stand, where to move, how to talk, how to relate to her,
而艾莉也发现了这一点
and Ellie picks up on this as well.
所以气氛真的很紧张
The tension is really palpable.
他们都知道犹他州的问题还没有解决
一代游戏结尾圣玛莉医院位于犹他州盐湖城
They both know what happened in Utah hasn't been resolved,
但都不知道如何去展开这个话题
but neither knows how to broach the topic,
所以两人只是简单地敷衍攀谈
so they simply delay it and push it off.
但这一段情节的重点是乔尔要表达艾莉在他的生活中是多么重要
But the point of this sequence is where Joel to express how much he needs Ellie in his life.
让我们花些时间放松一下 用心感受接下来这段场景的美
Let's all just take a moment to relax and appreciate how beautiful the scenery is,
以及艾莉极具个人特色的回复
and how Ellie responds in classic Ellie fashion.
如果有一天我失去了你
If I ever were to lose you
我肯定会失去自我
I'd surely lose myself
我在这里找到的一切
Everything I have found hear
都不是只靠我自己
I've not found by myself
尝试吧 或许你能做到
Try and sometimes you'll succeed
成就现在的我
To make this man of me
我丢失的一切
All my stolen missing parts
早已不再需要
I've no need for anymore
因为我相信
'Cause I believe
我深信因我可预见
And I believe 'cause I can see
我们未来的日子
Our future days
有你与我作伴
Days of you and me
乔尔：还不错吧。
Joel: There you go.
艾莉：嗯……
Ellie: Well…
不难听。
that didn't suck.
乔尔：我就当作是夸奖了。
Joel: I'll take what I can get.
不用我来提醒大家
And I'm sure I don't need to tell you this
这首歌将要在主线故事中一次又一次地出现
but this song is going to come up time and time again throughout the course of the main story.
所以请大家务必记好
So make sure that you remember it.
但我觉得也用不着提醒 毕竟这歌动听到你可能这辈子都忘不掉
Though I'm sure I don't need to tell you that because you'll likely remember this for the rest of your life.
considering how unbelievably touching it was.
另外一个有趣的知识点是 在编剧尼尔·德鲁克曼的推特里
Also a funny little thing that Neil Druckmann tweeted out.
很多人都问过他为什么这首Pearl Jam的歌曲《Future Days》会出现在游戏中
Apparently he had been asked many many times on Twitter and in person
why Pearl Jam's "Future Days" was used in the game.
大家问这个问题的原因是这首歌在2013年10月才正式公开
People ask this because the song didn't actually drop until October of 2013 officially.
但这是在TLOU的世界观中疫情爆发后一个月的事情
And that is actually a month after outbreak day in this universe,
所以这首歌是不应该出现的
so it shouldn't have actually existed.
尼尔·德鲁克曼回应说
Neil Druckmann responded by saying,
感谢您的提问！其实……这首歌在专辑发布的几个月
之前就在YouTube上有一场Live了。
甚至还有YouTube的链接
And you can actually go look it up on Youtube,
而且Pearl Jam也的确参演了这场Live
and sure enough, Pearl Jam performed this live,
而该视频发布于2013年7月26日
and that video was posted on July, 26th of 2013.
也的确是视频的发布时间
That's the actual date of the video.
这是顽皮狗专注于细节的一个完美例子
It's a perfect example of Naughty Dog's excessive attention to detail.
我觉得就算这首歌是在游戏中疫情爆发后三年才发布也不会有人较真此事
I don't think anybody would have cared, particularly if this song released three years after outbreak day.
但实际上 顽皮狗自己找到了符合游戏情感基调的歌曲
But the fact that they took it upon themselves to find a song that fit the theme and the tone of the game
完美匹配乔尔和艾莉的关系
and that fits so perfectly within Joel and Ellie's relationship,
然后回头去确认这首歌的时间线符合游戏的内容
and then to also make sure that it fit in with the timeline they were dealing with it.
太不可思议了
It's unbelievable.
这也再次证明了顽皮狗的完美主义
But once again its one of the examples of Naughty Dog's perfectionism.
他们完全没必要在意这些小事 但他们的确在意
They don't need to care about these little things, but they do.
这也让顽皮狗成为独一无二的制作组 无论你喜不喜欢他们
And that's what sets them apart, whether you love them or hate them.
在这段温馨的闪回过后 镜头切到起晚了的艾莉
After this touching flashback, we cut to Ellie, waking up late.
一位我们之后在游戏中会讲到的角色——杰西
Jesse, a character we'll get to see a little bit throughout the course of the game
咣咣咣敲门吵醒了艾莉
is at her front door, giving her crap for sleeping in.
在接下来的十分钟里 当你漫步经过这个小镇时
Over the next ten or so minutes as you walk through the town,
你会亲身感受2018年E3预告片里的各种内容
you have a recap of everything that went down and then some in the trailer from E3 2018.
而我发现比较有趣的一点是
Now I found this particularly interesting,
那段蒂娜和艾莉首次接吻的镜头
because that sequence where Dina and Ellie share their first kiss,
我本以为会是一段非常重要的场景
I thought was a pretty important sequence to see.
但顽皮狗却并没有展现给玩家 至少现在还没有
But Naughty Dog doesn't show it to the player, at least not right now.
取而代之的是两人用对话叙述了发生的事情
Instead, they rely on the dialog to explain what happened,
但玩到这我不禁发现
but I can't help to notice that
这是第一个预告片对游戏本身的背景把握起重要作用的例子
this is the first instance where trailers are important to a contextual grasp of the game itself.
因为在这个场景中
Because, after all, in this case,
两人谈论的画面在游戏结束前15分钟以前 一直没有直接展现给玩家
the scene that's being discussed isn't actually shown to the player
until the last 15 or so minutes of the game.
之前预告片展示的东西要么多次大幅改变 要么改变位置
Time and time again, stuff that was shown in the trailers is either changed drastically or is moved around
导致你必须看过预告片才能真正理解发生了什么
such that you need to have seen the trailer in order to truly understand what's going on.
当然我觉得这不算是一件令人困扰的大事
Now I understand that it's a small thing to point out or be frustrated by,
毕竟绝大多数买了游戏的人可能都看过预告片
because after all chances are every single person who bought the game had seen that trailer.
但我仍然觉得在预告片中展示一个场景
However, I still think it's strange to show a scene in a trailer,
却在游戏正作中只让角色讨论此事而不展示 是一件奇怪的事情
but then not show it in the game when that item is being discussed.
这在这部游戏中发生过很多次
It's one of countless times in this game,
顽皮狗会拿出一段内容 切成十几段
when Naughty Dog will take a sequence, cut it up into fifteen different parts
然后随机分散在整部游戏故事当中
and then spread it randomly, seemingly throughout the course of the story.
有时我会想这可能有助于叙事节奏
Sometimes I think it helps with pacing
因为这可以让玩家从非常紧张焦灼的游戏中解脱出来
by giving the player a break from a very stressful environment or activity,
但更多的时候这样的处理会让人感觉突兀
but often it feels as though it's jarring and out of nowhere.
不用着急 我们在故事的后面会讲到一些这样的反面例子
But don't worry, we're going to get to some very egregious examples of this later on in the story.
总之大家要知道的就是艾莉和蒂娜两人第一次亲吻了对方
All that's really important to understand is that Ellie and Dina shared a first kiss,
然后我们刚刚遇到的这位角色说了些不太好听的、偏执的话
a character that we meet briefly, said something offensive and bigoted,
而且大家也都希望你能知道他说的话太偏执了
and everybody wants you to know that it's bigoted.
然后人家给你一些三明治作为赔礼 你就收拾出发巡逻去了
You get some sandwiches and then you go off to start on patrol.
大家还要知道的是 杰西刚刚和蒂娜分手不久
It's also important to understand that Jesse just broke up with Dina
发生在大约7到10天之前
around a week to a week and a half before this is taking place.
也可能是蒂娜提的分手 也可能是俩人各走各的
Or maybe Dina broke up with him, or maybe it was mutual.
我也不太懂这些……男男女女卿卿我我这些……可太痛苦了
I don't know, it… it's so high school…  these first few conversations. It's kind of painful.
杰西先去马厩准备巡逻用的马匹和家伙事
Jessie heads off to the stable to prepare the horses and the rest of the attendees.
而蒂娜与艾莉和一帮小屁孩打了一场雪仗
While Dina and Ellie shared a snowball fight against a bunch of kids.
我个人感觉这段雪仗怪怪的
Now I kind of found this snowball fight to be a little weird
因为它设计明显是作为战斗教学用的
because it seemed as though it's meant to serve as some sort of combat introduction.
当然也可能是我过度解读了 因为我感觉这段教学做的并不好
But I think I was just reading too much into it because I don't think it does a very good job of that.
我后来还玩了二周目
Now I did go back through the game a second time,
选择“新游戏+” 困难难度
as I stated previously on "New Game +" and on the hardest difficulty.
在玩过整部游戏对操作完全熟悉之后
After becoming completely familiarized with the controls after playing the entire game,
这场雪仗就感觉比我第一次玩时候的体验要有意思多了
this whole snowball fight was much more intriguing and interesting and frankly fun
than it was the first time I played.
本作中艾莉有三种姿态 分别是站立 蹲下和匍匐
The three tiered stance that Ellie's able to have between standing, crouch and prone
这需要一点时间来适应
is something that takes a minute to get used to.
虽然说很多第三人称游戏和第一人称射击游戏都有这三个动作
I know it sounds weird because that's true of pretty much any third person or first person shooter
that they're going to have those three stances.
但在TLOU2中 这三个动作会衍生出大量其他动作
But in TLOU2, there are multiple levels of movement associated with each.
这也正是我觉得奇怪的点
And that's more of my point.
这段游戏内容并没有充分介绍游戏角色的这三种动作
The sequence does a very poor job of introducing the player to those three stances.
但却可以在这段游戏场景中使用它们
But you are able to use each of those three stances in this sequence.
所以看起来就有点不搭调
It just seems a little jarring,
但我还是要承认他们在这段场景中付出的努力
but I will admit I appreciate the effort that they put into this
因为还是要比其他游戏的新手教学强多了
because it's still way better than the alternative,
不用像大家刻板印象里那样主角学习瞄准射击
which would be to have the standard stereotypical sequence
where the protagonist goes and has shown how to use a gun,
还要射瓶瓶罐罐一些东西……我可烦死这些了
and it's like issue bottles or some craps…  I hate that.
我觉得最反面典型的就是辐射3开场拿着BB枪那段
Probably the most egregious example would be the opening of Fallout 3 when you're given a BB gun,
下楼拿枪射一些目标 还爬出来几只巨型蟑螂
and then you go downstairs, shoot some targets and then some giant radroaches.
我觉得这太离谱了
I just think that that's so overplayed.
你如果想向玩家介绍射击和战斗系统
If you're going to introduce shooting mechanics and combat,
那你好歹得稍微加一点点创意进去
you should at the very least have a little bit of a creative spin to it,
因此我还是很欣赏TLOU2里和孩子们打雪仗的这段内容
so I appreciate that throwing compacted snow at children was presented here.
玩了一身雪之后你和蒂娜一起去了马厩
After hucking some powder you meet up with Dina,
然后又是一些尴尬得让艾莉很难接的对话……
there's some awkward exchanges where Ellie isn't sure how to talk to…
真的 我都不懂这些的
I mean again, it… it's very high school.
然后两人走出马厩开始了巡逻
The two walks out the stables and you head out on patrol.
然后游戏的第一个惊喜就扑面而来了
Then the first surprise of the game hits,
说实话我觉得即使对于被提前剧透的玩家来说也够惊喜的
and to be honest, it's a surprise, even if you had the game spoiled for you.
镜头缓缓从几个睡觉的青年人上方略过
You see the camera slowly pans over a bunch of sleeping young adults.
最终定格在一个女孩身上
It centers on one girl
很多玩家一下就认出了她是2017年巴黎游戏周上预告片里的主角
who most of us will immediately recognize from the Paris Games trailer from 2017.
她起来后和一个年轻男子聊了几句 男子说要给她看些东西
She gets up talks to a young man who asks to show her something,
然后我们就开始控制她了
and then we are given control of her.
我之前说过 我也是玩游戏前就被剧透了的
Like I said earlier, I had the game spoiled for me.
但这些剧透说的都是你将要从游戏中间开始到结束的后半段里控制埃比
But all of those spoilers said that you were going to get to play half of the game as Abby
and start halfway through.
我完全没想到会在游戏开始半小时到45分钟内就能操控她
I did not expect to be playing as her within the first 30 to 45 minutes.
我敢说这时候可能就已经有一些人不玩了
I bet you, at this point, some people had put the game down.
毕竟总有个别少数人说这代整个游戏要是不操控乔尔和艾莉就把盘掰了
After all, there was a very vocal minority that said
that they were going to flip out if you didn't play the whole game as Ellie and or Joel.
但这里要知道的关键是 玩家必须在游戏上投入时间和精力 来让游戏证明自己
But a key thing to understand here is that the player must give it time and effort
to stand on its own and justify itself.
就好像你不能单纯从一本书的封面或者一部电影的预告来做出判断一样
In the same way that you can't judge a book by its cover or a film by its trailer.
不试试的话你永远无法给出对这部游戏的客观看法
You'll never get an informed opinion of the game if you don't give it a chance.
这并不是说你必须把每个游戏都玩一遍才能对每一个游戏有看法
This isn't to say that you have to play every single game in order to have an opinion of every single game,
而是说如果你对一个游戏有极其消极或批评的看法
but rather that if you're going to have an extremely negative or critical opinion of a game,
你首先必须要有合理的自证
you have to be able to justify that critical opinion.
在我看来 游玩游戏封面上没有的角色
And in my opinion, I don't think it's fair to say that playing as any character
就说这游戏不好不值得浪费时间 是一件不公平的事情
other than the one on the Box-Art is bad and means that the game is terrible and not worth your time.
在开始操控埃比后 你穿过树林
After you take control of Abby and you start exploring through the woods,
踩过深深的积雪
walking through some pretty deep snow,
看到了一些不错的景色
seeing some interesting landscapes,
俩人聊了聊团队里的其他人
these two characters share in some dialogue about other people in the group,
很可能就是刚刚镜头扫过的那几位
likely the same people that you just saw the camera pan over.
现在的情况是这些人玩家一个都不认识 而顽皮狗经常玩这一套
Now we don't know any of these people at this point and Naughty Dog will do this a lot.
他们觉得可以插入一些毫无解释的突兀的对话
They are unapologetic in their unexplained dialogue.
角色们会自己进行他们看起来可能合理的对话
The characters will have conversations that makes sense to them,
也可能是不合理的对话 甚至对玩家来讲完全离谱的对话
but might not, or perhaps don't make any sense at all to the player.
我其实很喜欢这点
Now I love this,
虽然我承认对于更喜欢被动接受对话内容的玩家来说这可能会很迷惑
though I do admit that it can be confusing to those who like to enjoy their content more passively.
但这是一部叙事导向的游戏
But this is a narrative game,
很多这类游戏的对话看起来都是这样的
it seems like it comes with the territory of this type of game to have dialogue
这让角色更加真实 更加接地气
that's much more realistic and grounded
而不是一股脑把对话和信息塞给你
compared to dialogue that just hit you over the head with exposition.
另外我一定要告诉大家 二周目再看这些对话的时候体验真的棒极了
I also think it's important to note that these conversations make a second run of the game AWESOME.
真的 他们讨论的每一件事
Seriously, every single thing they are discussing here,
都是合理的、前后相关联的
it makes perfect sense and is relatable and understandable.
当你通关一次 见过了所有这些角色
Once you've gone through the whole game and met all of these characters
认识了他们 并随着故事流程慢慢开始关心他们
and grown to know them and care about them throughout the course of the story,
作为一个测评游戏前至少要通关两次的人
and as somebody that usually placed their games that I critique at least two times,
我真的很喜欢这样的对话设计
I really appreciated this because it made it.
因此我在二周目里获得了更多的信息 对剧情也更加感兴趣
So my second run through was more informed and more interesting than my first run through.
真的 我强烈建议大家试试玩玩二周目
Really, I think you should play the game a second time through just to give it a shot.
你会惊讶自己之前竟然错过如此多的细节
I think you'll be surprised at how many little things were added that you didn't hear before.
但对于第一次玩来说
But for the sake of a first run through,
我们要记住这两个人的名字 女的叫埃比 男的叫欧文
it's important to note that Abby and Owen are the names of these two characters,
他们看上去曾有过一段感情经历
they seem to have a previous relationship.
换句话说 俩人之前曾经有过一段浪漫的爱情
In other words, they dated at some sort of romantic involvement at some point.
另外 那位现在和欧文在一起的 叫梅尔的女子 怀孕了
And also that some girl named Mel, who Owen is apparently involved with at this point, is pregnant.
我不知道是不是只有我这样
There may be, I'm all alone in this,
但当我听到梅尔怀孕的事情时 我的心都跟着紧了一下
but the second I heard she was pregnant, I got a pit in my stomach.
我在第一次玩这部游戏的时候发推想表达的就是这个意思
This is what I meant when I tweeted out early in my first run through of the game
即我感觉游戏的开场太压抑了
that I felt as though the opening was dreadful.
真的是字面意思 我感觉整个游戏都充满了压抑与恐惧
I meant it in the purest sense of the word that the game fills you with dread.
你潜意识里就感觉要发生一些糟糕的事情了
You have a sinking feeling in your stomach that something terrible is about to happen.
我不知道是不是因为游戏之前被剧透了 所以大家都有所预见
and I don't know if it's just that the game was spoiled and so everybody saw this coming,
还是说游戏绝佳的台词与场景设计渲染了这种气氛
or that it's some sort of masterful way that they designed all of these conversations and scenes
让你自然而然有一种不祥的预感
that makes you feel as though there's an impending danger and doom.
我不确定是哪种
I don't know which it is.
欢迎在评论区谈谈你的看法 或者在推特艾特我@LukeStephensTV
I would love to hear your opinion of it down in the comments section below or tweeted at me @LukeStephensTV.
总之我还是忍不住觉得一切可能发生的可怕事情都要发生了
But nonetheless I can't help but feel as though everything terrible that could happen is about to happen.
所以当我听到那个叫梅尔的女子怀孕了的时候
And so when I heard that this girl, Mel, was pregnant,
我就预感到她要遭难了
I just knew something horrible was going to happen to her
而且在我们还没介绍到的艾莉这边阵营中的某个人
and likely that one of the characters we were being introduced to on Ellie's side of the fence
也会怀孕 从而作为两边角色的对比
would likely become pregnant to contrast the two relationships
建立戏剧冲突 让一个角色面临一个选择
and to set up narrative beats where you could have one character faced with an option,
让另一个角色面临另一个选择
have the other character faced with the other option
看看他们在各自的时刻如何反应
and see how each reacts in their individual moments.
当然了 如果玩家此时还没通关游戏的话肯定对我说的话摸不着头脑
But I understand that they likely doesn't make any sense at all
if you haven't played through the game yourself,
所以我就继续讲 稍后再回过头来看这件事
so I'm simply going to move on and loop back to it later.
绝对说得通
I promise it'll make sense.
埃比和欧文到达了目的地 俯瞰整个杰克逊小镇
Abby and Owen reach their destination, and they overlook Jackson.
这个小镇真的很大
It's a massive city.
从埃比的反应来看 她应该没想到会这么大
And judging Abby's reaction, it seems as though she didn't expect it to be this massive at all.
目前还不知道他们在找什么 但肯定是个男子
It's not clear what they're looking for, but it's a man for sure.
用脚后跟去想都应该马上知道他俩找的肯定是乔尔了
any one with two brain cells to rub together will instantly know
that they're talking about and looking for Joel
虽然这个时刻我们还并不知道
though we don't know why at this particular moment.
接着欧文说他觉得他们不应该继续找下去了
Now Owen doesn't think that they should continue on this quest to reach whoever they're looking for
因为他们无论如何也没法摸进这座小镇
because they obviously aren't going to be able to infiltrate Jackson no matter how hard they try.
他们团队人不多 完全做不到
They're a small group and they aren't going to be able to do it.
所以欧文建议原路返回
So he thinks that they should just turn back.
尤其当下梅尔还怀孕了 他们需要回去照顾她
Especially since Mel is now pregnant, they need to return to take care of her.
请记住这个场景
Again remember this plot point,
这个男的 欧文 想要回去照顾因他而怀孕的女子
Owen, the dude, wants to turn back to make sure that he can take care of the woman that he impregnated.
你可能很奇怪为什么记住这种随机事件
It seems like a weird, random thing to say.
但在游戏剧情后面我们还要遇到类似的场面
But this is something that's going to be repeated later in the story,
当中艾莉会做出和埃比此刻做出的、同样愚蠢的决定
and Ellie is going to be making the same decision that Abby makes in this moment, a stupid one.
顽皮狗会在剧情中加入大量类似的操作
Naughty Dog will do this a lot throughout the course of the main story
先让埃比做某件事 然后换个时间地点场景
where they will have Abby do something and then change it with a fresh coat of paint
让艾莉做一遍同样的事情
and have Ellie do the same exact thing.
但你会不由自主地、双标地认为艾莉的行为更加正当
But you can't help feel as though Ellie is more justified in her actions,
认为埃比只是一个反派角色
while Abby is just a bad villainess character.
这个游戏就是靠不同视角来叙事的
This game is all about perspectives
这种频繁的视角切换是游戏叙事机制中的重要组成部分
and this flip flopping that they do constantly is an important piece of that narrative mechanism.
现在我自己肯定不想回头
Now I'll be obviously doesn't want to turn back.
他们到这里可能花了几天、几周甚至几个月
They've traveled, presumably for days, weeks and even months to get to where they are now
眼看杰克逊小镇就在眼前了却说要回去
and simply to turn around upon seeing the city of Jackson.
听着就不是啥好主意
It doesn't seem like it's a good option.
欧文说他们应该回他们目前所待的别墅屋里
Owen says that they should return back to the mansion they're staying at.
但埃比并不喜欢他的建议
But Abby doesn't like their recommendation,
她很生气 独自一人向杰克逊小镇前进
and she starts to become enraged, and she pushes on herself towards Jackson,
想去欧文发现的地方找找看有没有巡逻队
trying to find a patrol that was traveling that Owen spotted
从他们口中就能问出目标在哪
in order to get them to tell her where their target is,
这样她就能在回去之前独自完成该做的任务了
so that she can finish the job herself before returning back to wherever they came from.
在控制埃比的时候 一场暴风雪正慢慢形成
Controlling Abby, you push forward into an impending storm.
你杀了几个感染者 最后发现了一组巡逻队留下的马蹄印
You fight some zombies and you eventually find some tracks from one of the patrols.
这些巡逻队是由诸如艾莉、蒂娜、杰西、乔尔和汤米等等一些人组成的
These patrols are the same ones that characters such as Ellie, Dina, Jesse, Joel and Tommy are all on,
这是游戏早期为游戏叙述做铺垫而设定的大量巧合中的第一个
and this is the first of a plethora of coincidences in the early hours of the game that set up its narrative,
埃比恰好困于暴风雪
the coincidence that Abby happened to be driven into a rage
而同时乔尔和其他人恰好在外巡逻
at the same time that Joel and everyone else happens to be out on patrol.
这类的巧合还会有很多
It's going to happen a lot.
乔尔和汤米是同一年龄段的
Joel is an old man as his Tommy,
而且至少是和他们一起巡逻的年轻人的长辈
at the very least older than all the youngsters that they have out on the patrols with them.
在我看来 乔尔仍然去巡逻这件事就有点牵强
The fact that Joel is still going on patrols is, in my opinion, a bit of a stretch.
让他去巡逻本身就很蠢
It would be stupid for him to go on patrols,
尤其他还在小镇中扮演领导角色
especially because he has a leadership position within the city.
这点从他家超级大的房子就能看出
His super fancy house, I think, serves as proof positive of that,
更不用提他的弟弟汤米也要和他一起巡逻这件事
Not to mention that Tommy, his brother, who was also going out on patrols with him,
而汤米也算是杰克逊小镇的领导者
has a leadership position within the city.
汤米和他的妻子共同运营着小镇
In many ways, Tommy runs the city along with his wife.
所以在我看来 乔尔和汤米一起外出巡逻这样的安排有点牵强
So to me, it just seems like a bit of a stretch
that Tommy and Joel would be going out on patrols at all.
但我也能理解 或许乔尔和汤米就是想继续闯荡 干些脏活累活
But I understand that perhaps Joel or Tommy just want to get out and get their hands dirty.
他们不想让人觉得自己老了 他们想继续为小镇做点贡献
They don't want to feel old, they don't want to feel as though they can't contribute,
所以他们想出去巡逻 亲力亲为
so they want to go out and do things themselves.
这样想来倒还算合理
I understand that perhaps that's justifiable.
但我还是不禁觉得乔尔和汤米的巡逻路线
But I can't help feel as though Joel and Tommy being out on patrols
和艾莉、蒂娜与杰西的路线完全相同
the same patrol routes that Ellie Dina and Jesse are taking
纯粹是制作者有意设定的
was purely designed,
这样可以确保埃比在森林中迷路时能够遇到乔尔和汤米
and established that way to make sure
that Abby would be able to encounter Joel and Tommy while she randomly ran through the forest.
这也是我不喜欢叙事上强凑巧合的原因
And this is the reason that I don't like narrative coincidences.
这一般只是为了给编剧提供能让角色进入某种平常不合理的情况的一种方式
Often it's just to give a way
that the writers are trying to force characters into normally unjustifiable situations.
这并不都是坏事
But it's not always a bad thing.
实际上我觉得有些情况下 巧合可以引出一些很有趣的场景
In fact, in some cases, I think these coincidences can lead to some really interesting sequences.
版权规避 此处打码
就比如《绝命毒师》里的那段场景
I mean, look at that scene from Breaking Bad.
简的父亲在酒吧遇到沃尔特
Where Jane's father runs into Walt at a bar.
他们简单聊了聊为父之道、聊了聊孩子
They share a short conversation about fatherhood, about kids,
而他们完全不会想到他们聊的两个角色
and they don't realize that they're talking about two characters, in this case, Jesse and Jane,
会共同卷入一段过山车式的剧情当中
who are inextricably tied and who are about to go on a roller coaster together.
看过这个剧的朋友可能已经知道之后发生了什么
For those of you who have seen the show and know what happens right after this meeting,
所以应该能明白我说的过山车式剧情是什么意思
you are going to probably think roller coaster is a bit of an understatement.
但……我不想给大家剧透……所以……
But… I didn't want to spoil it, so…
我想说的是 快去看《绝命毒师》 老好看了
The point is, go watch Breaking Bad, it's awesome.
另一方的观点认为叙事上的巧合是可以接受的
The other point is that narrative coincidences can be fine.
毕竟生活中到处都充满了巧合
After all, coincidences do happen in real life all the time.
但当巧合被用来强行让角色做他们本来不会做的事情以完成某种情节时候
The problem comes when they are used to make characters do things they wouldn't otherwise be doing
问题就出来了
in order to fulfill some sort of plot point.
同样的我还很讨厌故事中强塞的“灵媒”或者“预言”
It's the same reason I hate psychics or prophecies in stories
这样纯粹就是犯懒
because I think that they're just lazy.
作者预先知道自己想让角色去哪做什么
The writers know that they want a character to go and do something,
于是就胡编个预言提前解释一下要发生什么
so they write some sort of prophecy to explain how it's going to happen,
再让他们的角色身上的预言应验
and then they make sure that they have characters that fit around that prophecy.
如果剧情有点乱
And if it's a little messy,
或者叙事上、角色上、动机上不太合理
or if it doesn't seem to be totally justified narratively or in terms of the characters, motivations,
那就直接说那个角色在依照预言行事
they simply explain it by way of while he or she was fulfilling the prophecy.
所以就得那样做
It had to happen.
预言说啥就是啥
It must have happened because the prophecy stated.
老懒狗了
It's just lazy.
虽然我觉得TLOU2中的许多巧合无厘头到了犯罪的地步
And while I feel as though many of the instances of coincidences in TLOU2,
are not justifiable and are a grievous offences,
但我认为其他的事件还算说得通
I think that other instances are more justifiable and could be explained.
但到头来发现这些事件又剪不断 理还乱
But eventually they become so many that stack up on top of each other.
因此看起来如果顽皮狗想让乔尔遇到埃比
It just seems as though Naughty Dog need Joel to run into Abby,
那这就是最快最干净的实现这个目标的方法
and this was the fastest, cleanest way that they could figure out how to do that.
我在之前的一期YouTube上的NitGrit节目中
In a previous episode of NitGrit, a show that I do here on Youtube,
就讨论过了TLOU2里的叙事巧合
I discussed narrative coincidences in TLOU2,
这些巧合都被塞进了TLOU2的前两小时内容中 让人没法不注意到
and I couldn't help but notice that they were all front loaded in the opening hour or two of TLOU2.
我抛砖引玉想出了另一种开篇剧情
I threw out a potential intro that they could have swapped where, for instance,
埃比 欧文和其它某些团队成员
Abby, Owen and perhaps a few other members of her crew
潜入小镇 努力干活 人人爱戴
infiltrated Jackson working with the people being welcomed in
并最终获得了乔尔、汤米和艾莉的信任
and eventually earning the trust of Joel and Tommy, and Ellie
最终反水 杀死乔尔 并趁夜色逃跑
until eventually they turned on everybody, killed Joel and escape in the middle of the night,
然后游戏剩余部分和原来一样进行
while the game then carries out just like it would have otherwise,
这样也可以会很有意思 比如让埃比和艾莉建立一段很牢固的友谊
it could have been really interesting because Abby and Ellie could have even formed a friendship,
或者至少对彼此有某种同情的感觉
or at least some sort of sympathetic position towards each other,
从而让之后的背叛显得更加深刻
which would have made the betrayal all the worse.
而且即使现在 汤米和乔尔也很欢迎这群人
I mean, as of right now, Tommy and Joel are very welcoming to this group.
二人甚至还邀请他们回杰克逊小镇补给一下再继续上路
They even invite them back to Jackson to restock on supplies before leaving
之后才发生了“那样”的事
right before you know the thing happens.
所以我们能看出汤米和乔尔是很开放的
So we know that Tommy and Joel are welcoming.
他们本打算把这伙人带来小镇 或者只带一两位进来
They would have brought this group in, at least for a little bit.
或许他们进入小镇后
Perhaps if they came in,
可以装作是想要从零开始新生活却不知所措、需要帮助的幸存者
they pretended to be wandering survivors simply in need of assistance in a new fresh start.
或许他们可以开始在杰克逊小镇干几周的活
Perhaps then they go when they work at Jackson for a few weeks,
或者只干几天就反水杀害乔尔然后逃跑
Or maybe even just a couple of days before turning and killing Joel and escaping.
至少这样安排 剧情上就不需要强凑那么多的巧合了
At the very least, then you don't have to rely on a bunch of coincidences.
但我也了解这样或许不利于叙事节奏
But I do understand that it might have been bad for pacing
尤其在游戏发售之前还发生了剧情泄露事件
and especially considering the leaks that happened towards the game's release.
我觉得目前或许的确是最好的选择
It seems as though is probably for the best.
因为一旦游戏被剧透了
because once the game was spoiled,
我们都早已知道埃比会杀死乔尔
we all knew that Abby was going to kill Joel
那一开始艾莉和埃比在开篇的友谊或者至少相互容忍的情节就会被完全否定
so that would have completely negated the opening sequence
where Abby and Ellie are starting to bond, or perhaps at least tolerating each other.
我在推特和邮件中听到过很多人说
I've heard from various people on Twitter and through Email
顽皮狗的确考虑过类似的内容作为开篇
that Naughty Dog was actually considering this as an opening,
这还是挺有意思的 因为这纯粹是我凭空脑补的
which is funny because I just let it roll off my dome,
我甚至没太认真去想
I wasn't actually thinking that hard.
但显然这是一个经过认真考虑过的开篇内容
But apparently this was a seriously considered intro sequence
不过没有正式出现在TLOU2游戏中
instead of what we got in the end product of TLOU2,
他们当前的叙事决策应该是因为其他版本会有很多叙事节奏上的问题
But they decided to go in this current direction because the other version ran into a lot of pacing issues.
换句话说 你很可能需要在游戏的前五六个小时在杰克逊做一些琐碎的杂事
In other words, you likely would have needed to spend
the first five or six hours of the game in Jackson doing menial chores
在被背叛之前了解了埃比和她的小队成员
while getting to know Abby and her crew before being betrayed,
这将完全改变游戏其余部分的结构
it would have completely changed the structure of the rest of the game,
所以顽皮狗决定简单粗暴
so Naughty Dog just decided to expedite the process,
让埃比在游戏开始的前两小时内就遇到乔尔 直接开始复仇剧情
have Abby get to Joel within the first two hours of the game and get the revenge plot moving.
我觉得说得过去
I think that's fair.
只是感觉他们为此强凑了这些巧合 还是显得有些草率
I just think it's a little sloppy, considering how many coincidences they rely on to make it happen.
在埃比发现雪地上巡逻队的脚印后
After Abby finds the tracks in the snow, leading to one of the patrols,
镜头切回了和蒂娜正在巡逻的艾莉
we swap back to Ellie, whose on patrol with Dina.
你骑着马 踩着结冰的河面 穿过一片风景迷人的区域
You ride your horses through a beautifully realized landscape, walking on ice in a river.
真的太美了
It's absolutely beautiful.
真的 我不知道顽皮狗是怎么做的这么美丽的风景
I mean again, how Naughty Dog achieves these graphical features, I don't know.
但真的比不少其他的工作室高到不知道哪里去了
It really makes it look like every other development studio isn't even trying.
你一边巡逻 一边对角色有了更深入的了解
There's a lot of character building in this sequence as you go on your patrol.
俩人打情骂俏
There's some light flirting,
很明显 蒂娜喜欢艾莉 艾莉也喜欢蒂娜
clearly, Dina likes Ellie and Ellie likes Dina.
而紧张的气氛此时开始酝酿起来
And the tension starts to rise here.
事情进展的太顺利 这不太对劲
Again there's a lot of dread, things are going too well,
我们都知道TLOU的世界是极其残酷的
and the world of TLOU, as we know, is very cutthroat, sometimes literally.
游戏里角色开开心心无忧无虑甚至在打情骂俏
The fact that everybody's happy that they are so carefree that they're even flirting with each other.
事实上玩家心里都知道要有不好的事情发生了
It's unsettling, because we know that something bad has to happen soon.
而你继续推进 到了一个前哨站 探索一些废弃的房子
But you continue exploring, you go to an outpost to explore some abandoned houses.
在某个时刻
And at one point,
艾莉提到她当晚要邀请乔尔一起看电影
Ellie even says that she's going to be inviting Joel over for a movie later that night.
这一信息在故事结尾时极为重要
This will be VERY important at the end of the game,
所以请各位务必牢记
so make sure you remember this.
艾莉打算当天晚上和乔尔一起看电影
Ellie on this day was planning on having Joel over for a movie that night.
看起来没什么奇怪的
It seems like a small point,
大家也都知道艾莉和乔尔有着很深的情感上的羁绊
especially considering that Ellie and Joel have this deep connection with each other.
她甚至就住乔尔家房子后面的附属房里
She lives right behind him, even still in the grandmother's suite,
俩人晚上一起打发时间看个电影 听上去很合理
and it makes sense that perhaps they would try to fill an empty time,
watching movies and spending time together.
但是到了游戏结尾 我们就会发现这部分的信息量有多么大
But again, at the end of the game, we're going to find out a lot more.
而且艾莉提到的这段内容是在你探索一废弃房子时作为可选对话发生的
And this very statement by Ellie something that happens as an optional moment
while you're exploring an abandoned house.
这将会非常非常重要
This is going to be very important.
艾莉和蒂娜来到了一个有感染者出没的超市
Ellie and Dina, come up on a supermarket that's infested.
两人清空了感染者 并借此学习了潜行或者战斗的技巧
You cleared out, gives you the chance to explore some stealth options and combat,
这是这款游戏做得真的很棒的一部分
and it's a good thing that this is a really well done portion of the game.
因为游戏自带的潜行与制作元素
Because this stealth and the crafting that goes along with it
将会是游戏本身的调味品
is going to be the bread and butter of the game,
尤其在高难度下
especially if you're playing on higher difficulties,
你更需要很快适应这部分的游戏机制
you're going to need to get acclimated to these mechanics as soon as possible.
然后游戏还快速介绍了一下循声者
You are also given a quick introduction to Clickers as well,
这类感染者和一代里的几乎完全一样
and these guys work almost identically to how they did in the first game.
我觉得不太需要过多解释循声者的机制
I don't really feel the need to explain a lot as to how these sequences work,
因为如果你玩过一代的话 就肯定已经知道了
because if you've played the first game, you're going to know how this goes.
其实我们还要玩很久才会遇到全新的感染者
It's going to be a hot minute before we're thrown anything that's markedly different.
而在第一代游戏当中
I will say that in the first game,
有一件事让我很困扰
it always bugging me that
循声者显然是利用自己的咔咔声产生的回声定位来识别环境的
Clickers are obviously able to navigate their environments
by use of clicking sounds that use echolocation to map out their environment.
然而 它们从来不会听到出角色们互相交流的声音
However, they never were able to hear characters talking to each other
也听不见你上子弹、翻背包或者背回去的声音
or you reloading your weapon or moving your backpack on and off.
但到了这代游戏 就只在低难度下才成立了
That is mostly true again in this game, except only on the lower levels.
我专门测试过 在我的二周目生还者难度下
In my testing, I actually found that on new game plus on Survivor difficulty,
循声者的确能听到这两点
the Clickers can actually hear this as well.
如果你打开背包切换武器 那它们真的会听到并向你走来
If you open your backpack to swap weapons, they'll notice and they'll come running.
在这方面游戏的沉浸感有所提升
This was a game changer in terms of immersion.
真的 我从来没有玩过这样一款需要如此蹑手蹑脚行动的游戏
Seriously, I've never played a game where I was so attentive to everything that I was doing,
就连打开背包这种事都会害怕
that I was scared to even open up the inventory,
因为我知道这样会制造一点点噪音 会吸引循声者过来
because I knew that it was going to create a small amount of sound that could attract Clickers,
导致我要么死要么重新读档
which could mean that I die and have to reload.
我向大家保证 循声者的声音可老吓人了
Granted to some people, I'm sure that sounds absolutely terrible,
所以游戏开始才会有难度设定
which is why there are difficulty settings to begin with.
如果你想有个完美的沉浸式体验
But if you want to be totally immersed in this game,
那我强烈建议玩个最高难度试试
I recommend you play it on the hardest possible difficulty.
真的感觉一切都不一样了
It really does change everything.
这段超市场景中另外一个要注意的点是
Another thing to note in this supermarket sequences that
艾莉现在暴露在孢子中时会戴着面具
Ellie is wearing a mask when she encounters spores now.
如果你玩过一代游戏
If you played the first game,
可能会比较奇怪 因为众所周知艾莉是对真菌免疫的
this is going to be kind of weird because obviously Ellie is immune to the virus,
那她为何还要戴着防毒面具呢？
or so we thought, why does she need to wear a mask?
在游戏发售前的预告片里
In the trailers we saw before the game's launch,
很多人认为这可能意味着艾莉不再有免疫能力了
a lot of people thought that this would mean that Ellie was no longer immune,
可能她不像之前那样可以对孢子免疫了
or perhaps she was not as immune as she once was,
可能如果她吸入了孢子 就会生重病
so perhaps if she inhaled spores, that would make her very very sick,
但她仍然能挺过去
but she would eventually pull through it.
然而真实情况简单得多
However, the explanation is far simpler.
乔尔和艾莉都知道艾莉是免疫的 但其他人不能知道这件事
Joel and Ellie obviously know that Ellie is immune, but nobody else can know that.
如果有人发现艾莉是免疫的这一点
If people were to find out that Ellie's immune,
之前火萤遇到的那些破事就会重蹈覆辙
the same crap with the Fireflies would happen all over again.
当然现在看来这更像是乔尔的一厢情愿
Now this seems to be much more Joel's wish than it is Ellie's,
毕竟艾莉自己是有打算想要自我献身为全人类研发疫苗的
after all, Ellie was totally prepared and fine with giving her life
to save humanity in the form of a vaccine,
而这也完全说得通 因为乔尔要保证
And this would of course make sense because Joel wanted to make sure
不会有其他人因为艾莉的免疫能力而对她穷追不舍
nobody else would come to Ellie to try and capitalize on her gift,
如果有其他人知道 那乔尔就很可能会失去艾莉
because if they did, it would mean that he would lose her.
但实际上 艾莉这边知道自己不需要 却还在戴着防毒面具
But the fact that Ellie is still using the mask, even though she doesn't need to,
我觉得还能说明艾莉是在乎乔尔的想法的
I think, serves as proof positive that she still cares about what he thinks,
而且她还没法完全离开乔尔独立生活
and she's yet to fully separate and become her own person.
但这件事在游戏中的此刻还是没有完全解释通
But this isn't something that's explained or really justified at this point in the game,
不过未来我们会看到乔尔和艾莉在对话中专门解释此事
but we will see an actual conversation between Ellie and Joel later on that explains all of this.
两人解决了一堆感染者和循声者
If I throw a bunch of zombies and Clickers
最终来到超市的楼顶
and eventually find your way up to the top of the supermarket,
跳下来回到超市前面
where you jumped down out to the front,
艾莉和蒂娜目的就是清空超市里的感染者
Ellie and Dina's entire goal throughout exploring this supermarket was to clear it of infected,
而她们也的确完成了
and they've done just that.
实际上我觉得游戏为了让玩家熟悉适应战斗系统
Honestly, it's not a bad way of forcing the player to kill zombies
而要求玩家必须杀死所有感染者是可以接受的
in order to get experience with the combat system and become more comfortable with it.
许多玩家在绝大多数场景下会采取潜行的方式
A lot of people are going to simply try to stealth around them in most instances,
尤其在游戏后期 资源非常匮乏的时候
especially later in the game, when resources become very scarce.
但如果角色的任务是清空所有感染者以保护杰克逊小镇的安全
but if the characters mission is to wipe out all infected in an area to protect Jackson, the city,
那就对无双打法就没什么顾虑了
you all of a sudden don't have to worry about players doing that
因为玩家这种杀光感染者的操作是完全合理的
because they're going to be justified narratively in killing absolutely everything.
毕竟如果玩家不清空区域内的感染者就无法离开这里
After all, they can't leave the area
unless they've completely wiped all of the infected within that area.
两人离开超市后 暴风雪越来越猛烈
Once you get out of the supermarket, the blizzard starts to come in full force.
于是她们赶忙穿越风雪 来到了蒂娜知道的一家图书馆
So Ellie and Dina race through the snow, and end up at a library that Dina knew about.
这里是一个叫尤金的人之前的住所
It's the previous abode of somebody named Eugene,
我记得他还在之前的前哨站的签到本上有出现过
who, by my calculations, using the log book in the first outpost,
很可能在前一年死于中风 就在这个游戏开始前几个月
likely died of a stroke laid in the previous year just a few months before this game starts.
我们了解到他曾和汤米一起在火萤组织服役过
Well, we know about him is that he was a firefly who served with Tommy,
还是个电子产品的怪胎 还是个哈草战士
and he was also an electronics geek who was a total hippy.
没错 他喜欢抽大麻
In other words, he loved weed.
在介绍了我在所有游戏里见过的最逼真的改装武器的工作台后
After being introduced to the workbench,
Which has to be the most awesome and kick ass weapon customization system
在介绍了我在所有游戏里见过的最逼真的改装武器的工作台后
I have ever seen in a game,
玩家来到地下室 发现了尤金真正充满秘密的小天地
you went down to the basement where you find Eugene's true passion.
我第一眼见到这些的时候
Now, when I first saw all of this,
我就想问他在卖这些东西吗？他会拿这些东西进行交易吗？
I had to ask the question: Was he actually like selling this stuff? Was he trading it?
我不知道 或许我漏了某个上面解释了尤金具体在做什么的纸条
I don't know, maybe there's a notes that I missed,
that explained what he was doing with all of this pot.
不清楚 如果还有什么我没发现的东西的话请大家告诉我一下
I don't know, let me know if there is something there probably is, and I just didn't find it.
但如果真用于贸易 那这似乎是杰克逊的一个巨大的潜在机会
But it seems as though it's a huge potential opportunity for Jackson in terms of trade,
利用完整的大麻供应链提供给进出的流浪者
if they had a whole of this marijuana to offer, to transients coming in and out,
如果杰克逊这样在末世中的繁荣小镇
I mean it would be pretty funny if Jackson, this thriving city in the apocalypse,
整个经济是基于大麻贸易 那将是相当有趣的
if their entire economy was based off of selling weed.
我认为这样的末世下 一种植物让大家团结在一起 是很搞笑也是很酷的事情
I think it would be hilarious and kind of cool
that in this world, this one thing this plant has brought everybody together.
我的意思是……嗯……我家在科罗拉多
科罗拉多州在2014年实行了大麻合法化
I mean, yeah, I live in Colorado.
或许这就是为什么我会这样想吧
Maybe that's why I'm partial to that argument.
当然我自己不抽那种东西的……不抽的
I mean I don't smoke and I don't… I don't smoke.
但当然了 科罗拉多的很多人都会谈论大麻 自己就跟着耳濡目染了
But, still, like you live in Colorado, everyone talks about pot, and this is what you do.
说到哪了？哦对！
What was I talking about? Oh, yeah!
蒂娜和艾莉抽了一根
Dina and Ellie smoke a blunt.
她们像高中音乐舞会一般聊了两人前一天晚上的吻
They shared some high school musical style discussion about their kiss from the night before.
然后一言不合就又开始打啵了
And then they share another one and then a few other ones,
最终俩人开始搞起来 然后镜头再次切回埃比
and eventually their overcome, and they begin making out as we cut to Abby, once again.
她在躲避大量的感染者
she's running from all sorts of hordes.
她弄的动静太大了 感染者们肯定都听到了
She's making a lot of noise, and they are definitely hearing it.
这与之前平静祥和的场景产生了鲜明对比
This increases the tension a lot after the calm of the previous scene.
这样的节奏变换在游戏中会经常出现
And this type of pacing is going to happen often.
说实话 我很喜欢
Honestly, I love it.
这是顽皮狗的特色招数
It's a very common Naughty Dog tactic.
先让你兴奋起来
They work you up,
然后作为对比 给你看一些平静的内容 降低你的心率
and then they contrast it with something that's very calm that lowers your heart rate
然后马上给你当头一棒 转而又让一切归于平静
only to whack you over the head again and then luring you back into a sense of calm.
最好的例子就是一代游戏的开场部分
The best example would be in the opening of the original game.
一开始一切是如此祥和轻快
Everything's calm and relaxed,
然后一下子世界末日就到了 然后你女儿就说没就没了
And then the world starts to fall apart and everything's terrible and then your daughter dies,
然后画面马上又切到了20年后乔尔从床上恍然惊醒的场景
and then you cut forward to Joel sleeping on a mattress twenty years later
再然后就是和泰丝的一段相对平缓的对话
and having a very calm, comparatively conversation with Tess
瞧好吧您嘞
and prepare your butts
这样的转折在续作中简直就是家常便饭
because this is going to happen on a regular basis throughout all of the sequel.
而且谢天谢地 这种转折的应用并不会对叙事效果带来负面影响
And thankfully, the predictability of this
doesn't actually negatively affect the efficacy of this mechanism.
仍然非常有看头
It still works pretty well.
玩家操控埃比逃离这群感染者 最后来到一处铁丝网后面
Now as you run as Abby through all of these hordes, you eventually reach a chain link fence.
你挤过这里 旁边还有感染者想抓你
You squeeze through it and a bunch of zombies grab onto you,
你的帽子被抢走了 感染者们对你上下其手 还有一只冲破了铁丝网
start ripping your hat off and doing all sorts of gross stuff, and then one breaks through,
然后就是……
and this happens.
乔尔：把手给我！
Joel: Gimme your hand!
我们赶紧逃。
We're gonna have to run.
汤米：他们的数量太多了！
Tommy: There's too many of them!
乔尔：我掩护你们，快走！
Joel: I'll cover you, get going!
汤米：过来，这边！
Tommy: C'mon, this way!
目前他们还没进行自我介绍
Now they haven't been introduced yet.
但就目前来讲 埃比很庆幸自己活下来了
but as of right now, Abby's just glad to be alive.
据她所了解
As far as she knows,
乔尔和汤米都是万千普通人之一
Joel is just some random guy, as is Tommy,
而刚好他们俩就在正确的时间正确的地点出现在她面前救了她一命
and they just happened to be in the right place at the right time to save her.
又是一个巧合
Again, a coincidence.
这点就很难说得通了
This one's a little harder to justify and explained.
他俩完全没理由要跑到这样一个建筑的死胡同
Because they have no reason to be out at this dead end area
of a building they have likely been in before.
三人一起逃到了雪山山顶的一个缆车站
All of you escaped together to a ski lodge at the top of the mountain.
你们骑上马
You up on some horses,
一段简短的介绍后埃比知道了他俩是谁
and after a brief introduction wherein Abby learns who she's with,
她提议去她和朋友们驻扎的那栋别墅屋里躲避暴风雪
she recommends that they weighed out the storm in a mansion
that she and her friends have been staying in.
乔尔和汤米想都没想就同意了
Joel and Tommy agree to go without any significant hesitance
完全不像是活过缆车站战斗的人能做出的决策
beyond the initial belief that they could survive in the lodge.
这又是一个巧合
Once again, it's another coincidence.
乔尔和汤米谁也不傻
Joel and Tommy, aren't this naive,
即使在这样艰难的条件下也不应该这么武断
or at the very least they shouldn't be, even when pushed in these extreme conditions.
我明白外面暴风雪肆虐
What I mean is, I understand that there's a blizzard raging,
我也明白这会让他们做出相比天气晴好的时候不会做出的选择
and I understand that would push them into choices that they wouldn't otherwise make,
should the weather be fine and dandy.
但乔尔和汤米都不傻 他们都知道不应该轻易相信陌生人的话
But Joel and Tommy aren't stupid, and they know not to trust strangers,
即使这个人看上去多么无辜善良
even a stranger that looks as innocent as a… hulked out heroin.
他们肯定应该知道不应该轻易相信一群住在他们巡逻路线上别墅里的陌生人
And they definitely should know that they shouldn't trust a group of strangers
that are living out of a mansion that's on their patrol route.
埃比说他们已经在那待几天了
She says they've been staying there for a few days
他们有武器 有食物等物资可以帮助乔尔和汤米
that they have weapons, food and all sorts of things that could help Joel and Tommy.
她能主动提出帮助固然是好的
While it's nice that she's offering to help them in this way,
但首先应该警惕的是她主动提供帮助的目的何在
it should also raise a lot of red flags that she's willing to help them first of all,
还要注意到这帮人神不知鬼不觉地就在离杰克逊小镇如此近的地方落脚
and also that this giant group of people is present so close to Jackson without their knowledge.
但总之乔尔和汤米还是同意一起去了
But nonetheless Joel and Tommy agree to go.
抵达别墅屋后 乔尔、汤米和埃比下马 一起进入了房间
Once you arrive at the cabin, Joel, Tommy, and Abby dismount and settle into the house.
埃比显然表情很纠结 而汤米和乔尔谁也没注意到
Abby is clearly distressed, while Tommy and Joel are none the wiser.
恐惧的氛围再次袭来
Again, the dread is building.
事情很不对劲
Something is very wrong.
大家都来到了地下室旁边的房间 乔尔和汤米各自做了自我介绍
Everyone moves into the nearby basement room, and Tommy and Joel introduce themselves.
同样 这种操作和他们本人人设太不符了
Again, this might be construed as out of character
竟然会在一堆陌生人面前自报家门
that they would use their real names to a bunch of strangers.
但我个人认为这点倒是没那么牵强
But in my opinion, it's not actually stretch
因为汤米和乔尔没必要认为他们的名字会暴露他们的身份
because Tommy and Joel have no reason to believe that their first names could give them away,
或者认为报了名字就会被追杀
or that one of them is being hunted for that matter.
他们的确干过不少烂事
Yes, they've all done a lot of really messed up stuff,
但光靠一个名字就全国范围内追着砍
but knowing somebody's first name and hunting them down across the country,
这才有点离谱
that seems like a bit of a stretch.
反正事已至此
But here we are.
我想说的是 我觉得乔尔和汤米两人在一群
Point is I don't think that it's unrealistic that Joel and Tommy use their real names
看似要帮助他们的人面前自报姓名没那么难以让人接受
when introducing themselves to a group that seemingly is helping them out.
当然我不得不承认 在整个游戏的序幕中
And I have to say it's pretty impressive at how slow and steady
如此缓慢而稳定建立起来的恐惧感真的太让人印象深刻了
the dread is building throughout this entire introductory sequence, the prologue of the game.
在乔尔说出自己名字的一刻 房间里所有人脸色都从友善瞬间变成冷淡与邪恶
And then at this very moment,
when Joel says his name and everybody's faces turn from very friendly to cold and evil.
我觉得我永远都忘不掉那一刻
It's a moment that I'm not sure I'll ever forget
乔尔说出名字的时候 房间瞬间安静下来
the second Joel says his name, the room shifts.
连地上掉根针都能听见
You could hear a pin drop.
他们从之前友好的神色一转变成紧盯猎物的鬣狗
Instead of being friendly, they all looked at him as though their hyenas looking at their next meal.
而且需要注意的是 在乔尔介绍自己之前我们感受到的这种友善
And it's important to note that this kindness that we feel before Joel introduces himself
是非常重要的 而且以后还会出现 我向大家保证
is very important and it will come up again later, I promise you.
接着 乔尔主动打破了这份宁静 然后……
Now Joel picks up on this shift, and this plays out.
女人：谢谢。
Woman: Appreciate it.
梅尔：对了，我是梅尔。
Mel: I'm Mel, by the way.
汤米：汤米。
Tommy: Tommy.
他是我弟弟。
This is my brother.
乔尔：乔尔。
Joel: Joel.
你们怎么看起来一副知道我们的样子。
Y'all act like you've heard of us or something.
埃比：因为他们的确知道。
Abby: That's 'cause they have.
汤米：不！
Tommy: No!
欧文：去抓另一个！
Owen: Get the other one!
诺拉？怎么样了？
Nora? All clear?
诺拉：他晕过去了。
Nora: He's out.
埃比：把他靠墙放。
Abby: Put him against the wall.
乔尔：汤米。
Joel: Tommy.
离我远点！离我远点！啊啊！
Get off me! Get off me! Aahh!
男子：Puta madre!
Man: ¡Puta madre!
埃比：乔尔·米勒……
Abby: Joel Miller…
乔尔：你是谁？
Joel: Who are you?
埃比：你猜啊。
Abby: Guess.
乔尔：要不你先说完准备好的台词直接动手吧。
Joel: Why don't you say whatever speech you've got rehearsed and get this over with.
埃比：给他的腿绑上止血带。
Abby: Tourniquet his leg.
快去！
Do it!
欧文：你他妈的不准动。
Owen: Don't you fuckin' move.
乔尔：该死！
Joel: God damn it!
埃比：散开。
Abby: Clear out.
你这个蠢老头……
You stupid old man…
不要心急。
You don't get to rush this.
镜头回到艾莉 她正慢慢接近别墅屋
We cut back to Ellie, closing in on the cabin.
就在乔尔与汤米一起和埃比来到别墅之前
Now right before Joel and Tommy pushed up to the cabin with Abby,
我们看到杰西在尤金的图书馆地下室里找到了事后的艾莉和蒂娜
We saw Jesse come across Ellie and Dina in the basement of Eugene's library in a compromised position.
他告诉两人乔尔和汤米不见了 暴风雪来了之后就没人见过他俩
He tells them that Joel and Tommy are missing and nobody has seen them since the storm came in.
艾莉突然惊慌失措 立刻上马去帮忙找他俩
Ellie becomes panicked and races off to help find them.
但要注意的是 艾莉强调
It's important to note also that Ellie stressed
他们应该分头行动 搜寻尽可能多的地方
that they should all split up to try and cover as much ground as possible.
一些人可能会觉得这也是在凑巧合
Some people have said that this itself is a coincidence
或者说这样行动有些牵强 他们实际应该不会这样做
or a bit of a stretch that they wouldn't actually do this.
但大家还是要想一想
But again, think about it.
站在艾莉的角度 我觉得这没什么牵强的
From her perspective, I don't think it's a stretch.
因为据艾莉所知
Because as far as Ellie is concerned,
乔尔和汤米很有可能只是因为暴风雪而不得不躲在某个地方
it's very possible that Joel and Tommy simply had to bunker down somewhere because of the blizzard
并且可能遭遇了意外
and were caught there by surprise.
她不可能预料到乔尔会被来自西雅图的一帮人追杀
It's not to say that she expected Joel to be hunted by some random chick from Seattle.
但不管怎样 大家都立即开始寻找乔尔和汤米
But regardless everybody breaks off looking for Joel and Tommy.
在埃比开始攻击乔尔的时候 镜头切到了逐渐靠近别墅屋的艾莉
After Abby starts her attack on Joel, we cut to Ellie, closing in on the cabin,
游戏在这里迷惑了大家一下 你可以在进入别墅屋后拾取一些弹药补给
they give a bit of a fake out here by dropping some ammo right as you enter the cabin,
让你以为大战之前必有补给
which makes the player think that you're about to fight.
我还挺喜欢这样的设定的
I actually really like it.
游戏在这里故意骗你
When games do this, do this little fake out.
让你做好战斗的准备
So you're prepped for a fight,
然后告诉你这些都没用 当然可能只有我喜欢这样的设定
and then it's taken away from you, but I know that's just me.
当然这样的设定完全依赖于我们进入地下室后 发生了这样的事情……
Of course this is in the case because the second that we enter the basement, this happens.
诺拉：压制她！
Nora: Pin her down!
艾莉：离我远点！
Ellie: Get off me!
诺拉：抓她的手！
Nora: Get her hands!
艾莉：他妈的放开我！
Ellie: Get the fuck off me!
男子：婊子——
Man: Bitch--
男子：你已经扯平了。
Man: You got her.
看，你已经扯平了！可以了吗？
Look, you got her! Okay?
男子：放开！
Man: Let go!
艾莉：你们他妈的死定了！
Ellie: You're gonna fucking die!
欧文：怎么回事？
Owen: What's going on?
艾莉：离他远点！
Ellie: Let him go!
梅尔：她是谁？
Mel: Who is that?
艾莉：离他远点！          诺拉：她偷偷溜进来的……
Ellie: Let him go!                          Nora: She snuck in…
欧文：你们为什么没在外面站岗？
Owen: Why aren't you posted up outside?
诺拉：我们根本没想到会有人出现。
Nora: We didn't think anyone was going to show up.
欧文：不然你们该死的以为会出现什么？
Owen: The hell did you expect?
我们得在整个镇子的人追上我们之前离开。
We gotta get out of here before the whole town's on top of us.
你可以停下来了。
You're done.
埃比：你和我想要的一样吧？
Abby: You want what I want, right?
欧文：那就一次解决他，快。
Owen: End it. Now.
艾莉：乔尔，起来。
Ellie: Joel, get up.
乔尔，他妈的快起来。
Joel, fucking get up.
拜托住手吧！
Please stop!
求你了，请不要这样……
Please don't do this…
乔尔，求你了，快起来！
Joel, please get up!
不要！
Nooo!
男子：在地狱中烧成灰烬吧，pendejo。
Man: Burn in hell, pendejo.
艾莉：我他妈要杀了你们……
Ellie: I'll fucking kill you…
不！
No!
男子：（含糊不清的声音）
艾莉：不……
Ellie: No…
我他妈要杀了你们……
I'll fucking kill you.
男子：（含糊不清的声音）
埃比的团队之间就如何处理艾莉进行了一番激烈的争论
There are some heated discussion between the members of Abby's party as to what to do with Ellie.
但声音非常小 玩家什么都听不清
It's all very muffled, and you can't understand any of it,
但我们稍后会从另一个视角看到这部分内容
though we will get to see this from another perspective later.
最后其中一人一脚把她踢晕了
Eventually they just knocked her out.
一段时间后 赶来救援的蒂娜和杰西叫醒了她
and Ellie wakes up after some time to Dina and Jesse rescuing them.
此时大家还不清楚汤米是否活了下来 但乔尔肯定没有
At this point is not clear if Tommy survived, but it's clear that Joel did not.
知道吗 我觉得现在挺适合聊聊大家一直视而不见的一件事了
You know what? This is as good a time as any to address the elephant in the room dead on the floor.
我玩游戏之前就被剧透了
I had the game spoiled for me,
所以我知道乔尔会在某个时间点死去
so I knew that Joel was going to die at some point.
而且说实话
And to be honest,
我感觉好像很多人都认为乔尔在游戏中的几年前就感觉他要没
many of us had a feeling as though Joel was going to die at some point in the game years ago
因为这完全说得通
because it only made sense.
很多人对“续作”有一个刻板印象 即前作里的某个主要角色会在续作中死去
One of the stereotypes of a sequel is that they're going to kill off one of the major characters
from the first iteration of whatever is in question,
不管是电影、小说、播客还是游戏
whether it's a movie and novel, a podcast or a video game,
我们一次又一次地看到无数桥段在上演这样的套路
time and time again, we've seen this trope played out.
而这之所以是“套路” 因为这样做其实很有效
And it's become a trope because this actually works pretty well.
在第一部作品的故事中 你和角色一起成长 爱上了这个角色
You grow the character and the audience falls in love with them over the course of the first story.
然后在这样的基础下 续作中直接拆散玩家与一代角色的羁绊
Then, with this foundation laid you pull the rug out from everybody
给所有玩家当头一棒
and smack them over the head with a two by four of emotion.
或者在这个游戏里应该叫……当头一高尔夫
Or maybe in this case, a golf club of emotion.
可能有点猝不及防 管他呢 继续说我的
Maybe that's too soon, I don't care, moving on.
即使在这个游戏推出之前 很多人就已经确定了这一预设
Even with this presumption, having been established by many people before this game was launched,
但顽皮狗似乎也积极地用发售前的预告片试图劝阻粉丝们放弃这一幻想
Naughty Dog seems to have actively tried to dissuade fans from this presupposition
by way of their pre launch trailers.
其实这点惹得不少玩家在通关后有所不满
Now this actually got a lot of people pretty upset when they played through the entirety of TLOU2.
预告片里有很多内容
There are multiple events that were shown in the trailers
在实际游戏里并没有出现
that aren't actually indicative of what the game has to offer.
最明显的例子就是这个
The clearest example would be this one,
艾莉正在和一群华盛顿解放战线作战
Washington Liberation Front, WLF: 华盛顿解放战线
where Ellie is fighting through a bunch of WLF,
突然一只手捂住了她的嘴
and then has a hand put over her mouth,
然后她转身 发现是乔尔
and when she turns round, she sees that it's Joel,
告诉她自己不会让她一个人做这些事
telling her that he's not going to let her do this by herself.
我对这个内容肯定不会像很多人在推特上那样无脑的说
Now I'm not going to respond in the same way that a lot of people on Twitter responded
“游戏在搞虚假宣传”“RNM退钱！”
where they demanded their money back to the false advertising.
我觉得这是不公平的
I don't think that's fair,
尤其你花了60美元已经玩了前面那么多游戏内容了
especially because you paid sixty dollars and have gotten a lot of game play out of it before.
我才懒得跟你们解释这些 太蠢了
You know, I don't even need to explain my reasoning, I just think that's stupid.
但我想说的是 这段内容让我很困扰
What I will say, however, was that this was very confusing,
至少对我来说 在我第一次通关游戏的时候
at least for me, the first time I play through the game.
我已经看过很多次预告片了
Having watched all of the trailers multiple times,
我知道乔尔在游戏后面仍然会出场 因为艾莉遇到他了
I knew that Joel made an appearance later on in the game because Ellie responds to him.
但这并没有在实际游戏中出现过
But that never happens in the actual game.
所以我一直在想是不是之后会有一段比如梦里的场景
So I kept asking myself whether or not there was going to be some sort of dream sequence
她重新进行了一遍那里的战斗
where she plays back through the same level again.
但这次那只手是乔尔的 然后他说了那样的话
But this time Joel is at the end of the line instead, and then that scene plays out.
当然不用我说你们也知道这并没有发生
Of course, I don't have to tell you that never happens.
这其实只是一种把粉丝的注意力从真正要发生的事情上转移开的方法
This was simply a way to divert the attention from the fans
away from what was actually going to happen.
而且顽皮狗干这种事不是第一次了
And Naughty Dog does have a history of doing this type of thing,
这也是我并不怪他们的部分原因
which is part of the reason I can't fault them completely,
因为通常他们的出发点是好的
because usually it's for a good reason.
最好的例子就是初代TLOU
The most obvious example would be with the original TLOU,
他们说你游戏全程只会操控乔尔
when they said that you would only be playing as Joel throughout the entirety of the game.
显然这不是事实
Of course, this isn't true.
这也使得当你在玩艾莉的时候
And it made it so when you actually get your hands on Ellie,
这话怎么听着这么别扭
that sounded weird when I said it out loud,
这也使得当你在操控艾莉这个角色的时候
it made it, so when you started playing as Ellie,
整个过程就显得更加真实 因为你根本没有想到会有这样的机会
the entire sequence was much more surreal because you didn't expect at all to have this opportunity.
另一个例子就是本作了
Another example would be with this very game,
他们说在TLOU2里 全程你只会操控艾莉一个角色
TLOU2 when they said that you would only be playing as Ellie throughout the entirety of the campaign,
这当然也是假的
something which was obviously not true.
这些本想为玩家提供更好游戏体验的善意谎言有一个问题
The problem with these sort of white lies to better the game play experience for the player
就是它们只能在人们不了解的情况下起作用
is that they only work if people don't know any better.
在初代游戏中 据我所了解到的情况
And with the original game, as far as I am aware,
大多数人都认为在整个游戏过程中你只能操控乔尔
most people believed that you would only play as Joel throughout the entirety of the game,
那当你开始操控艾莉的时候 这样善意的谎言就有用了
and it made it so when they got their hands on the controller playing as Ellie.
游戏突然变得更有意思了 因为玩家根本没有意料到此事
It was much more interesting because they didn't expect it at all.
但TLOU2的泄密事件让玩家们老早就知道要发生什么了
But with TLOU2 and all of the leaks that followed, people saw this coming from a mile away,
这种善意谎言的作用就荡然无存了
and it lost a lot of its punch.
我其实花过很多时间思考如果我没被剧透 没有预见这些 游戏会是什么样的
I've actually spent a lot of time thinking what this game would be like
if I had no expectations and nothing spoiled for me.
我觉得游戏体验会有很大不同
I think the experience would have been much different,
而且我也不知道这会怎样改变我的视角
and I'm not sure how that would have changed my perspective.
总之 如果您是这样的幸运玩家
Nonetheless, if you happen to be one of the few lucky people
玩游戏的时候没看过之前任何剧透的话
who got to play the entire game without having anything spoiled for you,
我希望您能在评论区或者推特留下您的想法
I want to hear your thoughts down in the comment section below or in a tweet.
我真的很期待能看看您对这一切有着怎样的视角
Sent it to me, I'm really interested in hearing what your perspective is on all of this.
但对于乔尔的死这件事 我觉得没什么问题
But as for Joel's death itself, I have no problem with it.
在第一部作品中 乔尔的行为相当鲁莽
Joel's actions throughout the course of the first game were quite reckless
他在第一部里坑了不少人 也杀了不少人
and he screwed over a lot of people and killed a lot of people while he was at it.
这话我之前说过 我现在也要说：我不认为乔尔是英雄
I've said before, and I'll say it again: I don't think Joel is a hero.
真要说的话 抛开一切来看 他应该是一个反英雄
If anything, he's an anti hero, if you look at his actions in a vacuum.
你完全可以说人生与道德在实际生活中会复杂得多
You can always say that life and morality is much more complicated than looking at it purely in a vacuum,
但我仍然认为乔尔不能算是我们大家应该敬仰 应该向他学习的道德标杆
but I think it still stands to say that Joel is not a pillar of morality,
to which we should all look and pray for guidance.
我觉得相反 他是一个有心理创伤的、悲伤的、有道德的角色
I think rather, he's a damaged, broken, sad and a moral character
他会为了生存 为了保护她所关心的人做他该做的事
who is looking to do what he needs to do, to survive and protect those he cares about.
这一点我认为从某种程度上说是值得钦佩的
That's something that I think is in a way admirable in and of itself.
但不能因为这就能说你是“英雄”了
But I don't think that that makes you a hero quote-unquote in the same way
作为对比 可以想想埃洛伊这样的角色
that you could compare a character such as Aloy
她无论遇到什么事情都会做出相对道德的决策
who is actively trying to do the moral thing in any instance that she comes across.
再往远了说 在游玩时我们一直在操控乔尔
Furthermore, from a game play perspective, we got our game with Joel.
我们了解他 站在他的视角经历了很多事情
We know him, we have experienced him and his perspectives.
我觉得应该换换角度看看新内容了
I think it was time for something new,
如果我们之前游玩乔尔和艾莉的比重各占一半
and if we had played through the entire game as Joel or half and half between Joel and Ellie,
那我想这样带来的震撼就会轻得多
I think it would have lost a lot of its punch.
乔尔的死对我来讲感觉丝毫没什么意外的
Now Joel's death didn't come as a surprise to me, or probably any one,
尤其当你走进别墅屋地下室那道门之后
especially once you walk through that door in the cabin.
当然 看到乔尔被高尔夫球杆打爆脑袋内心感受还是很糟糕的
That being said, it's still pretty horrible having to watch him get his head crammed in with a golf club.
这段剧情让你心里发堵 但它就是这样设计的
It's pretty haunting, but that's by design.
顽皮狗需要让玩家有和艾莉同样极度悲伤的感受
Naughty Dog needed the player to be just as haunted by this event as Ellie is
因为他们需要玩家能和艾莉有同样的内心情感
because then they feel emotionally equivalent,
尤其是对埃比的恨
especially in their hatred towards Abby,
这是他们想让玩家在游戏前期建立起的主要感情基调
which is one of the major elements that they need to establish early on.
而你作为玩家 需要对埃比从头发丝恨到脚后跟
You, the player, need to hate this girl with every fiber of your being.
就像艾莉也对埃比恨之入骨一样
Just like Ellie hates her with every fibre of her being.
这样一来等之后游戏完全调转视角
so that later, when they try to flip perspectives and flip the table on you,
就有很强的效果了
they can do that effectively.
如果你对埃比毫无感觉
If you're apathetic towards Abby
那你游玩整个游戏尝试复仇的时候
and then you go through the entirety of the game trying to pursue revenge,
就会感觉毫无动力
you're not going to be motivated at all.
整个游戏剧情的前提和故事都是空中楼阁 游戏会变得无聊
It's going to be pretty uninteresting because the entire premise of the game and the story is a moot point.
但如果你像艾莉想把埃比千刀万剐一样恨埃比
But if you hate Abby, just as much as Ellie hates her and wants to see her die,
你在游玩游戏前半部分的时候就会充满动力
you'll be motivated to get through the first half of the game.
然后顽皮狗再为最后一幕做准备
And then Naughty Dog has you set up for the final act.
至此 我们来到了游戏序章部分的结尾
Now, after this, we enter the end of the prologue.
没错 你已经看了一个小时的视频了 我们才要讲完序章部分
Yes, we are an hour into this video, and we are just getting out of the prologue.
艾莉和汤米讨论他们接下来的决策
Ellie and Tommy discuss their next steps.
汤米跟玛丽娅提了下 而她不让汤米采取任何行动
Tommy talk to Maria, and she's not going to let him go or do anything,
也不给他分配任何帮手
and he's not allowed to have any sort of spare men.
所以汤米必须把他们留在杰克逊小镇
He has to keep them all in Jackson.
玛丽娅认为他们应该放下这些
She thinks that they should just move on,
发生的事情很可怕 但生活还要继续
except that what happened was terrible and go on with their lives.
像往常一样 玛丽娅一直是那个看似最理智的人
As usual, Maria seems to be the one voice of reason.
而汤米和艾莉的不满也是可以理解的
Tommy and Ellie, however, are understandably upset.
汤米的哥哥惨死
Tommy lost his brother in a terrible way,
艾莉也痛失她的“父亲”一样的角色
and Ellie also lost her "father figure" in a terrible way.
他们还不知道这一切的缘由
They still aren't certain why this happened,
也不知道乔尔到底做了什么 让那帮人如此急切地想让乔尔死
or what Joel did that made them seek his death out so fervently.
汤米不小心看到他们身上衣服写着“WLF”
Tommy happened to see some patches on their coats that read "WLF".
因为他以前在火萤组织工作过
And because of his previous history with the Fireflies,
他知道这个缩写的含义是华盛顿解放战线
he knows that that would be the Washington Liberation Front,
说明这是一个在华盛顿州的组织
which is a group that's in Washington.
这不废话吗
Huh… Go figure.
这也给了艾莉下一步的目标
And that's what allows Ellie to know where she needs to go next.
埃比那帮人可能已经回去了 路途可不短
It's a long stretch that they would have returned to Seattle
而且还要保证他们还在那 还能找到他们
and that they would still be there and that they would be findable.
但如果你有如此强烈的动机在 那你无论如何都会想试试
But when you're motivated this strongly, you're willing to go and try anything.
就像埃比也火急火燎地想杀死乔尔复仇一样
In the same way that Abby was so desperate to go and get revenge against Joel.
艾莉现在也想去埃比的地盘找她复仇
Ellie now is motivated to go to her turf and get revenge against her.
现在汤米想只身前往西雅图找埃比报仇
Now Tommy wants to go to Seattle by himself, and Hunt Abby down and get revenge.
玛丽娅显然不会同意他去
Maria, of course, is not going to let him do that.
但汤米更深一层的目的是想阻止艾莉去西雅图复仇
But Tommy's main objective is to prevent Ellie from going,
他答应过乔尔无论如何都会照顾艾莉
he promised Joel that he would take care of Ellie, no matter what.
而此时 他也知道如果艾莉前往西雅图
And in this case, he knows that if Ellie goes to Seattle,
那大概率是有去无回
her chances of survival aren't very high.
所以汤米宁愿自己搏一把
So he'd rather go take on those chances himself
留下艾莉 只身前往西雅图为乔尔报仇
and spare Ellie while trying to get revenge for the sake of the both of them.
艾莉则说要么一起去
Ellie demands that they either go together,
要么让汤米同意自己带着蒂娜
or that Tommy allow Ellie to go with Dina
再带小镇里其他一些人一起去复仇
and some other people with some troops from the camp to get revenge herself.
汤米肯定不同意 跟艾莉说让她再给自己一天的时间
Tommy, of course, rejects this idea and asks for and more time just a day or so
让汤米考虑、安排一下
so that he can try and work something out.
此时 汤米只是在争取时间
In this case, he's just buying time.
他已经下定主意要怎样做了
He's made up his mind as to what he's going to do.
然后我们看到艾莉在乔尔的墓前
We then see Ellie in Joel's grave site.
这段真的很感人
It's a really touching moment,
游戏也再次提醒我们 乔尔已经走了
and it reaffirms that Joel is actually gone.
其他人的情况我不了解
I don't know about you guys.
但我自己第一次玩游戏的时候 有一种超现实的感觉
But I had this sort of surreal feeling when I played through this game the first time.
我不停对自己说：乔尔肯定还没死
I kept saying to myself: Joel can't actually be dead.
一方面我们看过预告片里乔尔在西雅图中出现过
For one because we saw that trailer, where Joel was featured later on in the game in Seattle.
另一方面 他可是乔尔啊！
And for two because Joel is Joel,
怎么突然间说没就没了啊 应该还有点别的戏份啊
you can't just kill off Joel that suddenly, there has to be more to it.
但真的没了
But there isn't.
乔尔死了 他的墓就在这 很遗憾
He's dead. This is his grave and it's sad.
艾莉之后和蒂娜一起去了乔尔的家
Ellie then visits Joel's house with Dina,
拿起了他在第一作里就已经坏掉了的手表
picks up his watch from the first game, it's still broken.
还拿走了他的左轮手枪 游戏剩余部分里你可以一直用
And also takes his revolver, which you'll be using throughout the rest of the game.
艾莉能拿到这件武器还是很酷的
It's actually pretty cool that this is where she gets it.
我们还能稍微探索一下乔尔的家
We do this though, only after exploring his house a little bit,
细节真的非常丰富
and there's a lot of incredible detail here,
也更加丰满了乔尔这个角色
and it really encapsulates Joel's character.
他热爱音乐 房间也打理得整整齐齐
He's very music heavy and organized his neat and tidy,
但房间也空旷得令人心酸
and his house is also painfully empty.
有很多空旷的大房间
There's a lot of big, empty rooms.
或许是我过度解读了
And maybe I'm just reading too much into it,
但我总感觉房子里空余空间这么大
but I couldn't help but feel as though there was a lot of space
如果艾莉想住进来是完全没问题的
where Ellie could have stayed if she had wanted to.
就像我之前说的 若不是因为两人的情感上的隔阂
Like I said earlier, there was no reason other than the emotional turmoil between the two
艾莉完全没理由住在房子后面的附属房里
for Ellie to go and live in the grandmother's suite out back.
另外相信我 我们之后还会看到房子里的挂画
But truly everything from the paintings on the walls which we'll come back to later, I promise to,
乔尔的床还是略显凌乱 床边有一本太空类的杂志和一些书
Joel's bed still being a little rough and that there is a space magazine and books by his bed,
他对太空感兴趣 所以在看这方面的书
that he was reading because he's interested in space
真的很……温馨 很感人
like it's… it's so cute, and it's so touching,
每每想到乔尔再也不会出现在这间房子里 都感觉心痛不已
and it's so painfully sad to know that he's never going to walk through that house ever again.
拿上这些东西后
After you grab these items,
你走下楼梯 发现玛丽娅和蒂娜在桌前等你
you walked downstairs and realized that Maria is there sitting with Dina.
她告诉你汤米已经自己去复仇了
She informs you that Tommy left on his own already
还说要把艾莉关起来 不让她跟上来
and is asking that Ellie be locked up to prevent her from following him.
玛丽娅为此肯定很苦恼 生气 闹心……
Maria is understandably frustrated, angry, pissed,
你能想到的啥词都行
whatever words you want to associate with it.
但最主要的是 她担忧汤米的安全
But more than anything, she's worried.
而且她深知如果能送艾莉和蒂娜过去帮助汤米
and she knows that if she sends Ellie and Dina off to try and help Tommy
那至少能提高成功的概率
at least still stand a better chance.
所以玛丽娅允许艾莉和蒂娜带着马和一些物资离开杰克逊小镇
So Maria allows Ellie and Dina to leave Jackson with their horses and some extra supplies
条件是要能把汤米完整地、活着带回来
so long as they promised to bring back Tommy, when they return, in one piece.
这为你和你操控的角色未来的旅程设定了两个目标
This sets up the dual purpose of your journey and theirs.
你要去杀死埃比复仇 还要去救汤米
You're going there to kill Abby, but also to save Tommy,
虽然汤米可能用不着你来救
although Tommy probably doesn't need much saving.
而且等你到了西雅图还会发现
And you'll realize that once we get to Seattle,
这趟旅途全程还会额外增加第三个目标
there's going to be a third purpose in their journey and motivation to everything that they're doing,
that's added on top of it.
我发现他们这样设定多个目标还是很有意思的
I find it really interesting that they set up these multiple goals
因为这样会让事情看起来很复杂 我很喜欢这样的设定
because it seems as though it just complicates things which I actually like.
如果目标单一 只要去杀了某个人就行了 就会显得单调
Having a single quest, we are just going to try and kill one person, is a little bland.
让游戏不那么有趣
It's a little uninteresting.
因此知道自己需要一次完成很多个目标还是挺有意思的
So to see that we have multiple things we're trying to do all at once is a little refreshing.
西雅图
至此 我们来到了游戏的核心内容——「西雅图 第1天」
After this we jumped to the start of the core game itself, Seattle day 1.
第1天
序章结束了 该开始游玩游戏的最核心部分了
And after this, we're done with the prologue and ready to move into the core of the game.
但在这之前 我想先和大家聊聊此时我的感受
But before we do that, I want to discuss our feelings at this point.
我一周目玩到这里 我感觉我充满动力
At this moment in my first run, I felt motivated.
同时内心又觉得充满顾虑 字面意思上的不好的感觉
Yet still pretty dreadful, in again, the pure sense of the word dread overwhelmed me.
因为这类复仇对任何人来说都不会有好下场
These revenge quests never end well for anybody,
我不禁去想艾莉最后搞砸了 弄得自己死无葬身之地怎么办
and I couldn't help but feel as though Ellie was going to totally screw herself over
and end up dead in a ditch somewhere if she tried to do this.
但我觉得这也正是关键所在
But again, I think that's kind of the point.
玩家需要去融入艾莉 切身体会她的彷徨与疑虑
The player should be just as hesitant and doubtful as Ellie is in this pursuit.
诚然 艾莉嘴上说着要去怎样怎样砍死埃比还不带眨眼的
Sure, Ellie talks a big game and explains how she's going to go and kill Abby without any remorse,
要让埃比为自己的行为付出代价云云
and she's going to get revenge for this terrible act.
但艾莉自己还是时不时表现出些许的保留态度
But she still shows some slight reservations every once in a while.
她深知自己的行为在逻辑上是不合理的
She knows that this doesn't make a lot of logical sense
就像埃比最初肯定也知道自己一头扎进暴雪中的杰克逊小镇
in the same way that Abby knew that her plan to just go in storm Jackson
也没什么逻辑可言
didn't make a lot of logical sense,
但她们都去做了 因为她们认为这似乎是正确的
but they are going to try and do it because they felt as though it was the right thing to do,
这也是她们坚持下去的原因
and that's what kept them going.
这是一场情感与动机的拉锯战
It's a tug of war of emotions and motivations.
这样的冲突才会造就有趣的故事
And that conflict is what makes an interesting story.
你可以说你对TLOU2这部分故事有自己的见解
Say what you will about TLOU2 at this point in the story.
但游戏本身还是有趣的
But it's interesting and engaging,
可能剧情不是那种令人开心的爽剧
none the less, might not be fun might not be enjoyable,
但对我来讲游戏还是很有意思的
but it's interesting at least to me.
可能会有人不喜欢 那我也欢迎大家在下面留言
Maybe you hated it, and if you did, I would love to hear your thoughts down below,
不过说真的 可能不喜欢的人早就关掉视频了
but to be perfectly honest, you're probably not still here in this video.
如果这游戏没有任何一点让你觉得有趣的地方
If you don't find the story of this game, at least somewhat interesting,
你还看了一个多小时序章的测评内容 还没关视频 那你真是纯爷们
I mean, after all, we just got through the prologue and we are well over an hour into this video.
就这样 我们带着寻找埃比的新动力 进入了游戏核心部分的内容
So it's with that newfound motivation to find Abby that we enter the core of the game.
有着这样的动机驱使我们继续游戏是很有用的
And it's good that we have this emotional drive behind us
因为我们即将进入一段节奏非常慢的部分
because we're about to enter a very slow sequence of the game.
说真的 这段里面有些解密内容玩的我都感觉有点腻了
Seriously there's moments in here where I became actively bored because it was all puzzle solving in platform.
感觉有点……YUE
It's just kind of… blaaaah.
不过不急 我们稍后会提到
But don't worry, we're going to get into it.
西雅图
就这样 我们来到了「西雅图 第1天」
And with that we move to Seattle Day 1.
第1天
来西雅图的第一天 主要元素是“大门”
Our first day in Seattle starts with the gate,
一开始和蒂娜一边唠嗑一边穿过树林
basically riding through the forest, talking with Dina.
然后你要想办法进入城市的主体部分
And you have to try and get into the body of the city.
当然 有很多在隔离期结束前建立的军事设施后来都成了废墟
Of course, there's a lot of military installations that were put up
towards the end of quarantine that have since fallen to pieces.
总之 你得想办法进去
But nonetheless you have to get through them.
这里有一些可以搜集的补给品
There's a few supplies here and there that you can gather.
但这个区域的主要内容就是解谜
But for the most part, this is a puzzle solving sequence.
玩家爬上爬下各种建筑和梯子 从找到的纸条上发现一些数字 输进去
We climbed some buildings go up some ladders enter some codes that we find on some papers
然后进入了西雅图市区
and we push into Seattle.
这可能是游戏中我最讨厌的部分了
This was probably my least favorite part of the game.
我们充满干劲地来到这里
We're emotionally motivated.
我们想搞定几个人 从他们口中问出一些名字
We want to go, kick some ass and take some names
然后再去搞定那些问到的名字
and then give those names to other people whose asses we've kicked,
结果却卡在这绞尽脑汁去玩什么解谜
but instead we're forced to just slowly solved some basic puzzles.
找到写有数字密码的纸条 然后去其他地方
Write down some codes, walked to another place,
打开笔记本 翻开纸条 然后手动输入进去
pull open our note book to look back at what the codes were and then enter those in manually.
这可一点意思都没有
It's not that interesting,
这和玩家此时想要做的事情是完全冲突的
and it is in direct conflict with what the player wants to be doing at this point.
我理解顽皮狗可能想要在此把节奏放缓
I understand may be Naughty Dog wanted to slow the pace down
因为在游戏序章结束后你可能会有巨大的失落感
after how emotionally distraught you might be after the prologue.
但我还是感觉这里或许有更好的处理办法
But still, I can't help but feel as though there would have been a better way to do this
比如多来点战斗环节 比如向你介绍新的感染者
may be some more combat sequences, may be introducing you to a new type of infected.
管他呢 反正啥内容都比这样解谜要好
I'm not sure, anything I think would have been better than this.
接着我们到了市中心 据我的估计 这应该是游戏中最大的单体区域了
We get to downtown and by my estimation, this is the largest single area of the game.
场景非常开放 有大约11个主要地点
It's very open, and there's about eleven main locations,
至少我自己在这片区域内找到了这么多
at least that I found to explore in this little area.
包括一个银行 一个犹太教堂 一个法庭 都有很多细节在里面
This includes a bank, a synagogue, a court house all very well realized.
银行里面很有趣的是一切刚好定格在一群人准备抢劫的时候
The bank is cool because it's frozen in time, right after a group of people tried to rob,
我喜欢一边看着银行里散落的无数钞票
I loved seeing all of the money strewn throughout the bank
一边看艾莉和蒂娜聊着这个时代如果钱还能用她们会怎么花
and watching Ellie and Dina ponder what they would do with that money
if it actually was worth anything in their world.
我必须得说 顽皮狗真的很擅长这种架空世界观的构建
And I gotta say Naughty Dog is really good at this sort of indirect world building,
它会让你思考你目前生活中哪些才是真正重要的
it makes you question your actual priorities in your current life.
如果看视频的你是个瘫在椅子上一心只想着钱的死肥宅
If you're motivated purely by money and you have fat stack
sitting next to you as you watch this video,
那当你走进这个钞票如同废纸的末世 肯定会不禁感慨万千
you can't help but feel a little bit strange
when you walk into this post apocalyptic world and the money is absolutely useless.
正是这些琐碎之事才让玩家脑中迸发了思想的火花
It's those types of little things that get the wheels turning in your mind
让玩家身临其境般 进入游戏中这样的世界里去
to start putting yourself in the shoes of the characters in that world.
这也让顽皮狗非常擅长引导玩家能继续融入故事中去
That makes Naughty Dog so good at motivating players to continue engaging with the story.
然而在这个章节中我最喜欢的部分
My favorite part of this chapter, however,
是音乐商店中的一个可选的互动内容
is an optional item interaction in the music store of this section.
基本上如果你在这里与吉他互动 Ellie就会开始弹唱《Take On Me》给Dina听
And basically if you interact with the guitar here, Ellie will start playing and singing Take On Me to Dina.
它真的很动听 是这个已经很放松的部分中的另一份平静时刻
It's really beautiful and is another calm moment in this already relaxing section.
我真的很喜欢 也希望大家能享受这份平静 因为这份平静并不会持续太久
And I really enjoyed it, and I recommend that you also enjoy it because it's not going to last.
但是尽管这部分游戏的故事元素令人印象相当深刻
But while the story elements of this section of the game are pretty impressive,
我觉得你要探索的广阔区域并不像我认为顽皮狗希望的那样令人印象深刻
I don't feel as though the expansive areas that you're meant to explore are quite as impressive
as I think Naughty Dog was hoping they would be.
整个这片区域很容易让人联想到《神秘海域：失落的遗产》
This whole area is very reminiscent of the opening of The Lost Legacy,
顽皮狗的另一款《神秘海域》系列游戏
Naughty Dog's, other most recent Uncharted game.
在《失落的遗产》中 游戏给玩家提供了一大片可以探索的区域
In The Lost Legacy, You have a huge open expanse to explore.
但这种探索
But by explore,
本质上都是从一个地方到另一个地方 进行一些战斗
they pretty much mean that you move from one location to the other, fights some bad guys,
解开一些谜题 然后再去下一个地方
solve a quick little puzzle and then move to the next area.
它和大家心中所想的“开放世界”还是有些出入的
It's not actually exploring in the same way that you would probably show it in,
比如《塞尔达传说 旷野之息》里 玩家的确会主动探索地图
for instance, The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild, where you're actively exploring the map.
当然也可能是我的期望值太高了
Maybe my expectations were just out of check
因为顽皮狗说自己在这块区域下了很大功夫
because Naughty Dog did talk these sections up a lot,
说这是他们制作的游戏中场景最大的关卡
saying that these were the largest levels they had ever designed in any of their games ever,
在这方面也确实相当令人深刻
which is true and they're pretty impressive on that front.
但像《荒野大镖客：救赎2》那样
But in the age of Red Dead Redemption 2
骑马自由穿过田野也真不是什么了不起的成就
riding a horse through a field really isn't an incredible achievement.
当然我不是在顽皮狗和R星之间搞什么一踩一捧
Now, of course, it's not a competition between Naughty Dog and Rockstar.
他们都是不可多得的游戏制作组
They're both the prettiest girl in the ball, and you can't have either of them,
但我还是不禁感觉《荒野大镖客：救赎2》里的骑马和植被
but I can't help but notice as though the foliage and the horses in Red Dead Redemption 2
在开放世界当中 相比晚两年的TLOU2还是要强得多
looked a lot better two years ago, in an open world game, when compared to those in TLOU2.
可能是我太挑了 也可能只是我个人的喜好罢了
Maybe I'm just really picky or may be my preferences are a skew.
欢迎在评论区留言讨论
Let me know in the comments section below.
但我真的感觉两款游戏在这方面有很大差别 而且《荒野大镖客》更占上风
But I really do feel as though there's a strong difference between these two and it's in Red Dead's favor.
总之 玩家继续探索 终于打开了被锁住的大门
Nonetheless, you continue exploring the map and eventually pushed through the gate that was locked,
keeping you in this area,
感觉好安静 街上也没有WLF的人 骑马穿过检查点就好了
everything's quiet and you simply ride your horse through the checkpoint,
然后就……
at least until this happens.
男子：抓另一个！别把她追丢了！快去！
Man: Get the other! Don't lose her! Go!
艾莉：蒂娜。
Ellie: Dina.
艾莉醒来后 我们发现她被捆在一所名为伊斯特布鲁克的小学的桌子腿上
We open back up with Ellie, tied to a desk in a small elementary school called Eastbrook.
这不是重点 重点是艾莉现在被劫持为人质
This is not really important, what's important is that Ellie is being held hostage,
而蒂娜貌似已经脱身了
and Dina seems to have escaped.
艾莉马上要被撕票 而这时蒂娜从天而降……就是……没降落好
Ellie is about to be executed when Dina comes in and saves the day… Well, at least… almost.
你眼看着这个人就要勒死蒂娜 自己却束手无策
You watches this guy tries to strangle Dina, feeling absolutely helpless.
这段做的真的很棒
It's actually pretty well done.
我玩这段的时候感觉心都要蹦出来了
I found my heart rate increasing quite drastically during this.
最终 你用腿够到了一块碎玻璃
Eventually, use your foot to grab a shard of glass,
用它割断绑绳
use it to cut your bindings.
然后艾莉冲上前去 解决了正在攻击蒂娜的人
And Ellie goes up and kills Dina's attacker,
随后她从那个男子的口袋中找到了一封信和一张照片
at which point she grabs a letter and picture from his pocket.
稍后会很重要
Which will be important in just a little bit.
接下来是一系列和人类敌人的战斗
You are through a few combat sequences here that pair you against human enemies.
这样的节奏变换处理得很棒 让你从之前一直面对的感染者一转面对人类敌人
It's a nice change of pace from the infected that you've been dealing with exclusively up to this point,
让你不得不改变作战策略
and it forces you to change your approach.
比如从现在开始 你需要注意手电筒的灯光
For instance, you have to really be careful managing your flashlights.
面对绝大多数的感染者 你是不需要管手电筒开关的
Going up against most infected, you don't have to worry about your flashlight being on or off
因为它们看不见 或者不会有反应
because they can't see it or don't respond to it.
但人类敌人肯定看得见
With humans, of course they do.
人类敌人视觉更好 但听觉更差
They're much more visual and much less auditory,
而且战术上他们还会在需要的时候包抄偷袭你
though tactically flank you and maneuver around you if they need to,
同时他们也会对一些异常声响做出敏感的反应
though they can be lured with sound into traps very easily.
但在生还者难度下 如果你没有子弹了 那局面会很难受
But on Survivor difficulty, I will say it can be frustrating if you run out of ammo,
那时候你只能扔个瓶子然后走为上计
as your only option in dealing with them and ranged attacks is to throw bottles and rush
或者躺平 祈祷他们能绕开走
or just sit and pray that they come around.
我明白在这样一种末世下你做什么都不方便
I understand that it's a post apocalyptic world, and not everything is going to be convenient within it.
但真的很让人闹心
But nonetheless, it's pretty frustrating.
一路杀过去 转危为安后
After fighting your way to safety,
艾莉拿出了从攻击蒂娜的人身上搜出的文件和照片
Ellie looks at the document and the picture that she swiped off of Dina's attacker.
这是利娅给乔丹男朋友的照片 而你刚杀死的那个人就是乔丹
It's a new picture that Leah gave to her boyfriend, Jordan, who is actually the guy that you just killed.
但抱歉了各位 照片上有块血污挡住了关键信息
And sorry boys, but there's a blood smear that covers all of the good stuff,
所以暂停视频肯定没用啦
so no use in pausing the video.
现在来看 利娅刚好也是埃比“杀戮之旅”的成员
Now, Leah happens to be one of the people that joined Abby on their "kill-cation",
又一个巧合 引导艾莉前往13频道电视台寻找利娅
another coincidence that leads Ellie to the Channel 13 Station to find Leah,
而利娅有可能帮助艾莉找到埃比
who might be able to help them find the Abby in turn.
艾莉和蒂娜还从WLF成员的对话中听说了这个叫伊萨克的人
Ellie and Dina also hear about this guy Isaac in conversations that can be overheard from the WLF members.
虽然我们对这个人的消息了解得不多
Now not much is known about this guy or revealed about him for that matter, for quite a while.
但我们知道的是他貌似负责运营WLF 而且权力很大
But what we do know is that he seemingly runs the WLF, and he has a firm grip on power.
大家都听他的 还都很害怕他
Everyone does what he says and are scared of him.
顽皮狗的游戏按照惯例会将此作为后来与伊萨克的Boss战的铺垫
Naughty Dog games of the past would use this as a set up for the later boss fight with Isaac.
既然提到他了 那他在游戏后面肯定是个关键角色了对吧？
If he's mentioned, he'll be a key part of the story later, right?
恭喜你答错了
Well, actually wrong.
这样的事情还会在未来另一个角色身上发生 可能是为续作之类的内容做准备
This will happen again with another character later, maybe it's a set up for a sequel or something.
但就伊萨克和另一位即将登场女性角色来说 这样的事情的确没有发生
But… as for Isaac himself and the other lady that's going to be shown off, it actually doesn't come around.
总之接下来艾莉和蒂娜继续前往城市中心 寻找13频道电视台
All of that said Ellie and Dina head into the heart of the city to find the Channel 13 Station
追捕利娅 想办法从她那里获得更多埃比的消息
to hunt down Leah to try and in turn, get more information on Abby.
你继续推进 顺手杀了一堆WLF士兵和感染者
You push through a ton of WLF soldiers and lots of infected as well.
你发现地上有绊雷 不禁想起一代里的比尔
You find some trip wire traps set up that reminded me of Bill from the first game.
但在这里它们除了减慢游戏探索速度之外似乎没有任何作用
But here they don't seem to serve any purpose other than to slow down game play and exploration then.
就我个人而言我很快发现这些绊雷的乐趣所在——它们就是单纯的烦
Personally I just soon find these trip wire bombs fun. They're just annoying.
偶尔用一些新的不同的东西来为单调的游戏调味的想法是好的
It's good to shake up the monotony of game play every once in a while that something new and different,
比如这些绊雷
such as these trip wire minds.
而在这里 这些绊雷并没有在游戏剩余部分中出现
But in this case, these things don't really come up again for the rest of the game.
它们只是一种不会让你形成游戏中新的习惯行为的烦人道具
They're just a one of frustration that doesn't actually drive you into any sort of new habitual behavior.
换句话说 在大多数游戏中 制作者向你介绍一个新的游戏元素
In other words in most games, when they introduce you to a new gameplay element,
其原因是这个元素会在游戏的剩余部分中用到
it's because it's going to be used throughout the rest of the game,
所以你需要学会掌握它
which is why you need to be taught how to deal with it.
但在这里 这个元素用的很少 而且很多可以避开
But in this case they're used very sparingly and in most cases they are entirely avoidable.
当然了 这可能是我自己的小癖好罢了
But granted. This is probably just a pet peeve on my end.
接下来你会遇到游戏中最棒的收集品
So you come up on the station after finding the best collectable in the game.
马赛克马赛克马赛克马赛克马赛克马赛克马赛克马赛克
之后你继续探索
And you begin exploring it,
来到一处疤脸帮某种仪式的事后现场
you find the remnants of a Scar ceremony of some sort.
有很多被吊起来开肠破肚的尸体
There's a bunch of bodies that are strung up everywhere and that have been disemboweled.
虽然不清楚具体是什么时候发生的 但肯定是最近
Now it's not clear exactly when this happened, but it seems relatively recent.
我相信肯定有人像我一样这时候突然意识到
Now if you're anything like me, you would have immediately realized that
即使找到利娅也不太可能对你寻找埃比有什么帮助
Leah is probably not going to be in any sort of condition to help you find Abby,
尤其疤脸帮已经弄得这里一片狼藉了
especially after all of this Scar stuff.
就算她还在电视台里 那也很可能已经死了
If she's even still in the station, she is probably dead.
果不其然 你来到电视台顶楼一间办公室内
And sure enough you finally at the top of the station in an office
发现她已经被射成刺猬了
shot dead with a bunch of arrows sticking out of her.
但没事 我们可以强凑巧合呀
But the coincidence is common clutch and save the day
这不 艾莉决定打开利娅行军床下的手提兜
because Ellie decides to open up Leah's duffel bag underneath her cot,
然后恰好有每一位去杰克逊小镇追杀乔尔的成员照片
which just happens to have pictures of all of the team members that went to Jackson and killed Joel.
显然 他们把整件事都记录得明明白白
Apparently, they basically have logged the whole thing,
所以我才管他们这趟叫“杀戮之旅”
which is why I called a "kill-cation" earlier.
这可能是，我觉得不止可能，它就是
This is probably, and to be perfectly honest, I think it is
靠巧合推动游戏剧情发展的最糟糕的例子
the most egregious example of coincidence is driving this story.
他们需要让艾莉牢牢把这些人的名字和长相记在脑海中
They needed Ellie to be reminded and have some sort of firm idea
of what these people looked like and what their names were,
这样她就能问别人这人是谁 这人在哪
so that she could ask other people who they were and where they were,
但他们完全想不出一个让艾莉通过更合理的手段获得这些信息的办法
they couldn't come up with any reasonable way of her coming up with this information herself,
所以就只好让她直接去“碰巧”找到一个被遗弃的包
so instead they had to have her stumble onto it by finding a bag that happened to be left behind,
然后包里还刚好被一个有工作任务的女子放置了所有的照片
that happened to have all of these pictures placed in it by some lady that was on a work assignment.
而且利娅甚至不应该在电视台呆很久
And that's the thing she wasn't even really supposed to be at this TV station for very long,
所以我完全搞不懂为啥她要随身带着所有这些照片……
so I don't understand why she would have brought all of these pictures very precious to…
实在想不通
I… I just, I don't understand.
算了 反正想也没有用
But I'll stop beating the dead horse there.
在你找到照片后不久 WLF的人就来了 以为你是疤脸帮
Right as you find the photos, WLF members show up and assuming that you're a Scar
冲进大楼想要找到你们俩
pushed through the entire building to find Ellie and Dina.
你和他们一番战斗后逃往了地下
You fight them and escaped through the basement
最终来到了地铁系统中
which leads to the underground tunnel system for the subway.
这段交战看起来挺难的
This encounter seems really intimidating at first,
但实际上想打过去还是挺简单的
but rest assured, it's actually pretty easy to spam.
比如视频中的例子 把燃烧瓶扔准 效果刚刚的
As you can see in this instance, if you know what I use a good Molotov cocktail, you can work wonders.
当你进入地铁
Once you're in the subway system,
你会遇到新的名为跛行者的感染者 会走到你面前释放一种酸雾
you find some new zombies known as Shamblers, which eject a sort of acidic cloud when at the road.
在普通难度下 我其实感觉它们令人失望的简单
At Normal difficulty, I will actually say that these things are disappointingly easy to kill,
简直完全不符合我的预期
like they do not meet the expectation at all.
它们抱住你的时候完全没有叫声听起来那么吓人
Their bite is nowhere near as bad as their bark,
但到了二周目生还者难度 这玩意虐你简直跟玩一样
but on Survivor new game plus, these things can eat my entire ass,
当然可能只有我自己会在之前觉得应付跛行者不难
and maybe it was just me that had an easy time with these Shamblers,
也可能是我对它期待太高了
or perhaps just expected way more for them.
因为有证据表明顽皮狗希望玩家能在这里遇到一些困难
Because there are some signs that Naughty Dog expected players to have more trouble with these guys.
比如蒂娜这样锁门的动作
I mean, look at how Dina locks this door.
我第一次玩还感觉有点奇怪
I thought this was kind of weird in my first run through
因为门那边已经什么都没有了
because there was nothing left to keep from getting through.
所有感染者都死了
All of the zombies were dead.
我为了防止它们跑出来 把它们都杀掉了
I killed them all, and there was nothing left in that room to prevent from escaping.
但在我二周目游戏中
But in my new game plus run,
我把绝大多数感染者留在里面 潜行通过了此区域
I snuck through this section, leaving many or even most of those infected alive.
这样 把门锁上这个操作就很合理了
In that case, locking this door made a lot more sense.
但在一周目普通难度下 杀死所有感染者后
But on my first run, on a normal difficulty with all of the zombies dead,
看蒂娜还去锁门的动作就显得怪怪的
it really seemed strange that Dina wanted to lock this door down.
虽然无关痛痒 但就是感觉怪怪的
I mean, I guess it can't hurt, but still it just seemed odd.
我觉得这是一个很好的例子
This is a simple, but I think it's an effective example of
能够说明顽皮狗可能很希望玩家能潜行通过这片区域
how Naughty Dog likely expected more players to stealth their way through these sections.
艾莉和蒂娜继续穿过这些隧道
Now Ellie and Dina continue to push through these tunnels.
这段场景玩的时候总能让我回想起一代游戏的内容
And it's actually a pretty cool sequence going through these things again when remembering the first game.
因为在一代里 艾莉是不会游泳的
Because of course, in the first game, Ellie couldn't even swim.
乔尔就得先去找漂浮物才能把艾莉送到目的地
And Joel had to use all sorts of floating platforms to get her from one area to the next.
而到了二代 艾莉会的东西多了
In this case, Ellie is much more capable.
真要说帮助 那也只能是艾莉去帮蒂娜
And if anything, it's Dina, who requires a little more babying.
但在探索了几条这样的隧道并爬过一些车厢后 其中一节车厢倒塌了
But after exploring a few of these tunnels and climbing through some train cars, one of them collapses.
然后她们被一群感染者扑倒 艾莉摔了一跤 她的面具摔碎了
Ellie takes a tumble as they're jumped by a bunch of infected and Ellie's mask actually cracks,
导致艾莉完全暴露在孢子中
leaving her exposed to the spores.
蒂娜显然吓坏了 以为艾莉死定了
Dina understandably starts to freak out, thinking that Ellie is going to die.
艾莉一边说她没事 先赶紧跑到地面上要紧
Ellie says she's fine as they raced to the street level
一边告诉蒂娜千万不要摘掉面具给两人共用
and insists that Dina does not take off her mask to share between the two of them.
你俩一路连滚带爬总算到了地面层
You fight your way all the way up to the street level,
关好门 看到马路对面有一家老剧院
locked the door behind you and look across the street and see an old theatre.
你们决定去那歇脚
You decide to take refuge there,
幸好这里防守还算牢靠 门也可以从里面上锁
and thankfully it's fairly well guarded, defensible, and the doors do lock from the inside.
艾莉和蒂娜进入剧院 准备在此歇息
Ellie and Dina break in, take refuge and start to rest.
蒂娜显然很悲伤 因为她以为艾莉要死了
Dina is understandably upset because she thinks that Ellie is going to die.
毕竟她刚眼睁睁看着艾莉吸入了孢子
After all, she just saw her inhale spores.
而对于据她所知的任何人类来说这无异于被宣判了死刑
And for any other human being that she knows that would be an instant death sentence.
但艾莉是个例外 她没事
But instead, Ellie seems fine. There's no problem.
这时艾莉再一次解释了她自己有免疫的事情
And it's at this point that Ellie again explains how she's actually immune.
她之前曾经和蒂娜在尤金的地下室大麻屋里解释过
She previously explained this to Dina
back when they were in Eugene's basement weed emporium.
然而当时蒂娜看起来并没有相信
However, it seemed back then that Dina did not believe her thought
她以为艾莉只是在骗她 开了个很黑色幽默的玩笑
that she was pulling your leg and just thought it was a cruel joke.
但现在蒂娜明白过来这可能是真的
But now Dina understands that this might actually be true,
虽然我感觉蒂娜好像没太把这当回事
although I will say that Dina never really seems to go any further with this.
她的爱人的天赋可是免疫一种能感染地球上所有人类的真菌
Her love interest is immune from the fungus that is infecting all of life on the planet.
但她好像丝毫不感兴趣
And she doesn't seem that interesting in it.
真的 我不确定她在整个游戏后来是否还提起过此事
Really, I'm not sure if she brings it up ever again throughout the entire game,
哪怕是游戏后面的场景片段里
even in the later cut scenes and sequences.
这点就有点奇怪
It's just a little strange,
我明白这个故事流程里涉及到很多内容
I understand there's a lot to get through during the course of this story.
也有可能某个片段她们更深入地交流了这方面的事情
And perhaps there were scenes that had been written where they discuss it further,
但最终被减掉了……我也不确定
but it was eventually cut… I'm not sure.
总之我感觉蒂娜没再跟艾莉提起她的免疫这件事是很奇怪的
But all I know is that it seems strange that Dina doesn't engage with Ellie further on this matter.
同时还是在剧院里 蒂娜说她感觉自己好像怀孕了
While also in the theater, Dina explains that she thinks that she's pregnant.
因为之前蒂娜和杰西在一起过 然后分手了 一周后又和艾莉亲亲了
You see, she dated Jesse, broke up with him a week before Ellie and Dina's kiss.
那显然孩子是杰西的
And that would mean that the baby is Jesse's.
这又让这些人之间的关系变得更加复杂
This, of course complicates the relationship between all of them.
我个人对这个剧情丝毫不感觉意外
Now, personally, this came as no surprise at all to me.
前面三四个小时的游戏内容铺垫下来
After all of the signaling that they did for the last three or so hours of game play
加之如果你完整读过艾莉的日记
and if you were reading Ellie's journal at all,
那你可能比艾莉知道得还早
you'll know this well ahead of Ellie.
蒂娜吐了几次 说是自己感觉不太好 太累了
Dina was puking a lot, saying that she wasn't feeling well, saying that she was tired,
把这些归于一路的血腥厮杀 但实际上只是孕吐
blaming a lot of things on the gore around her, but in reality it was morning sickness.
此外 在听到埃比和欧文讨论欧文的爱人梅尔 以及她的怀孕问题后
Furthermore, having heard Abby and Owen discuss Mel, Owen's other love interest, and her pregnancy,
基本上就石锤了
it seemed like a slam dunk
顽皮狗想让艾莉这边阵营某个人也怀孕这件事
that Naughty Dog was going to have somebody in Ellie's friend circle become pregnant
这样顽皮狗才可以在之后构建两条平行的故事
so that they could draw a further parallel later.
你看我说什么来着
Sure enough, that's exactly what they did.
总之 艾莉最后让蒂娜去睡觉 自己则走开了
Regardless, Ellie breaks away, allowing Dina to sleep.
这段尴尬的谈话过后 你想办法为剧院恢复了供电
You get some electricity running after the awkward conversation
并在技师的休息间里偶然找到了一个收音机
and stumble upon a radio in a technician's closet.
它坏掉了 艾莉很郁闷 于是给了收音机一巴掌
It's broken, Ellie becomes frustrated and wax at in frustration,
然后刚好就发现了进入剧院里面的钥匙
which is how she actually finds the keys that led her into the deeper areas of the theater.
我不明白为什么钥匙会出现在收音机下面
I don't know why the keys were under the radio.
但安排让沮丧的艾莉给机器一巴掌可真方便啊
It's almighty convenient that she hit the radio in frustration in the first place
因为不然她可就拿不到钥匙了呀
because if she didn't, she wouldn't have found the keys.
随便吧 你们懂的 我又开始抱怨游戏里的巧合了
But whatever, you get the point, I have been complaining about coincidences in this whole videos.
你们理解了就好 我们继续
So you get the point. I'll just, I'll move on.
你在剧院的后台找到一把吉他
You find a guitar in the back of the theater
并弹奏了在之前的闪回中乔尔给艾莉弹、还要教艾莉的同一首歌
and play the same song that we saw Joel played for Ellie in the flashback
wherein he was teaching Ellie how to play.
艾莉弹了几段 然后游戏又切入了一段闪回
She plays the first few bars, and then we cut to a flashback.
可能是整个游戏里我最喜欢的闪回了
Probably my favorite flashback of the entire game.
画面中是乔尔和艾莉
It's Joel and Ellie.
时间应该是艾莉的生日
It seems to be Ellie's birthday,
乔尔要带她去找她的生日礼物
and Joel is taking her to find her birthday gift.
这段内容除了温馨就是感动
There's not much to say about this sequence other than that it's very touching and sweet.
乔尔找到了这样一个门口有个大恐龙的博物馆
Joel found this museum that had a giant dinosaur statue in it
因为他知道艾莉梦想是见一见恐龙
because he knew that Ellie dreamed of seeing dinosaurs.
她还有个梦想就是去太空
She also wants to go to space, one of her dreams is to go to space.
所以乔尔还带她去了航天展区
And he takes her to the astronaut exhibit,
艾莉可以戴上头盔 进入真实的阿波罗指令舱
wherein she can put on a helmet and then climb into the actual capsule.
乔尔之后也进去了 给了艾莉一盒磁带让她听
Joel hops in too, gives her a headset and allows her to zone out
艾莉一边听一边想象自己坐着火箭起飞前往太空
while imagining herself going into space and taking off.
这段看着很像在一代DLC《最后生还者：遗落》里
This sequence is actually just like the arcade one in Left Behind the DLC from the first game
艾莉和莱莉脑补玩街机游戏的场景
wherein Ellie and Riley were imagining playing this video game.
机器显然没法玩了 因为已经坏好久了
Of course they couldn't play it, it was long since broken.
但莱莉让艾莉闭上眼睛 脑补自己描述的画面
But Riley had Ellie close her eyes and imagine everything while she described it.
我觉得这两个场景如此相近肯定不是巧合
You'd better believe it's no coincidence that these two events are so similar.
这个场景非常的简单
It's a super simple scene.
但这只是为了进一步确定乔尔和艾莉有很深的羁绊 也非常关心彼此
But it just serves to further establish that Joel and Ellie had a deep relationship and care for each other.
同时 两人的关系也非常复杂
Also that their relationship is pretty complicated.
因为这段闪回的最后 你在墙上看到了一个涂鸦
Because at the very end of this scene you come across a writing on the wall.
不用说 这明显是乔尔和艾莉都不想讨论的事
And needless to say, it's something that Joel and Ellie don't want to discuss.
于是俩人直接回去了
So they just leave.
西雅图 第2天
然后 我们来到了「西雅图 第2天」
And after that we jumped to Seattle Day 2.
西雅图第2天开始
Starting out our second day in Seattle,
艾莉在剧院醒来后看到蒂娜在放收音机的房间里吐
Ellie wakes up in the theater and finds Dina in the radio room vomiting,
算是对闪回之前剧情内容的一次挺直接的提醒
a not so subtle reminder of the revelation that we saw before the flashback.
蒂娜一直在监听电台 破译WLF的通讯内容
She's been listening to the radio, deciphering the WLF's communications
想要找出追杀乔尔那帮人的可能位置
to figure out where members of Joel's assassination party might be.
蒂娜和艾莉在WLF广播中听到在14区有一个枪手
Dina and Ellie overhear a WLF broadcast together that there's a lone gunman in Zone 14.
她们猜测这个14区就是不远的希尔科列斯特 艾莉决定亲自去调查一番
They guess that this is a neighborhood called Hillcrest and Ellie heads out to investigate.
她们认为这个枪手就是汤米 毕竟……还能是谁啊？
They think that this could be Tommy because, well, who else could it be?
抱歉 是我家猫在我键盘上乱打的 不关我的事
Sorry for the bell, I have a kitten on my lap and she's making noise.
但……反正肯定真不是汤米啦
But yeah, shocker have… of course it's not Tommy.
你操控艾莉继续穿过几个不同的区域
Playing as Ellie, you push through a few different areas,
和各种WLF的人作战 搜刮各种建筑
fighting all sorts of wolfs and looting lots of buildings.
大约三十分钟无事发生的探索后
Not much happens for around thirty minutes of exploring
所有WLF似乎瞬间和艾莉一起涌向了一个远处冒烟的地方
until all of the WLF seems to descend at the same spot,
a smoke signal that Ellie also follows.
这里的关卡设计真的很棒
The level design here is really fantastic.
这里使用了远处某个可见物体来引导玩家继续进行关卡
This use of a visual objective in the distance that you can follow as you go through the level.
这样设计很棒 而且顽皮狗使用类似的设计已经很久了
It's really well done, and it's something Naughty Dog has been doing for a long time
他们非常擅长于此
and that they really have perfected.
这里的一些关卡也非常难
Now these level really crescendos in difficulty,
尤其在高难度设定下 难度的峰值会急剧增加
especially in harder difficulty settings where difficulty spikes are far more severe.
这里我想说的是如果你之前没有节约 就很容易陷入没有弹药进退两难的地步
Now the thing about this is that you'll get caught with no ammo in this level
if you're not careful and use it all too early.
因此你必须处处节省
So you have to be very careful to preserve it.
但问题在于一周目下你并不知道
But the problem is on your first run through you're not going to know
弹药会消耗如此之快
that you're going to run out of ammo so quickly.
你不可能预知此事
You couldn't have known.
所以你会一直省着弹药 一枪都不想开
So in turn you are always careful and never want to use any of your ammo whatsoever.
但如果你一直这样小心翼翼处处节约的话
But when that's the case, you are always careful,
就意味着你的游戏行为不会有任何改变
which also means that you never are because your behavior isn't changing in any way.
你会一直不使用自己的弹药
You are just refusing to use ammo,
然后这个游戏就慢慢变成了一个近战肉搏游戏
so you're effectively playing through the game as a melee game.
这种不想用弹药的游戏行为我在很多恐怖游戏里见过
It's this game play hesitance that I have noticed in a lot of horror video games,
尤其是那些弹药稀缺的游戏
especially where ammo is very limited.
我觉得这样挺怪的 因为我认为这并不算是好的游戏体验
It's strange to me because I don't think it actually reflects a better game play experience
因为这会让玩家无法参与到多样的游戏机制中去
because it just ends up with the player refusing to use multiple mechanics
因为他们害怕如果随随便便使用了弹药
because they are scared that if they do use them,
就会很快耗光弹药 之后就很尴尬了
they're going to run out of ammo and be unable to use them later on.
但我也能理解如果彻底抛弃这样的游戏系统又会有一种因噎废食的感觉
But I understand that getting rid of this system could also be like throwing the baby out with the bathwater.
总之 艾莉来到了冒烟的地方
Though regardless, Ellie pushes to the smokestack,
在WLF的地盘上或杀穿 或潜行
killing and evading all sorts of WLF members while she goes.
最终解锁了弓箭
You eventually unlock the bow and arrow here,
这可能是游戏中我最喜欢的武器了
which is actually probably my favorite weapon of the whole game.
它不会发出声响 根据射中的位置和游戏难度的不同还有可能回收弓箭
It's silent, you can recollect a lot of the ammo depending on where you hit the enemy
and on what difficulty you're playing.
总之我喜欢这款武器 它真的很好用
And all around I just like it, I find it really satisfying.
艾莉来到了冒烟的地方下 然后……
She reaches the location of the smoke stack, and then this happens.
男子：嘘嘘！
Man: Shh, shh!
艾莉：你到底在这里干嘛？
Ellie: What the hell are you doing here?
杰西：你觉得我会坐视不顾吗？
Jesse: Think I'd let you do this on your own?
我觉得这实在是太怪了……因为……
This is really weird to me… because…
据我所知艾莉回头看见的应该是乔尔才对
as far as I knew, this was going to be Joel when Ellie turned around,
所以当我看到预告片里的画面即将发生的时候 真的满脑子都是问号
and I was really confused when I saw that we were getting to that point where the trailer happened.
我也知道乔尔已经死了
And I knew that Joel was dead.
那他怎么可能会回来拯救艾莉呢？
How could he possibly show up and save the day?
但最后明白了 原来是杰西
But sure enough, it ends up being Jesse.
我感觉他们选择用这种方法迷惑大家实在是太怪了
It's just strange to me that they chose to do this fake out,
因为我们都以为这里出现的会是乔尔
where we thought that it was going to be Joel here,
因为预告片里都放了
because that's what the trailer showed,
结果出现的是……感觉真的……太怪了……我感觉太怪了
and then it ends up being just… It's just it's weird… It's weird to me.
我感觉我都无语了
I don't know what else to say.
如果你有更多相关的信息 请务必在评论区告诉我
If you have more information on this, let me know in the comments section below,
我就是……觉得怪 已经不知道说什么了
I just…  it's weird. I don't know what to make of it.
总之 艾莉和杰西想方设法偷了辆车逃跑了
Nonetheless, Ellie and Jessie managed to escape by way of a stolen car
然后一段流畅的战斗后车子开进河里了 这段发售前也泄露过
that they drive into a river in a pretty impressive sequence that also leaked pre launch.
这段战斗简直是如丝般顺滑 不只是因为他们把车开水里去了
It's a superfluid sequence, and no, I'm not just saying that because they end up in a river,
我觉得打磨得非常棒 观感非常震撼
I think it's very well polished and it looks incredible to boot.
但当然了 毕竟这是顽皮狗的游戏嘛
But then again, I mean, this is a Naughty Dog game wouldn't expect anything else.
你把杰西带了回去 也带回了成吨的尴尬
You bring Jesse back to Dina and there's a ton of tension here.
艾莉自己先回去了 因为她被尬得实在绷不住了
Ellie, of course, leaves because she feels very awkward.
毕竟艾莉的女朋友的孩子的爸爸出现在面前
After all Ellie's girlfriend's baby daddy just showed up.
我觉得她很难能绷住
I don't blame her for wanting to leave.
随着艾莉慢慢往回走 我们来到了下一个闪回场景 这个场景实际上非常简单
As Ellie walks away, we jump into another flashback, and this one's actually pretty simple.
艾莉先是和汤米学习狙击枪的使用
Ellie and Joel are exploring a hotel while on their way to a music store
然后和乔尔去音像店的路上探索一家旅馆
after Ellie receives a lesson on sniping from Tommy.
这样的安排还是挺随意的
And this may seem really random,
因为狙击枪其实并不是艾莉整个游戏里的主要武器
especially because sniping will not be a major mechanic for Ellie throughout the entire game.
但游戏在此教玩家使用狙击枪还是有原因的
But there actually is a reason for them showing the player this sniping tutorial.
不过我稍后会细讲
I'll get to that more in a little bit, though.
汤米的狙击教学结束后 你和他骑马来到山脚下 发现乔尔正坐在那
After you finish your sniping tutorial with Tommy, ride back down the hill and find Joel sitting there
你打算和他一起去音像店找找有没有吉他弦
and you prepare to go out with him to find some guitar strings at a music store.
一个冷知识：原本这里的剧情安排是完全不同的另一种内容
Now, A fun little detail is that this actually was originally an entirely different plot.
原来的剧情是 艾莉上完了汤米的狙击课
Originally after Ellie finished her sniping tutorial with Tommy,
打算和乔尔去见他的女朋友 就住在沿着路走不远的地方
she and Joel were going to go and say Hi to Joel's girlfriend who lived just a little ways down the road.
他们打算骑马过去 到了以后发现乔尔的女朋友刚刚被咬了
They were going to ride up, find Joel's girlfriend having been freshly bitten
然后他们不得不做出一些非常艰难的选择
and they were going to be forced to make a difficult choice.
几个人来回争论了一下接下来该做什么
While they all negotiated back and forth what they should do about it,
然后乔尔和他女朋友让艾莉去小溪边取一些干净的水来
they send Ellie outside to grab some fresh water from the stream.
然后艾莉一出门 就听见砰的一声枪响
Once Ellie walks outside, she hears a gunshot,
然后乔尔走了出来 大家都知道发生了什么
and then Joel walks out, and they know that something happened.
他们都知道……乔尔的女朋友死了
They know that… she's gone.
可能是乔尔帮忙结束了她的痛苦
And either Joel put her out of her misery at her request,
也可能是她不想让乔尔做这个艰难的决定 于是自我了断了
or she put herself out of her own misery because she knew that she didn't want Joel have to do it for her,
因为他们都知道这样的结果是什么
because they knew how this was going to end.
总之 这将是一个非常感人的时刻
Regardless, it would have been a very touching moment
而且能看到乔尔和艾莉一起经历这些还是很有趣的
and interesting thing to see Joel and Ellie experience together.
他再次经历了失去至爱的时刻 而这次有艾莉陪他
Joel experiencing another loss and using Ellie to help him get through it.
但显然 根据游戏实际内容 和尼尔·德鲁克曼等一众编剧的评论
But apparently, according to the press release and comments by Neil Druckmann and all of his writing staff,
这段被删改成当前的内容了
this scene was cut in favor of this new scene
两人从一个废弃旅馆中穿过 抄近道去音像店
where they go and explore a hotel cutting through to a music store.
因为制作人认为之前那样安排太偏离故事重点了
Because they felt as though it was too much of a diversion from the priorities of the story.
换句话说 这部游戏是讲艾莉的 不是讲乔尔的
In other words, this is a game about Ellie, it's not a game about Joel.
而如果这段场景过于关注乔尔 那会给人感觉这个游戏是只关注他俩的
And if they had this scene focused on Joel, it would start to feel much more like a Joel AND Ellie Game.
而不是关于乔尔和艾莉、只能控制艾莉的游戏 当然大家怎么理解都好
But a Joel and Ellie game, where your only playing as Ellie, but make of that what you will.
你们穿过一间间客房 清理了大量感染者
You cut through the resort, clearing out a ton of infected
感觉颇有第一代游戏那味 感觉很不错
and it actually feels a lot like the first game, it's pretty nice.
在酒店里 乔尔还坚持让艾莉戴上防毒面具
As they pushed through the resort, Joel insists that Ellie wear her mask,
即使她对孢子免疫
even though she's immune to the spores.
艾莉问为何要多此一举
she asks why she'd would need to do this,
毕竟旅馆里没有别人
after all, it's just them exploring the hotel.
乔尔解释说 如果有人看到她 一定会引来相当多不必要的麻烦
And he says, because if somebody saw her, they would have a lot of questions understandably.
所以为了避免这些 她还是戴上了
So it's better to be safe than sorry, she should just wear it.
这也解释了我们在之前和其它场景里那样看到艾莉戴着面具的原因
and this explains why she was wearing it
and all of the other sequences like we talked about at the beginning.
她听从乔尔的要求一直戴着面具 因为她不想让其他人发现她的免疫能力
She wore the mask at Joel's insistence because she didn't want to risk anybody finding out
因为这样会带来太多的麻烦
because it would cause too much trouble,
或者甚至还要费劲去按乔尔的说法去解释在火萤那发生的事
or it just wasn't worth the headache of explaining everything that went down with the Fireflies,
even if Joel was going to stick to his original story of what happened.
但又一次和乔尔解决了一堆感染者和一个小boss
But after pushing through a ton of infected fighting, a mini boss fight with Joel again,
让人联想到第一场游戏的感动 并牵动了我所有的心弦之后
very reminiscent of the first game touching and tugging on all of my heart strings,
他们最终找到了几个月前离开杰克逊小镇的一对夫妇
they end up finding a couple that left Jackson a few months before
引出了两人关于在医院最后发生了什么的对话
which spurs a conversation about what happened at the hospital.
不幸的是 乔尔又选择了说谎
Unfortunately, Joel continues to lie.
艾莉：你为什么趁我还没醒过来就把我带走？
Ellie: Why did you pull me out of there while I still unconscious?
乔尔：因为我让他们进行了测试，
Joel: Because I let them run their tests,
我发现他们根本没有用，所以我就带你离开了——
and when I saw that they were useless, I got us out of there--
艾莉：你怎么知道他们没有用？
Ellie: How do you know they were useless?
如果你再给他们一点时间，也许他们就能找到方法——
Maybe if you just woulda given them more time, they could have figured something out--
乔尔：艾莉！
Joel: Ellie!
根本没有治愈的方法。
There was no cure.
我们救不了这两个人或是其他人。
There's nothing that could've helped these people or anybody else.
我知道你希望事情有所改变——我也一样。
I know you wish things were different -- I wish things were different.
但事实就是如此。
But they ain't.
镜头回到在剧院包扎伤口的艾莉
We then cut to Ellie, patching up a cut in the theater.
蒂娜上前帮助她 顺便化解了一下刚刚杰西到来后的尴尬氛围
Dina helps her and they try to resolve some of the awkward tension
that they just experienced after Jesse's arrival.
蒂娜说她用无线电发现了追杀乔尔小队里的诺拉
Dina reveals that she's figured out using the radio that Nora, one of the Joel's squad
现在就在医院里 她可能知道埃比在哪
is stationed at the hospital and may know where Abby is.
艾莉立刻出发前往医院
Ellie takes off immediately and heads for that hospital,
而这其实是游戏里非常安静的一章
and this is actually pretty quiet chapter of the game.
因为显然 艾莉是独自行动
Because Ellie is, of course by herself.
没人会来帮她 只能靠她自己
There's no one to bounce anything off of, she's just alone.
而制作组也利用这个机会给玩家设了好多措手不及的局
And they are actually able to throw a couple curve balls at the player as a result of this,
我非常非常喜欢这点
which I actually really really enjoyed.
最好的例子就是艾莉在工作台这里
The best example would probably be when Ellie walks up to a workbench,
游戏中工作台是用来升级武器的
which is where you do all of your maintenance on all of your weapons,
用你满世界搜刮来的零件资源给你的武器升级
adding upgrades changing things out using the scrap that you find in the world,
而就在这时惊喜来了
at which point she's jumped.
WLF士兵：抓到她了！我抓到她了！
我们不会回去，听懂了吗？！
艾莉：放开我！
WLF士兵：杀了她！
我第一次玩的时候感觉这段太牛逼了
I thought this was super cool when I saw it,
我当时就……我靠！在菜单里也能被偷袭吗！
I was like ah… shoot! I'm not even safe in the menus now!
我……我理解可能有些人会被吓到 甚至有些生气
I… I… I understand this probably pissed some people off when freaked them out.
因为一般来讲在游戏的菜单界面肯定是绝对安全的
Because if anything, in video games' menus are sacred, you should be safe in a menu.
但这个例子打破了这个惯例 我觉得太棒了
But in this case you're not, and I just thought it was awesome.
我们现在也来顺便聊聊游戏的制造系统
Now let's also take this chance to discuss crafting a little bit.
这代的制造系统和第一作非常像
The crafting system is pretty much identical to the first game,
只是多了几项武器 比如爆破筒
except there's a few new items like pipe bombs.
多数的角色升级选项一般只能点满一半的“技能树”
Most character upgrades will only get about halfway through their upgrade tree
很多游戏都这么叫 我就也这样说了
if you want to call it that throughout most runs.
二周目玩完两人各自那一半内容的话能点满艾莉和埃比的技能
New game plus lets you max Level Ellie and Abby
by the time you're done playing each of their respective halves of the game,
点满以后感觉自己都无敌了
which does make you feel like a superhero.
在高难度下 这些制作素材真的少得可怜
Now on higher difficulties, these crafting items are stupid scarce, really.
它们非常难找 一般也不会在游戏世界里自动刷新出来
They're pretty hard to find than they don't tend to generate or populate in the world itself
除非你在游戏里真的走投无路了
unless you are really struggling later in the game.
但顽皮狗在TLOU系列游戏里的动态难度调整得真的很不错
But these dynamic policemen systems that Naughty Dog uses in these TLOU games works pretty well
这方面的抱怨其实不多 除了治疗系统
and they don't have a lot of complaints about them, except for healing items.
游戏中各种快速回血的零食小吃在高难度下实在太多了
These quick snacks and things that refill your health are far too plentiful on high difficulties,
至少我认为如此 这让游戏变得太简单
at least in my mind, it makes the game too easy,
即使对于例如生还者难度来说也是这样
even though the combat is remarkably hard on, for instance, Survivor.
这里一部分原因我觉得是燃烧瓶和医疗包的制作材料相同
Part of the reason this is a problem in my mind is because Molotovs are crafted using the same materials.
所以实际上玩家经常会面对二选一的局面
So effectively, the player is always faced with a choice
做医疗包还是做燃烧瓶
between crafting a health kit and a Molotov cocktail.
看上去很蠢但我觉得其实很重要
Seems like a stupid delineation to draw, but I think it's important.
因为医疗包的使用只能说明玩家操控出现了重大失误
You see, health kits just represent a major mistake on the part of the player.
如果在高难度下犯下重大失误 那基本就是个死
If you make a major mistake, you're probably going to die on a higher difficulty,
继续玩也不值得
so it's not worth continuing.
玩家通常会选择读取存档重新战斗
You're usually just going to reload and save and continue on
这样在失误之前的所有弹药补给都还在
with all the ammo you had before you made that big mistake.
这意味着在我二周目的生还者难度游戏中
This means that in my new game plus run on Survivor,
我几乎从来没造过医疗包 因为燃烧瓶太有用了
I almost never crafted any healing kits at all because Molotovs were far more useful.
而如果我真到了生命值非常非常低的地步
And if I ever got to the point where my health was really, really low,
那我就干脆读取最近的存档
I would have just restarted from the previous save
尽量不要犯之前的、让我血量如此之低的错误
and not made that same mistake that landed me in that tough spot.
关于搜刮制作机制我想讲的另一点是
The other piece to all of this looting and crafting crap is that
搜刮材料的过程的确会让你感觉在探索整个关卡
looting materials does make it feel as though you are exploring the levels.
在大多数情况下它可以鼓励玩家探索关卡各处
And it motivates the player to explore the levels in most instances.
但开发者使用了一个动态平衡生成的系统来实现这个内容
But the developers used a balanced, dynamic generation system that makes it.
比如如果你在为某个Boss战做准备
So if you were preparing to go up against a boss fight, for instance,
那你就会发现大战之前必有补给
more ammo will generate as you get closer to that boss
游戏会让你的装备达到Boss战所需的推荐水平
to bring you up to the recommended level that they set for that boss fighting counter.
当然 没人逼着你捡这些东西
Now of course, nothing is forcing you to pick up these items,
但如果你真的需要这些补给 那游戏就会越来越频繁地给你生成这些东西
but the game will generate them more frequently and present them to you more obviously
if it calculates that you are in need of them.
如果是高难度 就会生成少一点
On higher difficulties, it calculates you as needing less of them.
总之 游戏会计算出你需要这些东西
But nonetheless, it calculates you as needing these items,
而这意味着其实你不用非得到处探索来搜刮材料
which means that you don't actually have to explore the levels to find the items
你直奔目的地都可以
you just have to get to the end of the level,
此时在你前往下一个区域之前游戏会有一个软件上的判定
at which point there's a software gate before you move on to the next section.
在这样的区域里游戏会给你自动生成某些补给品
And before that software gate is going to be a generation of items in certain stashes
以供你继续前行使用
that are going to refill your supplies before you move on.
说实话 我觉得这不是什么大问题
But to be honest, I don't think that this is a major issue.
真要说的话 其实这就是给速通玩家留的后门
If anything, it's just a perk for speed runners.
而且我认为这种机制是利大于弊的
And to be honest, it probably does more good than it does harm,
因为如果有玩家错过了某个有大量补给的区域
because it makes it so if players overlooked a certain area that had a lot of gear in it,
这个机制也不会让他们在之后的关卡中束手无策
they're not going to be totally screwed over in the next level.
而游戏在这段突发惊吓后继续进行
突发惊吓，即"Jump scare"
翻译来自维基百科
But after this little jump scare, we keep pushing through.
艾莉干掉了几个赛拉菲特帮 或者叫疤脸帮的人
Ellie fights some Seraphites, or Scars,
解决了几个谜题 干掉了几个感染者
solve some more puzzles, fight some more zombies,
包括一些以潜行为主的感染者
including some stealth focused zombies
如果不是它们太他妈蠢了游戏应该能更有意思一点
that could have been an interesting if they weren't so damn stupid.
但这一章节的高潮点在于我们第一次直面赛拉菲特帮
But the peak of this chapter is when we get our first extensive exposure to the Seraphites.
他们的战斗模式完全不同 他们更懂得潜行 战斗更加谨慎
You see, they fight differently. They're much more stealthy and careful.
战斗的时候还会用口哨交流
They communicate also through whistling.
基于玩家的音响系统适当调节一下音频设置的话 真的会有奇效
Now depending on your sound system, tweaking the audio settings could really work wonders.
说真的 你完全不需要使用聆听模式就能知道敌人在哪里
Seriously, you can figure out where enemies are without needing to use the listen mode at all.
所以如果你有一副不错的耳机 或者家庭影院音响 玩着就非常爽了
If you have a good pair of headphones or a surround sound theater, it's pretty damn cool.
而据我所知 在下一代主机上这类技术会更多
And from what I can tell there's going to be even more of this type of thing on next gen consoles
比如他们在搞的PS5上的3D音频之类的
with all of the PlayStation 5 3D audio stuff they're doing.
真的老牛逼了 我好期待
It's really awesome, I can't wait.
接下来是证明顽皮狗注重细节的一个有趣的地方
Now a fun little detail just to prove the point of Naughty Dogs attention to detail
我们来到有一群赛拉菲特帮的地方
here as we push up on a bunch of Seraphites.
如果我们一开始在邪教成员把那个人开膛破肚之前炸死他们
If we blow up all of the cult members before they're able to disembowel this man,
就会出现备用动画
they actually have a backup.
当然 这只能发生在你玩到这里时解锁了爆炸箭
Bear in mind, this is only possible if you happen to have explosive arrows unlocked
而且刚好手里有一发的时候
and crafted at this point in the game,
如果是一周目游戏 那这个过程还是挺漫长的
which is a long stretch, if you're playing through on the first run,
所以这更像是二周目游戏才能发现的事情
so it's more of a new game plus problem.
如果你解锁了爆炸箭然后炸死了所有的
If you do have it unlocked and you blow up all of the cult members
围在这个被吊起来的人周围想要给他开膛破肚的邪教成员
surrounding this man that's being hung and about to be disemboweled and killed,
那他会被一直吊在那 慢慢痛苦地死去
he'll actually just hang and it's a much slower and more aggravated death,
除非你去帮忙送他一程
unless you put him out of his misery.
我还真试过这个
I actually tested this,
看能不能射绳子 把他放走
where I tried to shoot the rope and cut him down to allow him to escape,
结果发现做不到
but I wasn't able to get it to work.
可能能做到但我瞄准太烂了打不到绳子
Maybe there is a way to do it, and I just have bad aim on the shore.
总之 游戏设计了两种情况的确很酷
But nonetheless, it's still pretty cool that they have two states available.
一种是邪教组织完成他们的小仪式
For one, if they are able to finish their little ceremony,
一边吊死他一边给他开膛破肚
kill him by hanging and disemboweling at the same time;
另一种是你在邪教成员给他开膛破肚之前就杀死了邪教成员
and then the other case being that you kill them before they are able to disembowel him,
那他们就会把桶踢到一边 让那个人被活活吊死
at which point they just kick the bucket out and he hangs slowly.
接着玩家或杀穿或潜行过多个赛拉菲特的地盘 最后遇到一个小型boss
Now you fight and sneak through multiple levels of these guys finishing on a mini boss fight
名叫赛拉菲特野蛮人 和艾莉蒂娜接吻预告片里看到的那个一样
with a big Seraphite Brute, the same one that was seen in the Dina Ellie kiss trailer.
我个人认为在这个最终版本里游戏打磨的不是那么完美
Now it's a little less polished in this final version, at least in my opinion,
少了些许流畅 但仍然很棒
it's less fluid, but it's still awesome.
我这样说是因为这里脚本化的内容与动画看起来太少了
What I mean by that is that there seems to be a lot less scripted elements and animations.
但说实话 毕竟都看过预告 也无所谓了
But to be honest, you'd probably expect that from a trailer.
这场战斗在里屋还会出来几个杂兵
Now there are grunts in the back room during this fight,
让战斗在二周目下变得很难
which actually makes this a really difficult to encounter a new game plus
因为等我来到这里的时候 基本已经把弹药用光了
considering that I had used all of my ammo by the time that I got here,
让我只能几乎全程近战和他硬刚
meaning that I had to take him on pretty much entirely with melee.
这也是TLOU令人诟病的一点 游戏需要大量的试错
Now one of the frustrations with TLOU is that it requires a lot of trial and error.
很多时候打通某个场景的唯一办法
A lot of the time the only way to figure out exactly how to get through a particular encounter
就是不停地死 不停地重试
is by dying repeatedly and trying again.
最惨的例子就是现在这个场景
The worst examples would be, for instance, this scene
我得想办法绕到里屋
where I had to run around into the back room,
先杀里面的人 然后出来和之前里屋出来的野蛮人近战肉搏
try killing those guys first and then moving outside melee, trying to fight the big brute in the back room,
打死外屋的野蛮人后再回到里屋去
trying to fight the big brute in the front room, and then moving to the back room.
需要非常多的试错才能找到最合适的方法
It required a lot of trial and error to figure out the best way to do it.
另一个例子就是稍后艾莉在洪水泛滥的购物中心中找船的那段
Another example would be when Ellie was trying to get the boat
in this flooded mall sequence a little bit later.
视觉上那段场景真的非常棒
It's visually fascinating as a scene,
但在生还者难度下我大概花了30分钟才找到一条刚好能避开所有人视线的路径
but on Survivor it took around thirty minutes of experimenting to find the path
that just narrowly dodged everybody's perception.
而且即使爬到船上我也无法相信自己能逃掉
And even then I'm not convinced that I should have escaped
因为我一上船 启动发动机 所有敌人就发现了我 开始向我射击
because I got in the boat, started it and was spotted and then shot started coming in,
刹那间无数子弹向艾莉袭来
at which point a lot of bullets definitely hit Ellie,
本来死定了 但游戏还是让她把船开走了
and she probably should have died, but I was still allowed to escape.
我能看出顽皮狗在你上船后削弱了敌人的瞄准
From what I can tell Naughty Dog tweaked their aim while you're inside this boat
给你营造一种在枪林弹雨中七进七出的感觉
to make it feel as though you are whizzing past incoming fire.
而且我最开始玩的时候还竟然忘记了游戏开船的设定
But here I actually forgot that the boat controls in this game
默认竟然是最最最蠢的布局
are defaulted to the stupidest lay out possible.
我坐船上像傻子一样按着R2键
So I sat there for a second holding down R2 like a chump
结果发现船的移动竟然要完全使用左摇杆
before I realized that it was all steered using the left stick,
等我反应过来的时候
and by the time I figured it out,
我可能早就凉透了 但我还是活下来了
I definitely should have died, but nonetheless I was allowed to live.
在那场小Boss战后 艾莉推进到了医院内
So the player and Ellie pushed to the hospital after the fight with the mini boss.
我们一路潜行进入医院
We stealth our way into the hospital.
我们杀死了这个拿着PSV摸鱼的女孩 稍后在埃比的章节里还会见到她
We kill this check that is holding the Vita who we will also see again later in Abby's sections.
但也不用怕 她反正只出现了几秒
But don't worry, she's only in there for a couple of seconds.
然后我们发现WLF正在清理整座医院 这也很合理
And then we find out that WLF are clearing the hospital, which makes sense,
他们要确保医院里没有感染者
they want to make sure that there's no infected here,
但他们还在把所有的补给品送往总部
but they're also taking all of their supplies back to their headquarters
个中缘由并没有解释
for some reason that isn't explained.
稍后到了埃比篇就知道了
Though we will figure it out later on when we play as Abby.
就目前来说 我们知道WLF的头目 伊萨克
But as for right now, all we know is that Isaac, the leader,
下令把所有的物资运回总部所在地
ordered that all of the supplies be returned to the centralized location.
我们又打过几段场景
Now we go through a bunch of sequences
你还是可以选择杀穿 也可以选择潜行通过这帮WLF士兵
where we can either stealth or fight our way through a bunch of WLF.
没什么重要内容 和之前一样
It's not particularly important, it's just more of the same.
而最终我们来到顶层 发现了诺拉
But eventually we push up to the top floor and find Nora.
她正在和其它WLF士兵谈论埃比的事
She's talking with some other WLF about Abby.
显然埃比不见了 这些WLF士兵认为
Apparently she's missing and these WLF think
诺拉知道埃比的去处 也知道她是怎么跑掉的
that Nora knows something about where she is headed and how she escaped.
这令艾莉有些疑惑 因为据艾莉所知
It's a little confusing for Ellie because as far as Ellie knew,
埃比是WLF的负责人之一
Abby was one of the head honchos with the WLF.
为什么她会被一些同伴追捕呢？
Why is she being sought out by some of the members?
她为什么会被关起来？
Why was she imprisoned?
为什么如果事实证明她知道埃比的下落就会有麻烦？
Why is Nora going to be in trouble if it turns out she knows where Abby is?
这很令人困惑 但稍后会解释清
It's very confusing, but it will make sense later.
现在对于玩家来说
As for the player right now,
看起来应该是埃比与WLF组织起了某种冲突
it just seems as though Abby is in some sort of direct conflict with the group.
有那么一瞬间
Now, for a brief moment,
我曾想或许我们之后会和WLF联手去追捕埃比
I thought that perhaps we were going to pair up with WLF members to hunt Abby down.
毕竟 敌人的敌人就是朋友
After all, an enemy of our enemy is our friend.
可拉倒吧 别做梦了
But don't worry, they're not going to do this.
你在医院里一路追着诺拉
You chase Nora through the hospital
在那之前两人有过简短的互动 其中诺拉这样问了艾莉：
after a brief interaction where she pushes back at Ellie asking:
诺拉：你现在还会听到他惨叫吗？
艾莉：什么？
诺拉：我每天晚上都能听到……
是啊。
那个混蛋死得一点都不冤。
艾莉：你这个贱货——
诺拉：救命！有入侵者！
诺拉：不、不、等等。
你把她追到了一个死胡同 走廊上有一个断口 下面是充满孢子的地下室
You chase her to a dead end with a break in the hallway that leads to the spore filled basement
不要、不要，求求你——
艾莉：后退！
WLF士兵：把枪放下！
全副武装的警卫也在追你
as armed guards chase you.
诺拉：你可以离开这里，好吗，我可以——
艾莉：你他妈闭嘴！
艾莉挟持诺拉为人质 拿她当肉盾
Ellie takes Nora hostage and holds her as a body shield,
WLF士兵：把枪放下，举起双手！
艾莉：往后退！
发现自己无路可逃
realizing that there's no way out,
WLF士兵：你无处可逃。
而且诺拉知不知道自己的免疫能力已经不重要了
and that Nora's knowledge of her immunity is of no importance
毕竟她马上就要因为吸入孢子而死了
since she's going to die from the spores in just a few moments,
诺拉：不！
WLF士兵：等等！
所以艾莉就带着诺拉跳进了地下室
Ellie takes Nora into the basement,
干掉几个感染者后 在走廊一个死胡同处发现了蜷缩着的诺拉
kills some zombies and finds Nora cowering in a dead end hallway.
然后便是接下来 我们看到艾莉黑化的一幕
And then this sequence plays out wherein we see Ellie get her hands dirty.
艾莉：埃比人在哪里？
诺拉：你把孢子吸进去了。
你就是那个女孩。
艾莉：你是火萤的人？
诺拉：已经没有火萤了。
艾莉：埃比人在哪里？
诺拉：我他妈的都要死了，为什么要告诉你？
艾莉：因为我可以让你死的快点。
或是慢慢折磨你。
诺拉：想想他的所作所为。
有多少人因他而死？
艾莉：给你最后一次机会。
诺拉：我不会出卖朋友。
艾莉全身沾着诺拉的血 回到了剧院
Ellie returns to the theater covered in Nora's blood.
她显然因自己刚刚为了获取埃比位置信息而做的一切感到痛苦
She's clearly distressed at what she's just done to figure out where Abby is.
但她还是做到了
But she did it.
她知道埃比因为某种原因在水族馆
And she knows that she's at the aquarium, for some reason.
蒂娜帮艾莉清理干净
Dina helps Ellie Clean up,
正是在这里 我们第一次看到了这场复仇对艾莉造成的肉体上的影响
and it's here that we see the first visual example of
what this revenge pursuit is doing to Ellie, physically.
从对话和行为中我们能看出艾莉精神上的痛苦
We can infer Ellie's mental distress through the dialog and behavior,
但这在很大程度上仍有待解释
but it's still largely up to interpretation.
而肉体上的伤害是大家有目共睹的
But these physical injuries are visual and apparent.
这段场景简短而安静
It's a brief and quiet scene.
在感人的片段过后 艾莉和蒂娜睡觉了
And after this touching moment, Ellie and Dina fall asleep,
故事进入「西雅图 第3天」
which takes us to Seattle Day 3.
两年前
首先是一段两年前的回忆
We begin with a flashback to two years earlier
艾莉回到了一代作品中结尾部分的医院
when Ellie returned to the hospital from the end of the first game.
在探索了医院 发现了一些文书和最关键的录音记录后
After exploring the hospital, discovering some paper work and eventually recording,
她发现了曾经这里的真相
she finds out what truly happened here.
火萤：大多数人早就离开了。
乔尔害怕永远失去艾莉 也终于不得不告诉她真相
And Joel is forced to tell the truth finally, so as to not lose her forever.
我不知道应该加入哪个组织……
他们说……
就算我们找到她，或是奇迹般出现其他免疫者，
也于事无补。
因为唯一能制造疫苗的人已经死了。
……或是奇迹般出现其他免疫者，也于事无补。
……奇迹般出现其他免疫者，也于事无补。因为唯一能——
乔尔：艾莉！
过来。
你到底在想什么？
大半夜的一走了之。
你可以跟我谈谈。
不能留下一张该死的留言就——
艾莉：告诉我……
在这里发生的事。
如果你再对我撒谎，
我会离开。
你永远也别想再见到我。
但是如果你告诉我真相，
我会回去杰克逊。
既往不咎。
告诉我吧。
乔尔。
乔尔：制造疫苗……
会让你丧命。
所以我阻止了他们。
艾莉：天哪。
你他妈别碰我！
我会回去的。
但我们就此互不相干吧。
这标志着乔尔和艾莉关系的一个重要转折点
This marks a significant pivot in Joel and Ellie's relationship.
艾莉很早就知道乔尔并没有那样诚实
Ellie is known for a long time that Joel was being less than truthful.
她心里有数
She had her suspicions.
然而即使她对乔尔有所怀疑
However, even with those suspicions,
也仍然是往的好方面去想的 以免破坏两人的关系
she still gave Joel the benefit of the doubt so as to not wreck their relationship.
但现在 真相大白于天下 艾莉感受到了背叛
However, now, with the truth fully released out into the open air, Ellie feels betrayed.
她所担忧的一切都是真的
Everything she feared is true.
也许成功制作疫苗的几率并不高
Perhaps the odds of successfully making a vaccine were not particularly high,
特别是考虑到火萤组织在整个第一部作品中是多么的废物
especially considering how incompetent the Fireflies were throughout the entire first game.
但重要的是艾莉得知真相后
However, it's important to note that with this revelation,
她便明白这个概率并不完全是零
it's made clear to Ellie that the odds were not zero.
没错 概率不高 但不是完全没有
Sure, they might not have been great, but they weren't zero.
这给艾莉带来了巨大的负担 她觉得自己对人类有责任
That places a huge burden on Ellie shoulders, where she feels a duty to humanity,
要献出自己的生命来挽救其他人 这样就有可能重建人类文明
to give her life so that others can live and so that humanity could potentially build itself back up.
这是一个有趣的问题 特别是当你把自己放在她的位置上时
It's an interesting question, especially when you put yourself into her shoes.
如果你是艾莉你会怎样做？
What if you were in Ellie's position in this world?
如果你的性命关系到这一切的解药？
What if your life held the answer to the cure for all of this?
如果你能牺牲你自己 那这一切的苦难就有可能得到化解
All of the misery could be fixed if you were to sacrifice your life.
我用的是“可能”因为没人保证这真的会成功
Now there is an emphasis on COULD because there's no guarantee that it would actually work.
就算疫苗真的被研发出来了
And even if a vaccine were successfully developed,
谁又能在整个地球上分发这种疫苗？
who's to say that anyone would be able to distribute that vaccine throughout the planet?
毕竟TLOU2的背景是全世界的秩序已经彻底崩塌了
After all, one of the big focuses in TLOU2 is the fact that the world has gone to absolute hell.
人们会毫无理由地互相背叛
People betray each other left and right for seemingly no reason at all.
信任在这个世界里早已不复存在
Trust is something that basically doesn't exist in this world any more.
而且毫无疑问 如果有人屁颠屁颠跑到你的据点前
And without a doubt, if somebody were to waltz up to the front of your complex,
说自己有疫苗 有治愈虫草菌的办法
claiming that they had the vaccine, the cure to the Cordyceps fungus,
那你首先会持高度怀疑的态度 根本不会让他进入你的据点
chances are you would be highly skeptical and wouldn't allow them into the base at all.
关键是 我理解艾莉对乔尔擅自为她做决定而伤感
The point is, I understand that Ellie is frustrated that choice was removed from her,
而这个决定也是为了她好
and that decision was made for her.
然而即使是这样也不能改变这样一个现实：
However, even with that being the case, it doesn't change the reality
这个决定不是治愈与不治愈那么简单
that this decision is not as simple as cure versus no cure,
也不是艾莉能不能拯救人类那么简单
or Ellie saving humanity versus not saving humanity.
事情没那么简单 这个世界也不是非黑即白的
Nothing is that simple. Nothing is black and white in this world.
也许总体分析TLOU2故事情节的时候
Perhaps for purposes of general analysis within the story of TLOU2
你可以指着乔尔的行为说他为了拯救一个他非常关心的人而毁了全人类
you could point at Joel's actions and say that he damned humanity
for the sake of saving one individual that he cared greatly about.
然而我认为凡事都有两面性 因为你完全可以说
However, I think there's two sides to the coin and you could say that
即使疫苗研发出来了 也不太可能分发出去
even if they were able to develop some sort of vaccine, it wouldn't have actually gone anywhere,
或者只能用在一个很小的社区环境内
or at the very least it would have been contained within a very small community.
但同时你还可以说如果确实如此的话
But at the same time you could also say that if that were the case
如果疫苗只在火萤组织或者WLF内部使用
and if the vaccine were only used within the Fireflies or the WLF
因为这些组织最后都分散到全国各地
as they eventually became after being splintered across the country,
那你的确可以说艾莉的牺牲是值得的
then you could say that Ellie sacrifice would have been worth it
因为她能拯救几十条 甚至成百上千条生命
because she could have saved dozens or perhaps hundreds or even thousands of lives.
当然不如几万几亿数量级那么多 但也是个很伟大的数字了
Sure, it's less than millions or billions, but none the less that's a significant number.
更广泛的观点是 艾莉觉得这个决定是乔尔帮他做出的
The broader point is that Ellie feels as though this choice was made for her,
因为的确如此
because it was,
而且艾莉因为乔尔欺骗了她多年而感受到了来自乔尔的背叛
and she feels as though Joel betrayed her,
especially considering that he's been lying to her about it for years.
这段闪回过后 镜头回到在剧院里醒来的艾莉
But after this flashback, we cut back to Ellie waking up in the theater,
她去看杰西和蒂娜
and she goes looking for Jesse and Dina.
简单谈论了蒂娜的身孕后
After a brief conversation about Dina's pregnancy,
艾莉和杰西决定一起去水族馆
Ellie and Jesse decided to push out towards the aquarium together.
他们认为艾莉很可能藏在那
They think that Abby is likely hiding out there.
他们不知道她为什么会在那
They don't know why she would be there,
他们不知道为什么她会躲着、会害怕WLF
and they don't know why she would be running from or have reason to be afraid of the WLF.
毕竟她看上去应该是属于WLF组织的
After all, they seemed to be the group that she originated from.
所以至少玩家会奇怪这里面到底发生了什么
So at the very least it should get the player intrigued as to what actually happened.
在我的一周目游戏过程中
When I first played the game,
我以为是其他人因她擅离职守追杀乔尔这件事而想整她
I thought, perhaps it was that they were acting out against her
after she took this group AWOL to go and find Joel.
但这又不太合理
However, that doesn't actually make much sense,
因为和她一起去的其他人
considering that all of the other people that went with her on that trip
都还好好在做自己的日常工作
seemed to be operating in their regular profession just fine.
所以在这最后一天
So at the end of the day,
我们所有的疑惑只剩下埃比逃离WLF的原因
all we're left with is a suspicious absence on Abby's part from the group
以及其他角色间听到的小传言
and lots of gossip that's overheard between the characters.
总之 艾莉和杰西一起向水族馆推进
But regardless Ellie and Jesse push up towards the aquarium.
而这段游戏内容我感觉做得相当一般
And the section in my opinion, is actually pretty unremarkable.
这里的战斗没那么有趣
There's not a lot of interesting fight sequences here,
宏观上讲 这段只是为了让艾莉和杰西能够直面蒂娜怀孕的问题
and more broadly, it's just served as a chance for Ellie and Jesse
to get all of the drama about Dina's pregnancy out on the table.
整段流程下来 他们认为必须让蒂娜回杰克逊小镇
Over the course of the sequence, they determined that she has to return to Jackson.
没有其他办法
There's no other way.
如果她想安全把宝宝生下来
If she is to receive any semblance of healthcare in the lead up to the delivery of the child,
她就必须从哪来回哪去
she's going to need to return to where they came from.
这也意味着这很可能是他们最后一次寻找埃比的机会了
This, in turn means that this is likely their last chance to find Abby,
因为他们一旦找到汤米
because once they find Tommy,
他们就要收拾东西回杰克逊了
they're all going to pack up and head back to Jackson together.
杰西、蒂娜、尤其是汤米 很可能不会让艾莉留下来
Chances are Jesse and Dina, and especially Tommy, are not going to allow Ellie to remain.
杰西知道孩子是自己的
Now Jesse knows that it's his baby.
没错 蒂娜自己还没告诉杰西自己怀孕的事情
Yeah, he's heard that Dina hasn't told him that she's pregnant yet.
她一直想保守这个秘密 看着挺蠢的 也可能只有我这么觉得
She's keeping it a secret, which seems kind of stupid, but I guess that's just me.
总之 大家的动机全都变了
Regardless, the motivations have shifted.
杰西的重心不再是寻找埃比复仇了
Jesse is not as concerned about finding Abby and getting revenge.
他现在更想赶紧找到汤米 然后大家一起回杰克逊小镇
Rather, he's looking for Tommy so that they can all return to Jackson together
艾莉嘴上也是这样说
whereas Ellie claims the same.
然而 她还是更想去找埃比 我们稍后就能看到她的具体表现
However, she is much more concerned with finding Abby as we'll see in just a moment.
当杰西和艾莉通过无线电得知码头上有一名狙击手时 整个事件达到了高潮
This whole climaxes when Jesse and Ellie here over a radio that there's a sniper on the pier,
这名狙击手干掉了一群WLF成员 带来了不少麻烦
that's taking out a bunch of WLF members in causing trouble more generally.
杰西和艾莉推断这人肯定是汤米
Jesse and Ellie determined that this has to be Tommy.
这倒很合理 毕竟WLF不可能自己中门对狙玩
And it's actually a fair point because the WLF wouldn't be sniping themselves.
而疤脸帮也不太会这样用狙击枪 所以不太可能是那边的人
And the Scars don't actually use sniper rifles in this way, so it's likely not them.
所以这人要么是汤米 要么是碰巧为了好玩想和WLF对狙的个人势
So it's either Tommy or another rogue individual
who happens to just be sniping WLF members for fun.
当然了 大家在这天结束发现他的确就是汤米
And of course it ends up being Tommy at the end of the day,
但在这里我们看到艾莉做了一个很难解释的决定
but it's here that we see Ellie make a decision that's much harder to justify.
艾莉坚持说汤米自己不会有事的 不需要她帮忙
She insists that Tommy is going to be OK by himself and that he doesn't need her help.
话是这样说没错 但问题在于艾莉的想法
While this is perhaps true, it's more the thought that counts.
诚然 汤米能一路杀到这里
Of course, Tommy has made it this long.
而他单人和WLF的人对狙这件事
And the fact that he sniping WLF members
也能看出他对他自己应付这么多人的能力还是有信心的
shows that he's at least somewhat confident in his abilities to deal with them.
但艾莉这样说不是因为她顾及杰西、蒂娜或者她自己的安危
However, Ellie isn't saying this because she wants to protect Jesse or herself, or Dina's well being.
而是明显想要自己赶快找到埃比 杀掉她复仇
Rather, she's seeing it purely because she wants to get to Abby quickly, kill her,
完成她自己想做的一切后 才能和汤米、杰西与蒂娜一起回杰克逊小镇
and then be able to leave with Tommy, Jesse and Dina back to Jackson,
having accomplished everything she set out to do.
我不知道你们怎样想
I don't know about you guys,
我第一次玩到这里时
but when I first played the game,
我立刻失去了对艾莉所有的同情心
this was the moment that I immediately lost all sympathy for Ellie.
在此时 她做出了一个在我看来错误的决定
At this point, she's making, what seems to me, the wrong decision.
她有可能为了一己私欲而伤害到所有她爱着的人
She's potentially damning all of those that she seems to love, for her own selfish pursuit,
这点在主题上类似于乔尔在第一部作品中的行为
which is thematically related to what Joel did in the first game,
他为了自己不失去艾莉而放弃了全人类的命运
where he seemingly screwed over humanity to serve his own private interests.
这也是整个游戏中制作者做了好多次的事情
And once again, this is something that they do time and time again
throughout the course of the game.
游戏流程中有很多平行的场景 旨在呼应之前发生的事情
There's parallels all over the course mirror sequences that are meant to echo what happened previously.
例子不胜枚举
It's all over the place.
不用说也知道杰西对艾莉的决定很不满
Needless to say, Jesse is just as disappointed in Ellie for this decision
玩家也很可能对她不满
as the player is likely disappointed in her.
所以他决定自己去找汤米
So he breaks off and goes to find Tommy
带汤米回剧院 这样大家之后就能一起离开西雅图
and help him get back to the theater so that they can all leave together.
艾莉独自行动
However, Ellie splits off alone.
她为一艘她看到的驶过运河的船而进行了一番战斗
And she fights for a boat that she saw driving through a canal
希望能开船到港口对面的水族馆
that she hopes to take to the aquarium that's across the harbour.
这段战斗真的非常有难度 尤其在高难度下
Now this sequence is super tough and especially in higher difficulties.
几乎需要非常完美的潜入技巧
It requires an almost exclusively stealth approach.
不过幸运的是游戏设计者也知悉这点
Now, thankfully, the designers seem to have anticipated this fact,
所以很多关卡都有一些秘密通道
which is why most of the levels have secret passageways
可以让你绕过很多敌人
that you can find to get around most of the enemies
这样你完全可以一人不杀来到下一个检查点
so that you either don't have to kill any of them to get through to the next checkpoint,
或者只杀特定的几个
or you only have to kill a select few.
在我看来 这是整个游戏中关卡设计的典范
In my opinion, these are the best designed levels in the entirety of the game.
让潜行机制充分发光发热 这点TLOU2做的非常棒
It's where the stealth mechanics really shine, and TLOU2 is at its best.
玩家继续向水族馆推进
So you continue pushing to the aquarium
干掉了几波赛拉菲特帮的敌人
and you fight your way through several waves of Seraphites,
解决了一个还是两个巨无霸 还解开了几个场景中的谜题
take on a Bloater or two, and you solve some environmental puzzles.
不太难 但绕不开
Nothing too difficult, but none the less they're there.
最后你终于来到港口这里
You eventually get your boat to the mouth of the harbour
向着水族馆旁边的海岸前进
and you start heading towards the shore over by the aquarium.
这时艾莉的船被一个巨浪拍碎 差点被淹死
It's at this point that Ellie's overtaken with a rogue wave and almost drowned,
但最后还是勉强游到了水族馆外的岸边
but ends up just barely escaping to the shore of the aquarium outcrop.
我想说这段游玩内容简直行云流水 做的太漂亮了
And I will just say this whole sequence is done so smoothly and beautifully well.
我吹爆
I can't complemented enough.
我自己并不是个游戏开发者
I'm not a game developer myself,
但我深入研究过很多关卡设计和内存系统管理的复杂问题
but I have delved into a lot of the intricacies involved with designing levels and managing memory systems
看看它们在整个游戏过程中扮演怎样的角色
to see what they're able to do throughout the course of this game,
而这一关绝对是榨干了每一滴的性能
and especially this sequence is absolutely ridiculous,
我必须为顽皮狗所有开发人员的努力工作献上掌声
and I have to applaud all of the developers over a Naughty Dog for their hard work.
回到正题上来 艾莉终于进入了水族馆 却发现了一些奇怪的事情
But with that out of the way,
Ellie pushes into the aquarium and finds a few strange things.
有几个门是锁着的
There are several doors locked,
有一个房间的灯光亮着 手术台上散乱着血淋淋的器械
there's lights on and there's bloody instruments strewn across an operation table.
以目前我们在游戏中掌握的情况来看
With the context we have in the game so far,
我们认为这里一定是在进行一些奇怪的拷问 仅此而已
we assume that there must have been some strange torture session going on here and nothing more.
然而 正如我们稍后看到的 这其实没有想的那么吓人
However, as we'll see later, this wasn't as terrible as it seems.
艾莉爬进了一段通风管 然后发生了这样的事情——
Ellie climbs into an air duct, and then the following sequence plays out.
艾莉：哦，不！
Ellie: Oh no!
啊！
Ahh!
天呐。
Jesus.
妈的！
Fuck!
可恶。
Shit.
蠢狗。
Stupid dog.
这条狗好像就是随便跑进来的一只
This dog may seem like it's just another dog.
就像预告片里你杀过的随便一只一样
After all, it was shown off in the trailers, as just some mud that you put down.
但别急 我们之后就会知道它的更多信息
But don't worry, we're going to see a lot more of her later.
艾莉调整状态继续推进 却发现一扇大门后有人说话的声音
Ellie recovers, but here's some muffled voices through a double door,
她打开门 然后发生了这样的一幕
She pushes through, and the following happens.
欧文：那个发动机速度够快，我们可以截住她。
梅尔：没人从那座岛上活着回来过！
欧文：埃比为了你冒了多少次生命危险？
梅尔：这一次可是她自愿的，我可不去。
欧文：那就算了！
你回去吧。
梅尔：去你妈的，欧文……
艾莉：举起手来。
埃比人在哪里？
欧文：你是杰克逊的那个妹子。
艾莉：她去哪里了。
梅尔：我们怎么知道你不会杀了我们？
欧文：告诉她的话，我们就死定了。
艾莉：你们不用死。我只想找到她。
欧文：扯淡。
艾莉：你。
过来。
他妈的快过来！
在地图上指出她的位置。
然后你来。
最后他妈的是同一个位置。
梅尔：好吧——
欧文：你干嘛呢？
梅尔：反正她很可能已经死了！
欧文：这样做不值得。
艾莉：别过来！
欧文：我们可以谈谈——
艾莉：你他妈的后退！
指出她的位置。
他妈的指出——！
梅尔：欧文！
艾莉：告诉我埃比在哪里？
欧文：她……
艾莉：她到底在哪里？
欧文：（虚弱）……怀孕……
艾莉：不、不、不……
妈的…
艾莉。
艾莉！
汤米：哦、哦、哦！
听我说……
艾莉：对不起。
汤米：没关系。
来，我们走吧。
走吧。
没关系。
无需多言 这是一个极其压抑的场景
Needless to say, this is a deeply upsetting sequence.
这件事我老早就预料到了
It's one that I personally saw coming a mile away.
顽皮狗的编剧们有一点我非常了解
You see one thing I do know about the writer's over a Naughty Dog,
尤其是尼尔·德鲁克曼和哈雷·格罗斯
especially Neil Druckmann and Halley Gross,
他们很喜欢运用类比
is that they love their similes.
他们喜欢人物之间的映射
They loved the reflections between characters.
这让玩家有机会观察到两个不同的人在类似情况下的反应
It gives you a chance to see how these two different people respond to similar situations.
因此每当你开始看到相似的东西或角色有共同点的东西时
And so whenever you start to see things that are similar or things that characters have in common,
你就可以假设开发者和编剧
you have to assume that the developers and writers
将迫使这两个角色进入某种可以明显看出来的类似状况
are going to force those two characters into a similar situation where those similarities can come out.
在这个例子里 艾莉的女友蒂娜怀孕了
In this case, Ellie's girlfriend, Dina, is pregnant.
而我们第一次见到欧文和埃比的时候
And one of the first things that we hear about Owen and Abby's group in general
梅尔也怀孕了
is that Mel is pregnant.
在当时 站在雪天悬崖边鸟瞰杰克逊小镇的我们还不知道梅尔是谁
At this point in the game we don't know who Mel is
when we're standing on this snowy hillside overlooking Jackson.
但我当时个人就猜想 艾利最后很有可能杀死了怀孕的梅尔
But I personally knew that there was a very good chance
that Ellie would end up killing her pregnant friend Mel
单纯因为蒂娜很有可能最后也会怀孕
simply because Dina was likely going to end a pregnant as well.
事实也的确如此 当蒂娜说自己怀孕了以后
And sure enough, when Dina is revealed to be pregnant,
我基本就确信我的猜想了
this point was solidified for me.
现在除了这个情节的可预测性外 我还要问另一个问题
Now besides the predictability of this plot point, I have to ask one other question,
那就是如果欧文和梅尔出卖了埃比 艾莉是否真的会杀死他们
which is whether or not Ellie would have actually killed Owen and Mel if they had tattled on Abby.
考虑到我们在这个游戏中对艾莉的了解
And given what we know about Ellie in this game,
我认为她很有可能会这样做
I think the odds are pretty good that she probably would have.
听起来很可怕 但艾莉就是为了复仇而来的
It's horrible to say, but Ellie was here for revenge.
这些仇人就站在面前 尽管某种角度上讲她其实欠欧文一条命
She knows that these people were there, even though technically she owes her life to Owen.
当艾莉趴在地上盯着乔尔的尸体 其他人都想杀了她以绝后患的时候
Owen is the one that stepped in when Ellie was on the floor, staring at Joel's corpse.
欧文就是那个插手的人
While everyone else wanted to kill her to clean up after themselves,
而且客观地讲 当时杀了艾莉才是更理智的做法
which objectively probably would have been the smarter thing to do,
特别是考虑到TLOU2的世界观
especially considering how TLOU2 plays out.
但总之 她的确欠欧文一条命
But nonetheless, she technically owes her life to Owen.
可即便如此 我还是觉得她会杀了欧文
Even so, I think she would have killed him.
另一个问题是 埃比在哪里 她怎么了
The other question that you have to ask is where is Abby and what happened.
她去哪了？
Where did she go?
还要多久她才会发现艾莉的所作所为呢？
How long is it going to be before she finds out what Ellie is done?
她当初为什么要离开？
Why did she leave in the first place?
看上去她像是在躲着艾莉
Now it's implied that she's fleeing from Ellie.
但这真说不太通
However, this doesn't really make a lot of sense,
毕竟她好像从一开始就在躲着什么
especially when you consider that she's already fleeing something else.
看起来她因为某事情而不得不暂时离开自己在WLF的职位
It seems as though she's involved in something that's taking her away from her duties within the WLF,
而这让伊萨克对她很不满
which is why Isaac seems to be upset with her.
但总之 我觉得顽皮狗在让故事顺其自然地发展
But nonetheless, I think Naughty Dog is trying to keep the story moving along
玩家不用想太多 坐着看之后更多的剧情内容就好
so that you don't think about it long enough to realize that there's got to be more to it.
而实际上我觉得这样是OK的
And honestly, I'm okay with that.
特别是因为艾莉无论是对埃比为何去别的地方的原因
Especially because Ellie herself isn't particularly interested
in the reasons why Abby is going to the places she's going
还是对埃比和其它成员不和的原因都不是特别感兴趣
or why Abby seems to be at odds with the rest of her group.
她现在只对复仇感兴趣
All she's interested in is revenge.
关于这段情节的最后一部分 让我不禁觉得
And the last thing about this sequence is that I can't help but feel as though
汤米、杰西和艾莉就这样一走了之好像有点奇怪
it's a little strange that Tommy, Jesse and Ellie just leave after this.
他们看见了地上的尸体 却选择了转身离去
They see the dead bodies on the floor, and don't do anything more.
竟然还押韵了 我不是故意的
That rhymed, I didn't mean it to rhyme.
抱歉……呃……我们继续说
I'm sorry, but I'm… you know what we're leaving it in.
我倒不是要求他们精心处理好水族馆的现场 清理所有的尸体
No, I'm not demanding an elaborate sequence
where we clear the entire aquarium of any sort of bogey
保证埃比没藏在水族馆的什么地方
to make sure that Abby is not some were hiding within the aquarium.
但至少
But at the very least,
他们没有对整个建筑的其他部分进行更细致的检查 这好像有点奇怪
it seems odd that they wouldn't have done a more elaborate check throughout the rest of the building.
他们只是找到了艾莉 显然她对自己刚刚做的事情感到非常震惊
They just find Ellie, and clearly she's pretty shaken up about what she has just done.
但他们直接就走了
But they just leave.
也许在这时 他们已经接受了他们不可能找到埃比的事实
Perhaps at this point, they have just accepted that they're not going to find Abby.
命运就这样了
That's not destined to be.
而且他们已经造成了足够的伤害 已经表明了自己的观点
And that they've done enough damage that they've made their point.
不管怎么说 这之后的场面其实很平静 相当令人清爽
Regardless, the scenes after this are actually quite calm and it's fairly refreshing.
我们看到艾莉和蒂娜在床上 只是在休息
We see Ellie in bed with Dina, and they're just resting.
过了一会儿 艾莉去和杰西和汤米谈话
After a while Ellie goes, and talks with Jesse and Tommy,
试图确定返回杰克逊小镇的最佳路线
trying to determine the best route back to Jackson.
他们已经正式决定不再继续找埃比了
They've officially determined that they can't stay and find Abby,
而是要为了蒂娜未出生的孩子 把她送到安全的地方
but rather need to get Dina somewhere safe for the sake of her unborn child.
一切都很正常 直到……
All is normal, until this…
艾莉：糟了！
杰西？
埃比：站起来！
举起手来，不然我开枪把他也打死！
汤米：别听她的，艾莉！快离开这里！
埃比：站起来！
汤米：你他妈敢试试——
埃比：你他妈闭嘴！
艾莉：妈的。
埃比：好吧——
艾莉：快停下！
埃比：扔掉你的武器。
扔掉你的武器！
艾莉：妈的！
汤米：不……不……
艾莉：我知道你为什么要杀了乔尔。
他那样做是为了救我。
因为我才没有疫苗。我就是你要找的人。
放他走。
埃比：你杀死了我的朋友……
我们放了你们一条生路……但你们浪费了机会！
这是一个极其突然且尖锐的叙事转折
This is a stunningly sudden and sharp narrative beat.
我知道要发生一些事情了 但我没想到会如此突然
I knew something was coming, but I didn't know that it would happen this suddenly.
杰西的死几乎是这段剪辑一开始就发生的
Jesse's death happens almost instantaneously as the cut scene begins,
没有任何警示 没有任何预想 就这样发生了 杰西死了
there's no warning, there was no forethought, it simply happens and Jesse's dead.
这里还有个问题是这他妈……这……这什么玩意？
There's also a problem with what the fuc… what it…  What is that?
这……也太辣眼睛了 好好 跑题了跑题了
What it… That's gross. Stop it, OK, OK, a slight detour.
我知道这段场景很严肃很悲伤
I know this is a serious scene and it's sad and everything.
但这画面几乎彻底把气氛毁没了 因为我第一次玩到这里的时候
But it was almost completely ruined because the first time that I play through the game,
艾莉的胳膊上缠着绷带
Ellie has a bandage on her arm.
但这里其实不应该有的
It's not actually supposed to be there.
这是来自之前的场景里用的医疗包
It's from the previous sequence when she patched herself up.
但不知道怎么回事 她胳膊的模型网格出问题了
However, it did something strange where it's warped the actual mesh of her arm.
看起来像得了软骨病一样
So it looks that she has some sort of weird noodle bone disease.
看着很奇怪 但我本来不想抱怨这事的
It… it's bizarre and I wouldn't complain about it,
可之后我玩二周目游戏的时候
except that when I went back through the game on new game plus
却没发生这样的事情 她的胳膊又正常了
it didn't happen and her arm looked normal.
所以我感觉这应该是游戏bug
So I can tell that this was a glitch.
这只是一个非常奇怪的问题 我真的不知道该怎么解释
It's just a really, really weird one that I don't really know what to make of.
总之它还是发生了
But nonetheless it… it happened,
我以后做噩梦都会看见艾莉长了个霸王龙一样的小手
and I am going to have nightmares about this weird T-Rex arm that she has.
唉 没救了 希望你们没遇到过这样的bug
But nonetheless it happened, hopefully this didn't happen to you,
但对我个人来说 整段剧情基本都因为我一直对着那条细胳膊傻笑而毁没了
but for me it almost spoiled the entire scene because I found myself giggling at her messed up arm.
你们懂的……就这样吧
But… you know, I'll leave it there.
到了这里 游戏的前半部分就算结束了
Now this marks the end of the first half of the game.
别急 我之后会讨论玩到游戏中期的想法
And don't worry, we're going to discuss midpoint thoughts
以及我游玩过程中的心路历程 情绪等各种内容
and where I was at in my play through, what my emotions were, what I thought of everything.
但首先我想先过一遍接下来的场景
But first, I want to go through the next scene.
在埃比枪杀杰西 貌似杀死了汤米 同时拿枪指着艾莉的镜头之后
You see right after Abby kills Jesse, seemingly kills Tommy, and is holding Ellie at gunpoint,
我们直接跳转到了一个年轻 还没有那么多肌肉的埃比
we jump to a clip of a young, non-yoked Abby.
她在找她爸爸 而她爸爸在找某只动物
She's looking for her dad, who is in turn looking for some animal,
后来发现是一只产仔过后的斑马
that turns out to be a zebra that's just given birth.
这段很温暖 给我们过去十小时游戏经历的悲痛带来了些许慰藉
It's cute, and it's a nice break from the dread that the last ten hours have brought.
说真的 我之前都没意识到TLOU2的前半部分玩着有多么艰难
Seriously I didn't realize how much of a trudge the first half of TLOU2 felt like
直到我玩到这个场景 感觉就像是从第一代结尾直接跳到这里一样
until we got to the sequence and it felt like something straight out of the first game.
至少对我而言 我感觉艾莉在这作是一个非常难相处的人
Ellie, God bless her, is a really difficult person to relate to in this sequel, at least for me.
在第一部作品中 她身上有一些能引起所有人共鸣的人性特点
In the first game, there was something really human about her,
something that was reflective of all of us.
玩家能与乔尔和艾莉以某种难以名状而遥不可及的方式产生情感共鸣
We can all connect with her and we can all connect with Joel in some weird, distant way.
然而这在第二部作品中表现却寥寥无几
However, in the second game, there's not much of that to be seen or had.
这让我实在喜欢不起来续作中的艾莉
But nonetheless I can't help but feel as though Ellie is painfully unlikable in the sequel,
所以游戏前半部分操控艾莉的时候总有种奇怪的感觉
which is why it's all the more bizarre to go through the first half of the game with Ellie,
你不会太喜欢她 也无法饶恕她做出的事情
where you don't particularly like her, or condone any thing that she's doing.
然后剧情到了你操控的埃比杀死了你开始尊敬 喜爱甚至爱上了的角色
And then you reach this point after this character you're playing as Abby
has killed characters that you really began to respect and enjoy and even love.
但你发现自己开始慢慢了解埃比 对她性格的喜欢甚至超过了艾莉
But now you find yourself relating to her and liking her personality way more than Ellie's.
这种体验很非同寻常 我认为其中有一半是制作者刻意为之的
It's really bizarre and I think it was half intentional and half not.
也就是说我认为这段埃比好相处与惹人喜欢的品质是刻意安排的
What I mean is that I think Abby's relatability and likability, was completely intentional,
而前半部分艾莉让人喜欢不起来的感受则不完全是刻意安排的
that I don't think that Ellie's lack of likability was completely intended.
当然 在这个时间点我觉得绝大多数玩家是非常憎恨埃比的
Now of course, at this point in the game, players for the most part are going to hate Abby.
我不怪大家
I wouldn't blame them.
毕竟她杀死了游戏史上最让玩家喜爱的角色乔尔
She killed Joel, one of the most beloved characters in gaming history.
我也理解游戏强迫你操控埃比所带来的厌恶感
And I understand that frustration that now we are forced to play as her.
然而 游戏制作者希望你能给埃比一个机会
However, they want you to give Abby a chance,
也正因如此 他们把时间调回了四年前
which is why they rewind the clock to four years before the events of this game.
我之前提到过
Now, as I mentioned earlier,
我曾做过一次调查 统计大家对这个游戏的看法
I conducted a massive poll of all of you guys to see what you thought of the game,
无论这个游戏是否达到了你的期待 都可以畅所欲言
and whether or not you felt as though it lived up to your expectations.
如果没有达到 那怎样改会更好
And if it didn't, what it could have done better.
调查中有几十个问题
There were several dozens of questions involved in the survey,
我不会在这一一列举这些问题 不过我已经整理好了一个Excel表格
so I'm not going to go through all of them, but I will include a Excel spreadsheet
大家可以随意筛选各种问题的答案
that you can actually use to sift through all of the answers yourself if you would like to.
这当中其实有很多有趣的信息
There's actually a lot of really interesting information in here,
我花了大约一周筛选了大量的回复
and I've spent the better part of a week sifting through a lot of the responses,
因为其中有很多宝贵的留言
because there's a lot of really good stuff here.
但其中令我震惊的一点是
But one of the things that I was stunned to realize
很多人在游戏玩到这就弃坑了
is that a lot of people actually gave up on the game at this point.
他们完成了游戏前半部分 大部分时间都很享受艾莉的章节
They got through the first half of the game enjoyed Ellie's sections for the most part,
但当他们看到自己要被迫操控埃比的时候
but once they saw that they are going to be forced to play as Abby,
他们就觉得受到了背叛 放弃游戏了
they felt betrayed and stopped playing completely.
我本来想直接放一些玩家们表达的这种挫折感的评论
Now I was going to show some direct quotations from some of the gamers that expressed this frustration.
但奈何其中一些人的言语实在难登大雅之堂
However, many of them had too much profanity for me to comfortably include in this video
要是放出来的话我这频道收益化就拜拜了
with any hopes of getting monetized at the end of the day.
所以我打算简单转述一下他们的意思
So I am simply going to paraphrase.
如果你想看实际评论内容的话
But if you want to read the actual word for word responses again,
视频下方会有整个调查结果的链接
I'll have the entire survey and all of the responses linked below.
总的来说 在这个时间点放弃游戏的玩家认为
In general, the people that quit the game at this point felt as though
他们被迫要与一个毫无兴趣的人产生情感上的交集
they were being forced to relate to somebody that had no interest in relating to.
但仔细想想这又有点奇怪
It's kind of a bizarre idea when you think about it,
会有人因为不得不去控制某些角色体会她的心路历程而感到不安
that somebody would be so upset that they would have to relate to somebody
以至于会直接关掉游戏彻底弃坑
that they would turn off the game entirely and walk away.
但还真就有
But here we are.
真要说的话 我觉得这反而是对顽皮狗角色塑造能力的一种赞美
If anything, it could be construed as a compliment to the character building
正因为之前乔尔这个角色太有亲和力了
and the relatability and care that people felt towards Joel initially,
导致玩家对他和以他为代表的这个想象中的角色会表现得非常忠诚
that they are so loyal to him and this imaginary character that he represents
使得玩家不愿意给杀死他的角色一丁点时间
that they won't even give the time of day effectively to the character that brought on his demise.
我也能完全想到顽皮狗内部做这个决定时会多么两极分化
And I completely understand how polarizing this decision was on Naughty Dog's part.
决定让埃比和艾莉都成为主角
It would have been a very early decision
并让她们各自占一半的流程本应是开发流程中一个非常早的决定
in the development process to have Abby and Ellie costars of this game,
to the point where they're both playable for roughly half of the game each.
值得庆幸的是至少在我看来 在大多数情况下 游戏做的还相当不错
And thankfully it seems to have for the most part, been done fairly well, at least in my opinion.
我理解有些人一开始就不同意这样的安排
I understand that some people who disagree with the thematic decision at the outset.
但这不是问题所在 问题在于当前的安排是否执行顺利
But that's not really the question. the question is whether or not it was well executed.
现在等我们看完了埃比的部分
Now, once we've gotten through Abby sections,
我就能跟大家多聊聊我认为的
I'll be able to talk a lot more about whether or not I feel as though
他们在呈现这两个角色方面是否取得了良好的平衡这件事了
they struck a good balance in trying to present both characters equally.
我认为TLOU2的最大问题是它的节奏
I think the biggest problem with TLOU2 has to do was its pace.
它真的很容易让人打瞌睡 失去注意力 特别是在游戏最后三分之一部分
It gets really easy to doze off and lose focus, especially in the last third of the game.
毕竟 TLOU2对玩家的要求很高
After all, TLOU2 asks a lot of the player.
实际上要保持对正在发生的一切的兴趣并参与其中并不容易
It's not that easy actually to stay intrigued and involved in everything that's going on,
特别是因为它在情感上如此令人心力交瘁
especially because it's so emotionally taxing.
但别担心 我们稍后会讨论这些问题
But don't worry, we're going to get into all of that a little bit later.
你继续游玩这个关卡
As you go through this sequence,
最终找到了被困于一些铁丝网中的斑马
you eventually find the zebra that's been trapped in some barbed wire,
埃比在欧文的协助下帮助她的父亲解救了它
and Abby helps her father with Owen's assistance cut her loose.
之后斑马和它刚出生的幼崽
She runs off in cuddles with her newborn in a field
一起跑向了一代游戏结束时看到的圣玛莉医院对面的田野上
directly across from the hospital that we saw at the end of the first game, St. Mary's.
一伙人刚刚得知马琳的女孩刚刚到了
Their group is informed that Marlin's girl just arrived
而且她好像真的像之前听说的那样具有免疫力
and that it seems as though she actually is immune as they were initially told.
说的当然就是艾莉了
This is, of course, Ellie.
就像一代结尾一群人发现乔尔和艾莉之后一样
Just as she was found at the end of the first game,
镜头切到一代里的马琳和埃比的爸爸争吵
we then cut to Marlin from the first game, arguing with Abby's dad
否是要实施这场可能研发出疫苗的手术
about whether or not to perform the operation that could lead to a vaccine.
这其实是我们一直想看到的对话内容
It's actually the conversation that we always wanted to hear.
埃比的父亲想做这台手术
You see Abby's dad wants to do it.
他觉得艾莉的牺牲将是值得的
He feels as though the sacrifice of Ellie is going to be worth it
因为这有可能会拯救成千上万条生命
because it could potentially save thousands or even millions of lives.
但问题在于他们不敢去征得艾莉或者乔尔的同意
The problem is that they can't afford to ask Ellie or Joel.
他们只能先斩后奏 事后请求原谅
They have to do it and ask for forgiveness.
如果他们去找艾莉 那艾莉很可能会同意
If they were to ask Ellie, she would likely say yes.
但如果他们去找乔尔 那乔尔很可能会不同意
But if they were to ask Joel, he would likely say no.
最后我们发现 何止是不同意 他能把你们杀穿了
And as we found out, he would also likely go berserk.
在这段对话的末尾 埃比进来了 她给她父亲送一些晚餐
It's at the end of this discussion that Abby comes in the room, bringing her father some dinner.
而她之后说的话很有意思
And she offers a fairly interesting anecdote.
埃比：你做得对。
杰瑞：嗯。
埃比：如果是我的话……
我会希望你进行手术。
随后很快画面一黑 镜头来到了埃比跑进手术室的画面
Immediately after this, we cut to black and we transitioned the Abby running into the operating room.
她发现她父亲已经死了
Finding her dad, dead.
欧文：他还在该死的楼里吗？
埃比：这是——
欧文：埃比。
埃比，别看——
埃比：爸爸！
爸爸！不！
不行！天呐……
这就是埃比要杀乔尔的原因
This is why Abby wanted to kill Joel.
全都明白了 为了强调这一点 画面马上切到乔尔死的时候
This made all the clear by the immediate cut to Joel's death to reaffirm the point.
看起来好像有点仓促 但我真的很喜欢这部分
It may seem a little ham fisted, but I actually really like this,
因为现在我们终于能听到之前在这里听不清的对话了
because now we can hear this sequence without the murmur and drowning out
that we had the first time that we saw it.
我们可以听到整段对话与人们的争论
Now we can hear the entire conversation, the debate that goes back and forth.
男子：在地狱中烧成灰烬吧，pendejo。
艾莉：我他妈要杀了你们……
欧文：喂，喂，你要干嘛？
曼尼。
曼尼：把他们收拾了。
欧文：别这样。我们是冲他来的。到此为止。
曼尼：留他们活口太危险了。
欧文：太他妈坏了。
梅尔：他说的对。
我们不能留下活口。
欧文：如果我们杀了他们，就和他没区别。
他们又没做错什么！
乔丹：是吗？看看我的脸——
欧文：去你妈的脸。
你应该听我的在楼上守着。
乔丹：闪开。
欧文：往后退。
梅尔：冷静点。
乔丹：你想怎么样？
欧文：你他妈的后退！
梅尔：冷静点！
曼尼：乔丹！
欧文：你要打死我吗？
埃比：行了！
我们收手。
这里正式来到了游戏的中点
This is the midpoint of the game, really.
我们可以看出的是 艾莉的游玩部分已经结束了
As far as we can tell, we're done playing as Ellie.
西雅图
接下来画面出现了「西雅图 第1天」
The next sequence pops up with "Seattle Day 1",
第1天
说明我们即将重新完整过一遍之前操控艾莉的这三天
implying that we're going to be going back through the entirety of what we just did with Ellie,
而这次是埃比的视角
but from Abby's perspective.
这样的转换很有趣
It's an interesting flip,
而这种视角的转换就是整个游戏叙事元素的核心
and the change of perspective is, after all, the operative narrative element of this entire game's design.
但我不禁感觉很多玩家玩到这里 经历了刚刚那样的旅程 已经身心疲惫了
But I can't help but feel as though many players are going to already be exhausted
from the journey that they just endeavored on.
也因此游戏到了这里 节奏的掌握就变得尤为重要
This is why at this point in the game, pace is more important than ever.
你必须得让玩家兴奋起来
You have to keep the player engaged,
特别是考虑到很多玩家会感觉自己明明刚刚玩过这三天的内容了
especially because many of us probably felt as though
we had just played through an entire game by itself.
现在游戏却让我再操控另一个角色再玩一遍
And now you're asking us to play through another game with another character,
而且还是大家眼中的反派角色
but in this case, the villain, as far as we're concerned,
游戏还想让我们陪她度过和艾莉一样的三天时间
and you want us to give her the same time of day and attention that we give Ellie,
可我们早在2013年的一代游戏中就已经和艾莉建立深厚感情了
a character that we have a deep relationship built up with
after having played a game with her back in 2013.
这里真的有很多问题要问
It really is a lot to ask,
而我也真不会怨很多玩到这里决定弃坑的玩家
and I don't really blame a lot of players that decided to walk away at this point.
诚然他们可能永远也看不到埃比在剧院拿枪指着艾莉之后的故事了
Sure, they may never get the actual story resolved with what happened
when that Abby pulled the gun on Ellie in the theater,
或者可能是快进 可能是之后就改看别人的视频流程云了
or perhaps they simply fast forwarded and watched a run through of the game after that point.
导致最后 不少玩家会对游戏后半部分自带一个怀疑态度
And lastly, most players are going to have a very skeptical outlook at this second half.
一进来都在拿放大镜找埃比可恨的原因
We're all looking for reasons to dislike Abby.
毕竟 她做了一些我们很可能会认为是不可饶恕的事情
After all, she's done something that we would deem most likely unforgivable.
然而 我想我们中的大多数人还是会有足够开放的心态来玩这个游戏
However, I would like to think that most of us would have an open enough mind to play through this
看看游戏是否能说服他们埃比行为的合理性
and see whether or not they could be convinced of whether or not she was justified.
在我进行的那份调查当中
In that survey I conducted,
绝大多数玩了这个游戏结果中途放弃的玩家
it seemed as though the overwhelming majority of people that decided to walk away from the game
几乎都是在这一时刻弃坑的
didn't play it after this particular point,
而这些玩家更倾向于给游戏打低分 平均分在4~5左右
and those people tended to rate the game very negatively, averaging around a 4 to 5.
而打通了整个游戏的玩家
However, of the people that played the game all the way through,
给游戏的打分多数在8~9分
the majority of them rated the game in the range of an 8 to 9.
结论看起来还是很明显的
Seems to be the conclusion is fairly clear.
那些给这个游戏证明自己的机会的玩家
Those that gave the game the chance to prove itself to them
通关后还是很享受这款游戏的
ended up enjoying it once they experienced the whole thing.
而那些决定中途放弃这款游戏的玩家
Whereas those that decided to cut and run
游戏体验就和正常做事半途而废的体验一样
had the experience that you would expect from somebody who cuts and runs.
就这么简单
It really is that simple.
玩家需要给游戏一个证明自己的机会
You have to give a game like this the chance to do its job.
游戏正在做的是说服你 你所恨的这个角色
What they're trying to do is convince you that a character you hate
是一个有血有肉、有真情实感的活生生的人
is actually a human being that has feelings and emotions
和你会觉得有亲和力的角色一样
that are perhaps just as justified as the character you'd find relatable.
这个论点并不是在短短一两个小时的游戏过程中提出的
That argument isn't made over the course of an hour gameplay sequence.
这需要时间 需要很多努力
It takes time and it takes a lot of effort.
更重要的是 还需要玩家开放的心态
And more than anything, it takes the open mind of the observer.
听起来有点像很多玩家都说的那样
It may seem like a cliche for many people to say
“你看你玩一半就弃坑了 就说你不喜欢这游戏
"Well, if you didn't like TLOU2 when you quit halfway through,
那说明你没玩到点上 你就永远不会喜欢这个游戏”
you just didn't get it, and you were never going to like it".
然而 我认为这里面有相当多的道理
However, I think there is a fair amount of truth in that.
但我也说不好 欢迎大家讨论
But I don't know, let me know what you think.
但我能说的是 当我一周目玩到这里的时候 我真的感觉身心俱疲
What I do know is that at this point, in my first run of the game, I was highly exhausted.
游玩埃比的部分需要相当大的精力 无论是心理上还是肉体上
Abby Sequences required a lot of effort, both emotionally and physically, to get through.
伴随着精神的高度紧张 和各种血腥厮杀
With the emotional tension and all of the gore,
这段10-15小时的游玩内容真的很令人疲惫
it's an exhausting 10 to 15 hours of game play to get through.
而且说实话 我玩到埃比章节的时候甚至也考虑过要不要休息一下
And I will be honest, even I considered taking a break before continuing on with Abby sequences.
但我还是决定埋头继续玩 给游戏一个它想要证明自己的机会
But I decided to put my head down and give the game the chance that it was asking for.
总之 我们开始操控埃比了
But regardless, this is the time when we begin playing as Abby.
节奏变了 态度变了 语气也变了
The pace changes, the attitude changes, the tone changes.
更广泛地讲 角色的行为风格也完全变了
And more broadly, even the style of character work changes.
在许多方面 无论是好是坏 都会让玩家感觉这是一个完全不同的游戏
In many ways, it's going to feel like a different game entirely both for better and worse.
但不要担心 我们会深入了解这一切
But don't worry, we're going to get into all of it.
「西雅图 第1天」
Seattle Day 1,
埃比醒来 游戏下半场开始
Abby wakes up and we begin the second half of the game
玩家操控这位大多数人眼中的反面角色
playing as who most of us will consider to be the antagonist.
然而这样的评价可能会在游戏结束后有所改变
However, this might change by the time we get to the end.
当然整个游戏都需要从不同角度去讲的
This whole game is, of course, about perspective in relativism,
在这方面游戏做得相对简单
and to that extent it works fairly simply.
游戏强迫玩家操控埃比
We're going to be forced to play as Abby
至少到玩家开始喜欢这个角色 甚至爱上这个角色
at least until we either start to enjoy her as a character like her or even love her,
或者最少是让玩家忘记之前有多恨她
or at the very least, until we forget how much we hate her.
这样的转变不能一蹴而就
It's not going to happen instantly,
而是需要8-12小时的游戏内容去慢慢渗透
but over the course of the next 8 to 12 hours of game play,
你才能慢慢缓解你对她曾经的恨意
you're probably going to start to lose the hatred you felt for her at one point.
这里埃比和曼尼搭档 而他也在去杰克逊小镇的一行人中
Here Abby is paired with Manny, who was one of the assailants in Jackson.
你会在这种非常轻松的场合中遇见很多人 这种感觉有点魔幻
You'll see a lot of them in very casual settings here, it almost feels surreal.
你恨这些人 他们杀死了乔尔
You hate these people, these people killed Joel.
为什么他们跟没事人一样吃得下饭睡得着觉
Why are they so normal, and why do they seem so happy and relaxed.
玩家探索WLF的基地 这里其实是由一个体育场改造而来的
You explore the WLF base where their station, which is actually built out of a stadium.
你准备出去执行任务
You're preparing to go out on a mission,
所以自然要去拿枪 之前还吃了点卷饼 和狗狗玩了一会
and so naturally you grab guns, a burrito and play fetch with a dog.
埃比：好吧，既然你这么问了……
Yeah, okay, since you ask so nicely…
把球捡回来！
Get the ball!
对不起，伙计。是我的错。
Sorry buddy. My bad.
现在 梅尔要和埃比、曼尼一起出去巡逻
Now Mel is going with Abby and Manny on this patrol.
没错 这就是刚刚艾莉杀死的那个女的
Of course, this is the same girl that we just saw Ellie kill.
那种奇妙感觉又来了
Once again, it's a little surreal.
你刚刚还看到这个女的遇害 而艾莉也精神近乎崩溃
You just saw this woman get murdered, and Ellie freak out as a result,
而埃比也因艾莉对梅尔和欧文的残忍行为而近乎崩溃
and you also know that Abby freaked out as a result of Ellie's actions towards Mel and Owen,
所以在这里看到她活蹦乱跳的 感觉有点怪
so to see her seemingly fine in this particular instance, is a little startling.
埃比还和曼尼就梅尔应不应该一起和他们巡逻的事情争论了一会
Nonetheless, Abby and Manny debate for a brief moment
as to whether or not Mel should be allowed to go with them.
毕竟大家都看到她挺着大肚子
After all, she's pretty damn pregnant, as you can probably see.
但也没太在意 因为他们感觉不会出什么事
But they dismiss it because they don't expect to see any action.
毕竟他们只是出去快速巡逻一下
They're basically just going to go on a quick patrol,
保证外面没有什么让人担心的事情
make sure that there's nothing to concerning out there,
有的话呼叫增援就好了
and if there is, they're going to call in support,
到那时梅尔在不在也无妨
at which point it wouldn't actually matter that Mel is there.
但我个人认为 带着这样一个身怀六甲的孕妇
In my opinion, it's still a stupid decision to bring what is a very pregnant woman
参加一场外出巡逻的军事行动仍然是很蠢的行为
on what is effectively a military mission to scout out the surrounding area.
但可能只有我和埃比这样认为罢
But that's just me, and it's actually Abby too.
这段场景结束埃比还跟曼尼说不应该带梅尔来的
At the end of this sequence, Abby actually gives Manny crap for having brought Mel along
还说从最开始就不应该允许她参加这次巡逻
and says that she definitely should never have been allowed to come in the first place.
但总之还是允许她来了
But nonetheless, they allowed her to go, from the outset.
现在既然说到梅尔 我们也知道她怀孕了 我们刚刚也看到她被艾莉杀害了
Now, while speaking of Mel, the fact that she's pregnant and we just saw her get murdered by Ellie,
我觉得有必要聊聊一个大家早已知道的问题
I think it's also important that we addressed the elephant in the room
就是有人认为这样安排毁了这场游戏
that some have said actually ruins the game.
即玩家此时已经知道了结局 所以感觉剧情没味了
That is that knowing what's going to happen removes all of the stakes in the story.
在玩过艾莉线后 我们知道这里很多角色最后会死
After Ellie's whole half of the game, we know that most of these characters are going to die.
而且更重要的是 我们会知道这些角色是什么时候 怎么死的
And more importantly, we know how they're going to die and when they're going to die.
因此这些玩家试图保护他们或与他们一起经历的情节
And so going through these sequences where we're trying to protect them or do things with and for them,
会少了很多紧张感 因为我们都知道结局如何
it removes a lot of the tension, since we know how it's all going to end.
然而 我对这样的观点表示强烈不同意
However, I strongly disagree with this idea.
在已知结果的情况下 中间的故事会有无数种可能
There are countless stories where the conclusion is known before the story even really begins.
大家可以看看那些简单而刻奇的电影 比如《泰坦尼克号》
You could look at something as simple and kitschy as the movie Titanic,
这是一部很俗但又很迷人的爱情电影
a fascinating film about an albeit cheesy and captivating romance.
就其核心而言 我们都知道故事结局如何
But at its core, we all know how that story is going to end.
泰坦尼克不可能像变魔术一样回到纽约
The Titanic is not magically going to make it back to New York,
而是会和很多人的生命一同沉入大洋
but rather it's going down and many people are going to die.
但它仍然是一个有趣而吸引人的故事
But it's still an interesting and captivating story
因为重要的不是故事的结果如何
because it's not actually about the destination that the story reaches.
而是通往这个结果的过程
It's about the journey to that destination.
或者另一个游戏中的例子是2018年的《战神》
Or in a gaming example, we could look at God of War from 2018.
我们从游戏一开始就已经知道游戏结局是奎托斯和阿特柔斯
We know from the beginning of the game that the story is going to end with Kratos and Atreus
将菲的骨灰撒在九界最高峰
spreading Faye's ashes from the highest peak in the realms.
我们从一开始就知道结局如何
We know the ending from the start.
而故事仍然很吸引人 因为重要的不只是结局
and yet the story is still captivating because it's not just about reaching that destination.
所以我觉得这是明摆着的事情
Again, to me this seems fairly obvious,
但实际上对这种已知结局的故事的批判总是不少
but it is actually a pretty common accusation against stories that have presumed endings.
在我个人看来 如果你觉得一个故事被毁了
In my mind, if you're going to allow a story to be ruined,
仅仅是因为你知道了角色在故事最终会怎样
simply because you know how the characters are going to end up at the end of that story,
那我认为你实际上并没有以一种正确 或者至少是最有效的方式去和游戏互动
you're not actually engaging and absorbing the media in the correct,
or at the very least, most effective way.
回到游戏 埃比和曼尼、梅尔 当然还有那条叫爱丽丝的狗一起上了卡车后座
Regardless, Abby leaves on the back of a truck out on patrol with Manny, and Mel
and of course, the dog, Alice.
还记得我说艾莉在水族馆捅死的那条很快还会出现的狗吗
Remember, I said, that that dog that we found in the aquarium earlier that
Ellie actually stabs the crap out of would come back again
呃……没错 就是这条
well… yeah, this… this is actually the same dog.
它名叫爱丽丝 贼可爱 最后被艾莉捅死了
It's Alice, and she's cute and lovable, and Ellie kills the crap out of her.
埃比和梅尔聊了聊日常
Abby and Mel talk about how they're doing.
显然大家在杰克逊杀死乔尔之后都睡不好觉
Apparently everybody's been struggling with sleep ever since they killed Joel in Jackson.
埃比和欧文不停接外出巡逻的活 想让自己忙起来
Abby and Owen are also going out on countless open assignments trying to keep busy
忙到让自己没工夫去想自己做过的坏事
and exhaust themselves to the point where they don't have to think about what they've done.
这些可是受过军事训练的人
These are hardened militaristic people
但他们却为自己对乔尔的所作所为感到无法释怀
and the fact that they're so torn up over what they did to Joel.
这很有趣
It's interesting.
因为至少表明他们对自己所作所为有些苦恼
Because at the very least, it shows that they were somewhat distressed by what they did
甚至可能有点后悔
and perhaps even some of them regretted.
这是使这些你一开始认为是反派的人展现其人性一面的第一步
This is the first step towards humanizing these people that you wanted to villainize from the start.
很微妙 但很有用
It's subtle, but it works.
它还打破了人们对埃比及其成员只是冷血杀手的看法
It also breaks the perception that Abby and the crew are simply cold blooded killers.
他们是活生生的人 也会搞砸一些事情
They're humans, and yeah, they do so messed up stuff.
而他们会为一些不公平的事情感觉到后悔
But some of them can feel regret over something that they felt was unjust.
或者至少认为自己做了错误的选择
Or at the very least, a bad choice.
然而这段对话被一群骑马搞伏击的赛拉菲特帮打断了
However, this gets interrupted by a group of Seraphites, ambushing the group on horseback.
我个人挺讨厌这些战斗的
I personally hate these sequences.
瞄准很蹩脚 伤害也感觉不合理 简单来说就是不好对付
The aiming is awkward, the damage feels unfair, and often it's just generally awkward.
如果对比其他汽车战
If we compare it to other car sequences,
比如之前和杰西把车开河里那段
like the one earlier with Jesse traveling all the way down into the river.
会发现两者是不太一样的
It's not quite the same.
艾莉和杰西的那场从头到尾都有很多脚本参与
The one with Ellie and Jesse is very scripted from start to finish
因为脚本成分很重 让游戏感觉很公平
and feels fair because it's so heavily scripted.
玩家并不需要太多操作
The player doesn't actually have that much agency.
但如果在这场被赛拉菲特帮伏击的汽车战中你什么都不做的话
However, if you don't do anything in this car sequence when you're ambushed by the Seraphites
那你就会被打死 然后重新读档
you're going to be killed and have to reload.
所以你必须进行这种蹩脚的游戏操作
So you have to be actively engaging with the game in its most awkward state,
而对我来说 既然这种操作是被迫的 那我觉得就是一个值得批评的点
which to me means that it's subject and worthy of criticism since you're forced to engage with it.
现在 埃比一行人终于到达安全地带
Now, Abby and her group eventually get to safety.
你们穿过几座建筑
You push through several different buildings,
解决掉几波感染者和赛拉菲特帮
and after fighting through multiple waves of infected and more Seraphites,
来到了一座加油站 发现自己又被另一波赛拉菲特帮伏击了
you find yourself in a gas station being ambushed by yet another wave of Seraphites.
我现在就感觉这些东西很臃肿
Now a lot of this just feels like bloat.
而当我们谈论游戏节奏的时候
And when we're talking about pacing,
这样的臃肿是你在经历游戏这个阶段时最不想遇到的事情
that's the last thing that you want to be thinking when going through this stage of the game,
玩家此时需要比他们在整个游戏中到此为止还要更高的参与度
players need to be more engaged than they have been in the entire game to this point.
但我认为大多数人到这都会开始感到厌烦 因为它只是更多重复的东西
But I think most people are going to start to feel bored because it just feels like more of the same.
的确有一些轻佻有趣的时刻
There are some interesting moments of levity,
也有一些令角色展现人性一面的时刻
and there are moments where these characters are actually humanized a lot,
而这或许才是游戏这段内容中更有用的东西
which is perhaps more the point of this section of the game.
这并不是真的要让玩家超级投入
It's not really about keeping the player super engaged,
而是要确保玩家慢慢开始与这些他们之前讨厌的人产生情感上的联系
it's about making sure that the player starts to relate to these people that they previously hated.
我知道要求我们既要有有趣的游戏内容 让玩家参与其中
I know it's a lot to ask that we get both an interesting game play sequence that keeps the player engaged
又要让玩家感受到这些角色人性的一面是很难的
and humanizing sequences with these characters.
但尽管如此 我仍然希望能有一些更吸引人的东西
But nonetheless, I wish that there were something a little bit more engaging.
我最喜欢的部分可能是埃比与梅尔讨论她恐高症的时候
My favorite part is probably when Abby is discussing her fear of heights with Mel.
这是一个很短 很容易被忽略的时刻
It's a small moment, and it's something that could be easily missed,
但我觉得真的很有爱
but I actually find it really endearing.
梅尔：真难想象你也有怕的东西。
Mel: It's kind of hard to imagine you being afraid of anything.
埃比：我不是你以为的那么无所畏惧。
Abby: I'm not as fearless as you think.
梅尔：哦，最好是……
Mel: Oh please.
埃比：比如我永远无法像你一样做手术。
Abby: Like I could never do the surgery stuff you do.
如果搞砸了，我会很抓狂。
I'd be too freaked out about fucking it up.
梅尔：你以为我不是这样吗？
Mel: You think I don't feel the same way?
埃比：不管怎样，我爸总说你是他最好的学生。
Abby: Well, for what it's worth my dad always said you were his best student.
梅尔：真的？
Mel: He did?
你总是说他是个笨蛋。
Well… you always said he was an idiot.
得了。
C'mon.
在铁路线和加油站的一番混战过后
Once you at the gas station and after a shoot out in a rail yard,
一队WLF士兵
a crew of WLF members,
可能是被几分钟之前的伏击引起的警报吸引过来的一队
presumably alerted by the assault that happened just a few minutes before,
来到现场拯救了大家
come in and save the day,
解决了所有攻击你们小队的赛拉菲特帮
killing all of the Seraphites that we're about to get the jump on you.
你们都脱困了 并且一起去了所谓的前线基地
And so you're all rescued, and you brought to the forward base as it's called.
梅尔去处理伤口 埃比和曼尼去见伊萨克
Mel goes to get patched up while Abby and Manny go into see Isaac.
我们终于能见到这位老大了
Finally, we're going to get to meet the head honcho,
这位自从艾莉到西雅图以后在游戏中听了能有12小时的幕后大佬
the guy that we've been hearing all about
for the last 12 or so hours of gameplay since Ellie got to Seattle.
在去见伊萨克的路上 埃比和曼尼听说
On the way up to see Isaac Abby and Manny are told
欧文和另一个小队分开了
that Owen was actually off with another member of the squad,
而他开枪打死的人——丹尼说欧文是为了保护“某位疤脸帮”
and that he shot that guy, Danny in order to save quote unquote "some Scar".
不用说也知道 一旦此事被证实 那欧文无疑会被判死刑
Needless to say, this could lead to a death sentence for Owen if proven true.
我们不知道到底发生了什么
We don't really know what exactly happened.
但如果欧文真的只是为了他们眼中的野蛮人害虫就杀死了一名WLF士兵
But if Owen did actually kill a WLF member
simply to save what's considered a barbarian pest on their people,
那一定会对欧文很不利
It ain't good end a pretty bad for Owen.
所以埃比和曼尼想去见伊萨克
And so Abby and Manny head up to talk with Isaac
而伊萨克可能是整个游戏里登场方式看上去最邪恶的角色了
and Isaac probably has the most badass introduction of any character in this game.
WLF士兵：诶，埃比。
埃比：我们要上去。
WLF士兵：伊萨克在那里面。
埃比：哦。
你知道他还要多久吗？
WLF士兵：他说等你们到了就叫他。来吧。
长官。埃比和曼尼到了。
伊萨克：别让他睡着。
WLF士兵：遵命。
伊萨克：我们上楼。
现在伊萨克并不像让他们去救欧文
Now Isaac doesn't want them to go and save Owen
因为WLF正在组织一场对疤脸帮的进攻 他需要人手
because they are revving up for some big assault on the Scars, and he can't spare them.
埃比说了句“去他的吧” 然后就去找欧文了
Abby says "Screw it" and they go after him anyways,
要不然……没法演了啊
because why not?
我要说的有两点
Now there's two things about this.
一方面 埃比留下其他人 自己去找欧文
For one, Abby leaving the group to go and find Owen
解释了为什么之前很多地方里艾莉寻找埃比的时候
explains why she seems to have gone AWOL in all of those sequences,
埃比看起来总是擅离职守
when Ellie was trying to figure out what was going on;
也解释了为什么埃比没和团队其他人在一起
and why Abby was not with the rest of the group.
WLF方面对她很不满 想要追捕她
The WLF were upset with her and wanted to hunt her down
因为她擅离职守 违抗伊萨克的命令
because she went AWOL and disobeyed Isaac's orders.
这当然不代表她就不是艾莉的威胁了
This, of course, doesn't mean that she's not a threat to Ellie,
但却能说明她对单纯追求WLF的目标和愿望并不像艾莉最初想象的那样感兴趣
but it does mean that she's not as interested in simply pursuing the goals
and hopes and aspirations of the WLF as Ellie perhaps initially thought.
埃比更像是一个独立的个体
Abby is much more of an individual,
这甚至还是埃比和艾莉的共同点
and perhaps that's even something that Ellie and Abby have in common.
另一方面 埃比看起来好像很轻松就能擅离职守
The other thing about this is that it seems relatively easy for Abby to go AWOL
还能这样直接违抗命令
and disobey direct orders like this.
也许只是她特别能干
Maybe it's just that she's particularly capable,
所以她能够偷偷溜走而不会有大问题
and so she was able to sneak out with any major issue.
但她看起来好像还很怕伊萨克
But she also doesn't seem particularly threatened by Isaac,
特别是他一登场我们就看到他在拷问一个人
which is strange considering that our introduction to him is of him torturing a guy.
所以不管是她太傲慢了还是游戏在这方面设计欠考虑
So whether its hubris or simply a lack of consideration,
埃比还是想办法出去自己找欧文了
Abby breaks out and decides to go find Owen herself.
当然 她希望的是自己能够救出欧文
Her hope, of course, being that she's going to be able to save Owen
并且能在围攻赛拉菲特帮之前想出一些应对办法
and figure something out before the big raid on the Seraphites
让其他人不会察觉到她曾经失踪了一段时间
so that she's never realized to have gone missing.
然后画面很快切到埃比和欧文曾经一次短暂的约会
We then have a quick cutaway where we go to a short date between Abby and Owen.
他们在一座摩天轮上 这段场景也很有趣
They're on a Ferris wheel, and it's actually super cute.
我们再一次看到了埃比对高处的恐惧
Once again we see that Abby is terrified of heights,
再一次看到了她在欧文面前表现出害怕恐惧的人性一面
and it's again a humanizing moment to see her chilling with Owen and also freaked out.
然而这就又到了讨论叙事节奏问题的时候了
However, once again, this is a point when the pace really starts to come into question.
这里在讲什么？为何节奏如此缓慢？
What is the deal here? Why is it moving so slowly?
为什么我们要融入这段我们不太了解 甚至多数人完全不关心的角色的回忆？
Why are we going through all of these cutaways with characters we don't particularly know,
and most people probably don't care that much about yet?
我们什么时候能进入一段更有趣更快速的叙事片段？
When we need to be engaged and going through a much more interesting and fast base sequences?
也许可能只有我这样 喜欢节奏更快一点的叙事片段
Now perhaps I'm alone, and my tolerance for fast pace narrative sequences is much much higher.
所以我希望多来点
So I need a lot more.
可也许这部游戏就是这样 所以节奏上可能没我想的那么糟
Maybe that's what it is, and the pace isn't actually as bad as it seems to me.
但在即将到来的西雅图第2天和第3天的内容中
But in these sequences that are coming over the course of Seattle Day 2 and 3,
游戏中很多片段真的开始大大放慢节奏了
the games really going to slow to a crawl in multiple moments.
我也不是很懂……欢迎在评论区讨论
But I don't know, let me know what you think.
这场约会还是很暖的
The date is relatively cute
在水族馆的最后 埃比和欧文俩人在亲亲
and at ends within the aquarium with Abby and Owen talking about their feelings.
埃比突然打断 她自己有些心事
At one point, Abby breaks away, she's got something else on her mind,
结果发现是她还在想乔尔的事情
and it turns out that she's still thinking about Joel.
他们正想办法找他 从而实施某种报复
They're trying to find some way of finding him so that they can enact some sort of revenge.
欧文似乎对这种复仇并没有很深的执念
Owen doesn't seem particularly interested in that pursuit,
尽管从我们可以看出他确实和埃比的父亲很熟
even though he did know Abby's father fairly well from what we can tell.
但他也懂这对埃比意义重大
But he understands this means a lot to Abby,
所以他选择顺着埃比的意思 至少多数部分是这样
and so he goes along with it, at least for the most part.
我们明白的是 这点是埃比的诉求 是她想要的
What is clear is that this is Abby's pursuit, and this is what Abby wants.
而且在找到并杀死乔尔之前她是不会放弃的
And she's not going to quit until she finds Joel and kills him.
她多次提到他们要回去训练
She references multiple times that they need to get back to training,
也解释了为什么她当前不是那么壮
which explains why she is currently not particularly shredded,
至少和“现在”那个手撕感染者、大战艾莉帮时候的肌肉块相比
at least compared to what we see in the present day
quote unquote sequences of Abby going through and fighting infected, and of course Ellie and her gang.
这就是为什么我认为在很多时候她的身体状况和外表
That's why in many moments I think her physical buffness and appearance
是她精神状态的直接反映
is a direct reflection of her mental state,
这就是为什么在游戏的后期 当她被复仇的艾莉追击时
which is why later in the game, when she's led off of that revenge-base pursuit,
整个人瘦了很多 没那么大块头了
she actually thins out a lot and is no longer as much of a meat head.
但抛开节奏问题 其实游戏真的体现出它的作用了
But other than the pace, this is actually starting to work.
我发现自己真的开始关心埃比和欧文
I found myself actually caring about Abby and Owen,
开始感兴趣他们的人生道路上到底发生了什么
and being involved and interested in what was going on within their lives.
说起来有点离奇 但我真的开始为杀害乔尔的凶手而感到难过
It's kind of bizarre to say, but I was starting to feel bad for Joel's murderer.
然后镜头来到了在WLF领土边界的埃比和曼尼
We then cut to Abby and Manny at the outskirts of the WLF's territory.
她要去找欧文 而出于某种原因曼尼留她独自前往
She's going to find Owen, and for some reason Manny leaves her to go on by herself.
他说这样不会引起太多注意 也不至于让他们惹上伊萨克的麻烦
He claimed, so it's not to draw too much attention and to get them in trouble with Isaac.
说是这么说
Even with this excuse,
但感觉曼尼能让她一个人去还是有点牵强
it seems like a bit of a stretch that Manny would leave her to go on by herself.
但我觉得还能接受 又不是什么大事
But I'm willing to let it slide, it's not that big of a deal.
现在这里游戏的引导系统非常有趣
Now the navigation in this chapter is actually pretty interesting,
设计得非常精巧 非常美
and it's done in a subtle and beautiful way.
玩家要做的 就是跟着日落
All you have to do is follow the sunset.
非常简单 又非常优美
It's simple, it's elegant,
这样的指引在你探索一个关卡时简单易懂
and it's easy to understand and follow as you explore a given level.
因为TLOU2中的很多光照都是环境光
Because pretty much all of the lighting in TLOU2 is ambient.
玩家总会与外面照进来的光线方向一致
You're always in tune with the direction of light that's coming in from the outside.
而且我不得不说 当我在探索这些关卡的时候
And I have to say while exploring multiple of these levels,
我会让自己根据从窗户射进来的光源调整自己的方向
focusing on the sunlight coming in through the windows to reorient myself,
我发现这个过程非常自然 而这个设计的实现是如此流畅 感觉真的很酷
I found it remarkably natural and really cool at just how fluidly this worked.
我自己已经不记得上一个
I personally can't remember the last time
使用类似的光源引导玩家的游戏了
that a game used the sunlight to direct players in a particular way,
我觉得这真的很新鲜
but I find that kind of refreshing.
当然 很多游戏都使用地图坐标来为玩家指出正确的方向
Sure, a lot of games use cardinal directions to point players in the right direction.
他们会直接告诉你往北还是往西
They'll say, go north or go west,
或者是屏幕上有个罗盘 让你自己知道该去哪
or they have a compass on screen that allows you to figure out where you need to go.
但我觉得这是两码事
But I don't think that that's the same thing.
一方面 这会让你不停地去看游戏里的罗盘
For one, it forces you to look at the compass itself.
比如《上古卷轴V：天际》 如果你想知道自己的方向
Look at a game such as Skyrim, if you ever want to reorient yourself,
且你又碰巧不是那么了解地图的话
if you don't happen to know the map like the back of your hand,
你那就不得不抬眼看一下上面的罗盘 找到你要去的地方
you have to glance up at the compass and figure out where you need to go.
这个过程中你的眼睛从游戏画面中移开
This takes your eyes off of the map
从工作室的所有开发人员花费数年时间制作的所有惊人的艺术作品上移开
and in turn off of all of the amazing artwork
that all of the developers over at the studio spent years and years working on.
我一直认为这是开放世界游戏设计的一个真正的悲剧
I've always thought of this as a real tragedy when it comes to open world game design
开发者辛苦花费这么多时间创造的精美游戏内容
that a developer can spend all this time working on something,
但却让玩家因为简单的探索寻路过程而完全分心
only to have the player completely distracted from it by way of simple exploration,
而这两件事本应是共同推进的
something that should go hand in hand with it.
这也是为什么我非常喜欢把屏幕上UI界面完全打散的方式
This is why I'm often a fan of completely mixing UI on screen.
我只是感觉这样不太值
I just don't think that it's worth it.
特别是当还有其他选择的时候 比如游戏内UI
Especially when there's other alternatives such as having in game UI.
比如像《死亡搁浅》这样的游戏
Look at a game such as Death Stranding.
当你想导航去某处送货的时候
Whenever you want to navigate to a given destination to complete a delivery,
你会在地图上设定好路径点
you set the way point on your map.
然后 当你在游戏世界里向着目的地进发的时候
Then, as you head out into the game world to reach your destination,
你会发现你所有的目标点都点缀在了游戏的地形当中
you find that all of the direction that you're given is interspersed with the terrain.
这使得游戏指引你去目的地的导航过程
This means that the guidance you are given to get from one destination to another
并没有把你的思绪从游戏世界中拉出来
doesn't pull you out of the game world or distract you from it,
相反 它能让你更加融入其中
but rather it pulls you in even more.
这会让你注意到每一座山峰 每一条山脊
It makes you look at every hill crest, every ridge, every mountain top.
这才是这类开放世界游戏真正展现光芒的时刻
It's at that point that these open world games really shine.
而我真诚地相信 这就是为什么《死亡搁浅》即使其世界在主观上相当空洞
And I honestly believe that's why Death Stranding even though its world is subjectively quite empty,
但仍能以如此引人入胜 吸引玩家眼球
can still captivate players in such an intriguing way.
当然 如果你想听我关于这款游戏的全部想法
But if you want to hear all of my thoughts on that,
可以去看我完整的《死亡搁浅》评测
go check out my full length critique of Death Stranding.
两个多小时 有亿点点长
It's over two hours' long, it's… it's a monster.
但你既然这个视频都看了这么久 那你可能已经看过那个了
But if you're this far into this video, you're probably gained for it.
总之 我认为顽皮狗在埃比这部分关卡中引导玩家的设计
All of this to say, I think that the level design in the direction
that Naughty Dog gives the player in this particular sequence with Abby
是非常了不起的 我吹爆
is phenomenal and I can't applauded enough.
把让玩家跟随阳光这样简单的事情被实现得如此之好
Something as simple as having the player follow sunlight is implemented so well,
我认为这绝对是惊人的成就
that I think it's absolutely astonishing.
随便一个工作室都能做一个要求玩家跟随阳光的关卡场景
Any studio could set up a scene where they demand that the player follow the sunlight.
但要让阳光贯穿于玩家进入的每个场景、每个区域、每个房间
But it's much harder to have that sunlight carry through in every scene, every area, every room
让他们清楚地知道下一步要去哪里 这就非常有难度了
that the player enters, such that they know exactly where they need to go next.
因此 在这种引导下 埃比一路西行前往水族馆
And so it's with this guidance that Abby heads west to try to get to the aquarium,
她认为欧文就藏在那里
where she thinks Owen is hiding out.
她想和欧文谈谈 因为她需要弄清楚他到底为什么要枪杀丹尼
She wants to speak to Owen because she needs to figure out why exactly he shot Danny,
以及故事是否还有反转
and whether or not there's two sides to the story.
在这个相对平静的游戏内容中
Throughout this relatively calm sequence,
你主要是在收集弹药、探索建筑、找找收集品
you're mostly collecting ammo and exploring buildings, grabbing some collectibles.
这真的是暴风雨前的平静 因为在这之后
This really is the calm before the storm because after this
游戏就真的开始全程高能直到结尾
is when the game is really going to pick up and carry through to the final act.
而这个高能就是从埃比爬入墙缝里的时候开始的
And this descent into chaos begins when Abby's climbing through a crack in the wall.
呃……然后就……
And well, this happens.
埃比：该死！
我真的很喜欢这种“你安全了……吗？”的设计
I love these you-are-not-safe moments, I really do.
就像之前提到的 艾莉在工作台升级武器的时候被偷袭
As we mentioned earlier, Ellie actually gets jumped while she's adjusting weapons,
and you're upgrading abilities at a workbench.
而现在埃比在一个看上去很隐蔽的、让你以为游戏在读条的空间里
And now Abby while you're in what is presumed to be a covered, loading space,
也被突然吓了一跳
and Abby even gets jumped.
我……我真的感觉这太爽了 可能我算是这样想的少数人吧
I just, I think it's so cool, I… I know that maybe I'm in the minority with this,
但我真的感觉这样很有观感
but I really do think that it's cool to see.
这也让我回想起艾莉和乔尔之前的片段 两人在墙缝中缓缓前行时
This also reminded me of a flashback when Ellie and Joel were climbing through a crack in the wall,
巨无霸把墙里的艾莉一把拽出来
原文有口误 是巨无霸不是循声者（Clicker）
and the Clicker punched through the wall, pulling Ellie out,
引发接下来的Boss战
and it starts in many boss fight.
可能这也是一处类比让你感觉两人是相似的 有关联的吧
Maybe it's a similarly between Abby and Ellie to make you think of them as relatable and similar.
但也可能是我过度解读了
But perhaps I'm reading too much into it.
在关卡的最后 你会遇到当年隔离区的一个检查点
At the end of the level you come upon a checkpoint from the initial quarantine.
埃比：烈士之门……
停站期已经结束，但你们还是不停过来……
哇哦……
这里设置了一个神龛 专门用来供奉赛拉菲特教的先知大人
There's a shrine set up here dedicated to the Prophet of the Seraphites cult.
神龛周围还有各种纸条 都在向她索要各种东西
There's also all of these notes surrounding the shrine that are asking her for various things,
先知大人：
我请求您赐予我 请求您赐予我
也许我所求的是天方夜谭，但我必须请求您：用您的洞察力、
您的智慧和您的仁爱祝福狼，让他们放弃自私的行为，放下武
器。希望您给世界带来和平。
我想这让玩家意识到
and I think it makes the player realize
赛拉菲特帮与WLF有多大的不同 艾莉也同样意识到了这一点
just how different the Seraphites are from the WLF and in turn Ellie.
现在我们还未见到过这位女先知 实际上我喜欢这样的设定
Now we never get to see or meet the Prophetess, which I actually like,
就像我们最终也没有和伊萨克有过Boss战
similar to how we don't end up having a major boss fight or clash with Isaac,
放到一般游戏 介绍了这样的大人物却什么都不做简直是大罪过
something I think video games are definitely guilty of doing
whenever there's a notable character introduced.
如果玩家看到游戏中介绍了某个大坏蛋
If you see a bad guy introduced to the story at some point,
先知大人：
我想要的不多，我的请求很简单。但是我双手笨拙，无法为我
们村子做出贡献：修补、锻造和建造。我请求您赐予我这些能
力，让我更有效率，更受人尊重。
那你很可能会和ta打一场Boss战
chances are you're going to have some sort of boss fight with him or her.
否则最开始就不会介绍这个人
Otherwise they wouldn't have been introduced in the first place.
可能只有我这样想吧 但我真的很高兴顽皮狗能打破这个常规
And maybe I'm alone, but I really appreciate that Naughty Dog bucked this trend
这些角色还是他们自己
and made sure that these characters stood by themselves
只是偶尔会放进Playstation的奖杯列表里
and simply turn them into a trophy on your Playstation achievements list.
现在说到这个女先知
Now speaking of the Prophetess,
或者游戏中更多人只是叫她“先知”
or as she's more commonly referred to in the game, just "the Prophet",
我们实际上并没有发现很多关于她的事情
we don't actually get to find out a lot about her.
我做了很多调查 试图弄清楚这位女士曾经究竟是谁
I did a lot of digging to try to figure out who this lady actually was,
我说“曾经” 因为游戏暗示她实际上在二代游戏故事之前就已经遇害了
and I say WAS because it's implied that she actually was killed before the events of this second game.
似乎在疫情爆发 西雅图陷入一片混乱后不久
You see, it seems that soon after the outbreak and Seattle fell into absolute chaos,
这位女士就成为了一个小型邪教团体的领袖
this woman arose as the leader of a small cult.
她宣称虫草菌实际上是对人类过度依赖科学技术的惩罚
She claimed that the infection was effectively a punishment on humanity
for their overreliance on technology.
因此 她自然而然地规定她的所有追随者从事长年累月艰苦的体力劳动
So naturally she prescribed all of her followers to years and years of hard manual labour,
躬耕于田 以符合自然本身的方式生产自己的食物
working in the fields to produce their own food in a way that was congruity with nature itself.
这显然也导致了赛拉菲特帮严格的生活方式
This obviously lead to a very strict lifestyle for all of the Seraphites,
而他们愿意追随女先知的指引 愿意这样做
but they were willing to do it because of her guidance.
然后 在某个时刻 因为某种原因 她死了
However, she died, at some point, somehow.
就我所知 没有人提到她到底是怎么死的
As far as I could find, there's never a mention of exactly how she died.
如果你发现了什么 欢迎在评论区告诉我 我很想听听
If you came across something, please comment down below, I would love to know.
但我在游戏中多次深挖后
But in all of my digging in my multiple runthroughs of the game,
还是无法找到任何详细说明她具体如何死亡的资料
I couldn't find anything detailing specifically how she died.
我们知道的是 在她死后不久
What we do know is that soon after she died,
赛拉菲特教会的其他长老接管了大权
a bunch of other elders in the church of the Seraphites took over
并开始加强邪教的关键因素——对人的控制
and started ramping up the critical element of the cult, which was control.
自然 许多新掌权者开始陷入腐败状态
Naturally, many of the new leaders started to fall into corrupt states.
他们开始霸占更多的食物 开始控制不同的领土
They started to hog more food, they started to control different territories,
而在教徒们发现之前
and before they knew it,
赛拉菲特帮崇拜的就已经不是与自然不协调的生活
the Seraphites cult wasn't about living incongruity with nature,
而是越来越多对人思想的控制 与对长老命令的严格遵守
but rather was much more about control and strict adherence to the guidance and dictum of the elders.
这是顽皮狗编剧们的一个有趣的设定
This is an interesting choice by Naughty Dogs writers.
特别是由于其让赛拉菲特教徒更加让人同情
Specifically because it makes it so that the Seraphites followers are much more relatable and sympathetic.
每当你觉得
Whenever you feel as though
他们为了达到某种目的而采用了一些非常禽兽、野蛮的手段
they're employing some very animalistic and barbarian tactic to achieve a certain ends,
比如将人开膛破肚是为了让他升上天堂之类的
such as gutting somebody to release them into the heavens for some reason,
你总是可以回头借口说是这一切是有原因的
you can always fall back and partially excuse it
因为这些人只是遵循他们认为的来自宗教高层的指示
because these are people simply following directions that they believe are coming from on high.
大多数赛拉菲特教徒不是因为喜欢就去做一些罪大恶极的事情的大恶人
Most of the Seraphites aren't viciously evil and despicable people
trying to do despicable things because they enjoy it.
相反 他们只是试图在这样一个礼坏乐崩的世界中谋求生存的受害者
Rather, they're people simply trying to survive in a world that's really really messed up.
玩家这样的一个思想观点刚好是在
and it's no mystery that this is set up right around the time
埃比开始对之前邪教的成员感到同情的时间点建立起来的
when Abby is starting to feel sympathy towards members, or in this case, former members of the cult.
再次强调 整部游戏都是关于视角的
Again this game is all about perspectives.
它的目的是试图让你同情那些你以前认为自己不可能同情的人
And it's all about trying to get you to sympathize with people
that you didn't think you could possibly sympathize with before.
重点是 先知是一个非常有趣的角色
The point is, the Prophet is a very interesting character,
特别是考虑到她对赛拉菲特教徒思想上的控制
specifically considering the control that she seems to have over the Seraphites.
然而由于没有太多关于何时死亡或如何死亡的细节
However, without many details on exactly when she died or how she died,
我们不清楚她究竟死了多久
it's unclear at just how long she's been gone.
如果她只死了几年 那是一回事
It would be one thing if she had been dead for just a few years,
而这个时间可以慢慢往上加
and this is what's starting to ramp up.
但如果她已经死了十年十五年 导致了十多年的权力斗争
But it's an entirely another case for her to have been dead for ten or fifteen years,
最终滋生了这样病态的邪教 那就完全是另一回事了
leading to over a decade of power struggles, which eventually bred this new, morphed cult.
总之 我觉得赛拉菲特帮的设定还是挺有意思的
Regardless, I think the Seraphites are fairly interesting.
至少他们是一个而与众不同的团体
At the very least they are a little bit different,
而且他们提供了一种一群人如何在这样崩坏的世界里生存的崭新视角
and they offer a fresh perspective
on how a group of people might go about surviving in a world that's this messed up.
我特别喜欢这点 因为通常这类故事里出现的都是
I especially like it because so often these types of narratives are completely drowned out
食人族、野蛮部落或者只知道烧杀抢掠的之类
with cannibals and barbarians and looters and raiders,
基本都是你在一代游戏里遇到的那样
and basically everybody that you encountered in the first game.
在我看来 只有存在与众不同的点 才能让这些故事更有趣、更有创意
It's only in these more interesting and creative, in my opinion, stories
where you find something that's a little bit different.
比如《疯狂麦克斯》里的人对汽车、汽油的疯狂迷恋与崇拜
Such as in Mad Max, the strange obsession and worship of gasoline and cars.
这种与众不同就让人感觉真的很酷
It's something that's just really cool, and different.
扯远了
But I digress.
埃比在通过这段检查点后就算正式进入疤脸帮的领地范围了
Abby pushes through this checkpoint and officially enters Scars' territory.
这里我们会和大量的疤脸帮作战
Here we'll fight a ton of Scars,
而且相信我 等打到这关结尾你会杀一大堆的疤脸帮
and believe me, you're going to be ploughing through them by the end of this sequence.
而且这部分很多Boss战我非常喜欢
There's actually a great many boss fight here that I really enjoyed
这个女boss 我暂且叫她海尔格
Helga 德语名字 很强壮勇猛的感觉
算是名字的一种刻板印象
类似提到“吴克”就会想到光头
with a woman that I can only assume is named Helga.
我不知道她真名叫什么
I don't actually know if her name is Helga by the way
但她一看就感觉太海尔格了
I'm just saying that because she looks like Helga.
呃……反正最后埃比把她的耳朵咬下来一块 我觉得挺逗的
But regardless Abby bites off a part of her ear, which I thought was kind of funny.
但她又叫来了一群帮手
But eventually a bunch of her friends come over.
他们按住了埃比 把她打晕了
They overpower Abby and knock her out,
画面来到了四个月前的闪回
which then leads straight into a flashback to four months before.
这段闪回刚好发生在游戏序章以前
This would place this flashback right before the events of the prologue,
埃比和她的整个小队准备出发前往杰克逊小镇
when Abby and her whole group left for Jackson.
时值冬日 埃比发现欧文在水族馆里架起了好多彩灯
It's Winter, Abby finds Owen in the aquarium with a bunch of pretty lights put up.
很惬意
It's really relaxing,
TLOU2游戏后半部分这样的节奏变换与对比很常见
and it really is this calming contrast that's the name of the game for the second half of TLOU2.
先发生了一些坏事
Something horrible will happen,
然后给玩家看一些轻松愉快的内容
and then we'll see something pretty and relaxing,
然后更糟糕的事情发生
and then something, even more horrible will happen.
然后切回冬日里这样的温馨画面
and then we cut back to a nice winter scene, and so on.
这里有很多互动小游戏 你可以拿玩具弓箭射一堆目标
In here there's actually many game where you can shoot some targets with a kitty bow and arrow.
看着挺蠢的 但能让玩家不用看枯燥无味的对话
It's pretty damn stupid, but it gives the players something to do that isn't just talking.
否则这段闪回就纯粹是埃比和欧文俩人唠嗑、上楼、再唠十块钱的画面了
Otherwise this entire flashback would simply be Abby, talking to Owen,
walking up some stairs and then talking some more.
倒不是说顽皮狗不敢在游戏里放长达十分钟的过场动画
It's not to say that Naughty Dogs afraid of doing that in games or having a 10 minute cut scene,
但我感觉他们是能避免就避免
but it seems to me that if they can avoid it, they will,
他们会穿插这样的小游戏来打破单调的气氛
and they'll interspersed little mini game such as this to break up the monotony.
不过现在这一段剧情的重点是告诉玩家 埃比找到了汤米
Now the point of the sequence, though, is to show that Abby found Tommy,
或者至少知道他住在杰克逊小镇了
or, at the very least has a lead that he's living in Jackson.
当然了 重点是他们希望汤米能帮助他们找到乔尔
And the point, of course, is that they hope that Tommy could help them find Joel.
而我们当然也知道乔尔其实也住在杰克逊
Of course, we know that Joel was living there too,
但显然这时埃比并不知道此事
But apparently, at this time Abby didn't know that.
至少我不清楚埃比在开场时是否仍认为他们只在寻找汤米
It's not clear to me at least
if Abby still thought they were looking only for Tommy in the opening sequence,
或者到那时她是否认为乔尔也可能在那里
or if by that time she thinks that Joel could be there too.
但我认为一些对话显示出她肯定想要去找乔尔
But I mean some of the dialogue seems to imply that she's looking for Joel primarily,
但他们以为自己只能先找到汤米
but that they only expected to find Tommy.
当然了 我说过我认为这没那么重要
But again, I just don't think it matters too much.
重点是 他们要去杰克逊小镇 通过汤米这条线索找乔尔
The point is they're going to Jackson for Joel by way of Tommy,
如果乔尔也在那 那妥了
and if Joel happens to be there, great.
但他们预想是先找到汤米 然后希望能从他口中套出乔尔在哪之类的消息
But they mostly expect to find Tommy and hope to convince him to share Joel's location or whereabouts.
总之 在埃比告诉欧文自己有一条乔尔弟弟的线索后
Regardless after breaking to Owen that she has a lead on Joel's brother
她还告诉欧文伊萨克批准了执行这次行动的小队
Abby also throws out the fact that Isaac approved the whole squad,
允许他们离开几周去追杀乔尔
leaving for weeks on end to chase Joel down.
她说艾萨克比谁都坚持正义
She exclaims that Isaac is more about justice than any one,
所以他才会允许这些人离开西雅图几周 甚至几个月的时间
which is why he apparently approves of the plan
for them to leave for weeks and weeks on end, potentially months
去追杀一个好几年前做了一些坏事的人
trying to hunt down a guy that did something terrible years and years ago.
我个人感觉伊萨克能允许这么多人离开挺牵强的
To me, it seems like a stretch that he would be willing to let this many people go,
尤其还有不少要参加巡逻、戍守WLF边防的年轻新兵
especially young whippersnappers, who were involved in the active patrolling
and maintenance of the WLF's defenses.
但可能只有我这么想吧
But regardless, maybe that's just me.
或许让他们离开这件事是符合伊萨克的性格的 而我却感觉牵强
And may be it actually is within Isaac's character to let them go but it seems like a stretch to me.
在一阵争辩过后 他们决定了
After a brief debate back and forth, they settle on it.
他们要去杰克逊寻找汤米
They're going to Jackson, they're going to try to find Tommy,
然后尝试找到乔尔复仇 了结这一切
and then they're going to try and find Joel, once and for all, and finish it.
画面切回丛林里
Now we cut back to the forest.
这其实是我们很多年前在预告片里第一次看到埃比的场景
This is actually the trailer sequence that we saw back when we first met Abby years ago.
我还记得我第一次看这个预告片的时候
I remember when I first saw this scene in the trailer,
我还猜埃比这人会不会最后发现是艾莉的妈妈
I thought that Abby was going to turn out to be Ellie's mom in this flashback,
但……好吧……
But… well…
我猜错了
I was wrong.
错得离谱
Like… really wrong.
疤脸帮把埃比吊起来准备处刑
The Scars start to string up Abby for execution
却被他们刚抓来的一个女孩中断了
when they're interrupted by a young girl that they've just captured.
赛拉菲特：雅拉。
另外一个叛徒呢？
我们目前还不知道这是什么意思 但简单来讲的话
Now we don't know what this means, but for simplicity's sake,
这个叫雅拉的女孩和其他的 不知道是谁的叛徒
this girl Yara and the other apostate, whoever they may be,
做了一些事情激怒了疤脸帮
did something to piss off the Scars.
在雅拉向那个疤脸帮长老吐口水之后 她下令“折断她的翅膀”
After Yara spits in this elder Scars face, she is sentenced to having her wings clipped,
而我不得不说
and I have to say,
我看完才这段操作发现这分明是属于暴力拆解
this is probably the least clippy way they could have possibly clipped her wings.
另一个叛徒后来也现身了 名字叫勒弗
The other apostate shows up who will eventually find out his name Lev.
他向赛拉菲特帮射了几箭
Lev starts shooting arrows at the Seraphites,
解决掉了几个
killing a couple of them.
又和长老纠缠了一会 也把她解决掉了
And after a brief tussle with the elder, she's also killed.
然后勒弗听从雅拉的指示 把埃比放了下来 差点就要被勒死了
Following Yara's direction, Lev cuts Abby down, just in time for her to not die.
真的 她刚才可太悬了
I mean seriously, she was really close.
他们杀死长老后就让她吊在那 太扯了
They just kind of left her hanging here after she killed the elder little… little ridiculous,
但……埃比还真就在那吊了一会
双关：“hang in there” 直译是“吊在那”
一般意思是“坚持住！”
but you know whatever she was just hang in there, and… and that's that.
放埃比下来后 他们开始准备对抗感染者
After Abby's cut down, they all prep to fight some zombies,
怕你们忘 提醒你们一下这游戏是有感染者的
just in case that you forgot that this game actually has zombies in it,
因为到这时好像好久没看到感染者了
because at this point it's been a hot minute since they were featured.
这里有一点很有趣 值得注意一下
And a fun little fact, and something to notice is that
埃比脖子上这条勒出的伤痕会一直伴随埃比后半段的游戏
this rash and brews over Abby's neck will actually remain for the rest of the main story.
这个细节很棒 提高了游戏的沉浸体验
It's a great detail, and it really helps with immersion,
尤其等稍后的场景里
especially as later scenes come and go,
你可以看到埃比用手揉自己的脖子 因为还很疼
you'll see Abby rubbing her neck because it still hurts,
毕竟当了那么久的晴天娃娃
because after all she was just hung from it.
顽皮狗可是出了名的喜欢钻细节
It's this attention to detail that Naughty Dog is really known for
这点没得黑
and that you have to compliment them on.
这些场景之间的拍摄可能隔了几个月
These scenes are filmed months apart from each other
有时可能还要经历数年后重写 重拍
in some cases, years apart after rewrites and reshoots,
然后围绕其对游戏关卡进行修改
and then changing the game and level design around them,
然后关卡改了 过场又要跟着重拍
they have to reshoot it because the level design change.
从这样大量的细节就能看出他们有多在乎此事
This amount of detail that's thrown in shows just how much they care.
他们会记录下角色身上发生的一切事情
They made notes of absolutely everything that was going on with the character
这样即使过了几个月 他们也可能翻出来 想想说
so that months after the fact, they would be able to reference back and say,
“诶 埃比在这吊了这么久 是不是脖子应该疼啊
"Oh, Abby's neck was sore here because she was hung from it,
在游戏的时间里她也刚被放下来几小时
just a few hours of gameplay before this in the game's timeline,
所以你应该在人物表演中表现出这一点”
so make sure that that's reflected in your performance."
这种水平的细节追求是非常罕见的
That level of detail is something that's really rare
大多只能在好莱坞看到 而且也不是很多作品都有
you mostly only see it in Hollywood, and even then you don't see it on very many productions.
最后你逃出了一众感染者 遇到了老朋友海尔格
But anyway, you escape the infected and come upon your old friend, Helga,
她正在攻击落单的勒弗
attacking Lev who was leaving the pack.
你和她有一段快速的肉搏战 最后你终于一个大锤80让她……
You have a quick fist fight where you eventually finish her with a hammer to…
……破相了
well, the face.
埃比也把装备拿了回来
And Abby gets her stuff back
因为海尔格刚好在抓走埃比之后把她的包背在了自己身上
because Helga just happened to be wearing Abby's backpack after capturing her earlier.
我觉得这样的设定还是挺有趣的
I actually thought this was kind of a fun touch,
因为类似这样的游戏 在角色被绑架后想找回装备
since the normal way that you would find all of your gear after being kidnapped like this in a video game
而装备通常只是放在某个箱子里或者桌子上
would be to just find it in a chest or sitting on a desk somewhere.
现在三人之间进行了一段关于赛拉菲特帮和WLF的对话
Now there's some dialogue here about the Seraphites and the WLF
看他们能互相信任还是挺奇怪的
and it's strange for them to trust each other.
但在这个节骨眼上 他们都互相救了对方
But at this point they've both saved each other's lives,
所以还是稍微能理解的
which is why it's a little more understandable.
埃比刚刚从海尔格手里救下了勒弗 勒弗也救下了要被吊死的埃比
Abby just saved Lev's life from Helga and Lev just saved Abby from hanging.
我觉得这种一报还一报的情节的存在促使两人结成了血盟关系
There is a clear tit for tat here, which is why I think this blood pact is formed.
埃比最后还直截了当地问了勒弗怎么回事
Now Abby eventually asks Lev the obvious question
埃比：从没见过疤脸帮自己人追自己人。
勒弗：赛拉菲特。
埃比：你到底干了什么？
勒弗：我剃了头。
埃比：好吧，不用告诉我。
而勒弗的回答其实很真诚
and Lev is being honest here,
我其实不在乎。
但背后的具体内容远比看起来得复杂
but it's far more complicated than it seems.
不过不着急 我们会聊到这部分的
But don't worry, we're going to get to that later.
你和你新小队又杀了几波感染者 慢慢开始相互信任起来
Your new little crew fights through waves of infected and slowly begin trusting each other more and more.
剧情在埃比抱起雅拉 让勒弗看好四周的时候达到了高潮
The sequence actually climaxes with Abby carrying Yara while Lev keeps watch.
你们一起来到了一个拖车小屋 打算过夜
You all push into a small office trailer and set up camp for the night.
埃比出于关心 帮雅拉简单看了一下胳膊
Feeling bad for them, Abby helps Yara set her arm,
明显看着挺严重的
which is clearly in some serious trouble.
简单打理好后 埃比离开了
After helping them with this Abby leaves.
她救了一个疤脸帮 她和他们一样感到了纠结
Just as baffled as they are that she just helped a Seraphite.
而作为另一个游戏角色之间的类比
In yet another reflection between characters,
埃比发现她自己变成了另一个欧文
Abby has found herself in the same position that Owen found himself in.
她帮助了一名疤脸帮
She seemingly helped a Scar,
而这在WLF里可是大忌
which is something that the WLF is never supposed to do.
这将完全改变接下来的情节
This is going to completely change the following scene,
我们马上就会看到
but we'll get to that in just a second.
埃比走的时候 内心的纠结是可想而知的
As Abby leaves Yara and Lev, her perplexion is palpable.
她关心这两个孩子 但她自己却不知道为什么
She cares for these two kids, and she doesn't even really know why.
这种感觉就像玩家现在对埃比的情感一样
It's the same emotion that the player is likely feeling towards Abby herself,
游戏这样的安排真是太妙了
which is why it's so brilliant that it was done this way.
埃比和玩家有相同的困惑与内心的矛盾
Abby is feeling the same confusion and inner conflict as the player.
埃比是因自己竟然会同情对面阵营的两个敌人而困扰
But in this case she's baffled that she's been made to feel sympathy
for members of a group that she's supposed to hate,
而我们玩家 则是因为我们想去恨杀死乔尔的埃比而感觉到矛盾
whereas we, the player likely feel that conflict because we want to hate Abby for killing Joel.
可能我们中还有一些人仍增恨埃比
And maybe a part of us still does,
但我们至少已经慢慢开始同情她 甚至开始关心她了
but at the very least we're beginning to sympathize with her and even care for her.
这样的处理真的很棒
It's masterfully done.
正是这样精妙的故事安排才成就了这样一款游戏
And it's this subtle character work that makes this game what it is.
也因此 我认为虽然游戏有节奏上的问题 但我还是建议大家能够认真通关
And why, in my opinion, you have to play it all the way through, even despite the pacing issues.
最后 埃比在船厂解决了一大堆的感染者
Now, eventually, Abby fights her way through a ton of infected in a shipping yard
来到了一些停泊于此的船上
and finds her way to a series of boats and ships.
你又杀了一堆感染者 最后拿到了十字弓
You fight your way through another group of infected and stumble across a crossbow,
这是整个游戏里我最喜欢的武器
which is actually my favorite weapon in the entire game.
解决掉所有感染者后 你来到了欧文所在的水族馆
After you push through all of these infected you get to the aquarium where Owen is staying,
但你到处都找不到欧文
However, you can't find Owen anywhere.
埃比有点担心 怕他死了 或者被抛弃后决定离开自己的岗位
Abby starts to kind of freak out, worrying that he's dead or just abandoned and went AWOL.
但最终埃比还是找到了他
But eventually Abby stumbles on to him.
他坐在船上 正在修上面的冰箱
He's sitting in the boat that he's been trying to fix up fridges.
埃比：欧文？
这条船看起来是他在世界上唯一安全的小空间了
and it seems as though it's his one safe space left in the world.
然后埃比和欧文开始对话
Abby and Owen start talking, and…
你们懂的……这段不太好解释……
you know, I can't really explain this part in a good way,
我就直接播片了……
so I'm just going to let it play… so…
埃比：要不要说说发生了什么事？
欧文：我们当时正在收拾一小拨人。
就几个疤脸帮的，然后……
我照着头给了那个人一下，
特别重的一下，
然后他就倒在地上了，
他的武器就在旁边，
但是他也没去拿。
他直接……
转了过来。
是个老头，
看着像是活够了。
已经……
准备好上路了。
疤脸帮的人我杀过不少，
可是……
这个可恶的老头，
我实在下不去手。
当然了，丹尼就不停地催我动手。
我直接告诉他我不干。
想动手的话他可以自己来。
结果他就拿着他那把枪对着我了，
我就本能地去抓，然后……
我一开始根本都分不清我们俩是谁中枪了。
埃比：你当时是自我防卫。
欧文：够了——
埃比：这件事情包在我身上，
我去跟伊萨克说——
欧文：埃比，我干腻了。
爱怎么样怎么样吧，我不想再为要占据那些地区卖命了。
我准备去圣塔芭芭拉。
埃比：你能不能别听风就是雨？
欧文：那个消息我听到了不止一次。
埃比：火萤并没有要重新集结。
不会再出现了。
欧文：这是一条线索……
我不能就这么放过去了。
埃比：那梅尔呢？
欧文：她待在这里会安全点。
埃比：好吧。
我们明早再说这些，等你清醒点。
欧文：你什么意思？
埃比：什么我什么意思？
欧文：说得我他妈神经不正常似的。
你也有同样的感觉。
埃比：如果火萤真的正在圣塔芭芭拉重新集结……
那我他妈能离他们多远就有多远。
怎么了？
欧文：没什么。
埃比：不好意思，我长大了。
欧文：（不屑）
埃比：你也应该试试。
欧文：是吗？埃比，你教教我，怎么长大？
我是不是要先找到杀害我家人的凶手，
把他们切成碎块？
我可以折磨他们，直到他们哭着——
欧文：埃比。
好耶！18+！18+！好耶！
So yeah, sexy times,
我完全没料到会是这样的发展
I personally didn't see that coming at all,
而且说实话我也完全不知道该说什么
and I'll be honest I'm not entirely sure what to make of it.
就感觉挺突然的……明明都要打起来了 怎么就突然开始……热身运动了
It kind of comes out of left field because they were fighting and then they start… start banging,
我真不……彳亍口巴……你们开心就好
I don't… good for them, I mean, I guess it makes sense.
感觉有很多发自肺腑的真情实感在流露出来
There's a lot of tension and visceral emotion going on,
但我感觉这些都是毫无根据的
but it seemed to come out of nowhere to me.
我也不明白 如果有什么深度的文学原因 请告诉我 谢谢
I don't know, there's some deeper literary reason for this. I would love to hear it.
我也不知道自己想没想过这些 但我反正是不知该如何评价
I'm not sure I've thought about it, but I don't really know what to make of it.
所以……我们继续
So… moving on.
在「西雅图 第1天」结尾 埃比做噩梦了 梦见她在自己父亲去世的医院房间里
Seattle Day 1 wraps up with Abby having a bizarre nightmare about Yara and Lev being killed and strung up
看到雅拉和勒弗被吊死
in the very same hospital room where her father died,
在我看来 这似乎意味着她对他们有某种家人般的情感
which to me seems to imply that she feels some sort of familial attachment to them.
因为在埃比的梦中 他们死在了和父亲一样的地方
Since in her dream they die in the same place that her father died.
我觉得一定不能低估她在这样的一个地方梦见他们的意义
I really don't think you can understate the significance of her seeing them in this space.
如果她单纯因为担心他们遇害而感到压力
If she was stressing out purely about them being killed,
那她大可只梦见回WLF基地的路上看到了他们的尸体
why wouldn't she just have a nightmare where she imagines coming across their bodies
as she was heading back to the WLF base.
所以她这样的梦境发生在那所医院内是非常重要的
The fact that she has this dream and it set in the hospital is significant,
我认为这体现出她自己有着超乎自己想象的 与这两个孩子的情感上的联系
and I think it shows that she has a much deeper bond with these kids than even she realizes.
所以这样的梦过后 她决定亲自回去看看 确保他们还安全
So after this dream she decides that she needs to go and make sure that they're okay.
没错 她正式决定要去帮助那两个疤脸帮了
Yeah, she's actually going to go and help Scars.
就像其他WLF士兵一样困惑
She's just as baffled as any other WLF member would be,
她似乎也发现 之前欧文在这样的场景也是同样的感受
and it seems that she's coming to the realization that Owen also came to.
她也干腻了
She's done with all of it.
西雅图 第2天
「西雅图 第2天」
Seattle Day 2.
埃比一醒来就回到了船厂的方向
So after Abby wakes up she rushes back to the shipping yard
想要找到雅拉和勒弗
to try and find Yara and Lev.
她遇到了大量的疤脸帮 其中还有几个野蛮人
She encounters a ton of Scars, including several Brutes,
让战斗更加有趣
which leads to a fairly interesting combat encounter.
解决掉他们后 埃比回到了拖车上小屋
After clearing them out, Abby heads back into the office trailer,
发现雅拉的状况真的很糟糕
and she finds Yara in really bad shape.
她的胳膊肿的像猴屁股一样
Her arm looks like a cherry laffey taffy,
很明显她需要一些……就说是“非常严重的治疗”吧
and it's clear that it's going to need some… let's just say "severe treatment".
所以埃比抱起雅拉 把她带回水族馆 勒弗一路跟随
So she picks Yara up and she brings her to the aquarium with Lev trailing close behind.
她的计划基本上是让梅尔尽一切手段治疗雅拉的手臂
Her plan is basically to have a Mel treat Yara's arm in whatever capacity that may take.
不用说也知道 这是一场豪赌
Needless to say, this is a pretty big gamble.
因为埃比相当于出卖了伊萨克和其他WLF成员
Because of Abby has found out and ratted out to Isaac and the other WLF members,
她最终很有可能会完全被组织排斥在外
she's likely going to end up either completely ostracized from the group,
或者因为帮助敌人而直接被处决
or downright executed for helping out their prime enemy.
诚然 你可以说这俩人是前疤脸帮成员
Sure, you could say that they are former members of the group now
他们背叛了疤脸帮 所以帮助他们也没什么问题
and that they should be helped because they are apostate from the group.
但我感觉这点并不重要
But it doesn't really matter.
通常情况下 敌人的敌人就是朋友
In this type of situation, the enemy of the enemy is your friend.
但在这个例子里 敌人的敌人还真不是你的朋友
In this case, the enemy of the enemy is not actually your friend.
他们都是你应该杀死的敌人罢了
It's just somebody that you should ostracize and kill
因为在这样一个末世 人们没工夫考虑那些复杂的道德与伦理难题
because complicated moral and ethical quandaries aren't worth the trouble
in a post apocalyptic world.
总之 梅尔在初次见面没被吓到过后
Regardless after taking a look and not initially freaking out,
诊断说是粉末性骨折 想活命就必须截肢
Mel determines that the bone is completely shattered and that the arm has to come off
if she has any chance of surviving.
随后梅尔列出了手术需要的工具列表
Mel then explains what she needs for this operation.
欧文说为啥不直接一刀下去然后用火药烧一下伤口呢
She could just take a knife and hack at it and try to cauterize the wound with fire,
as Owen points out.
但这样很容易导致感染
But this would likely lead to infection very quickly.
他们要帮人帮到底 送佛送到西
If they're going to do this, they might as well do it right.
所以梅尔说她需要一些手术器具
So Mel requests to saw and some other surgical equipment.
埃比说她可以回医院拿
Abby, says that she could get it from the hospital.
问题是按照WLF从水族馆到医院的正常路线
Problem being that the hospital, according to the WLF routes that are in place right now,
单程就要一天 来回需要两天 雅拉根本等不了那么久
is gonna take roughly a day to reach and then a day to return from, far too long for Yara.
这时勒弗提出他们可以走疤脸帮用的“桥”
It's at this point that Lev offers help
by giving access to the bridge system that the Scars used
这样就能在城市的楼顶上方穿行了
to navigate the city from the rooftops.
目前大家还不清楚具体是什么样的桥
It's not clear exactly what this is going to be or what form it's going to take.
另外 让我感觉有点奇怪的是 欧文和埃比这样的WLF成员
It also, it's a little strange to me that the WLF member, such as Owen and Abby,
竟然对他们所谓的“桥”毫不知情
don't seem to be aware of this bridge system whatsoever.
WLF的确知道疤脸帮能在城市里非常快速地移动
They are aware that the Scars are able to navigate the city very quickly
快到让人感觉像变魔术
so quickly that it seems almost supernatural
但显然他们从来就没想过
but apparently never occurred to them that
疤脸帮可能会利用房顶上的桥来在城市里旅行
they might be using bridge systems above the city by using the rooftops.
勒弗说可以带他们去疤脸帮的桥梁系统
The point is that Lev offers to give them access to this bridge system.
他非常熟悉路线
Lev knows these routes very well
并说按照他们的路线大概能在两小时内就能到达医院
and says that they should be able to reach the hospital in around 2 hours if they were to follow the route.
埃比没有过多犹豫 直接就出发了
And so without much hesitation, Abby agrees and leaves.
他们出门的时候 欧文拦下了埃比 想要和她谈谈
As they're leaving the aquarium, Owen stops Abby and tries to talk,
但她一点也不想聊昨晚的激情一夜
but she is not interested in addressing what happened a night before with the sexy time.
因为她好像找到了自己新的家庭上的归属
And it seems that she's found her new family and obsession.
我们看到她真的放下欧文了
This is the first time that we've really seen her move past Owen
而且行为上也不那么依赖他
and behave in a way that doesn't seem completely obsessive towards him.
给人一种刮目相看的感觉
It's kind of refreshing to be honest.
在此之前埃比很明显还对欧文有感情
Prior to this, it's very clear that Abby still has feelings for Owen.
即使是序章里我们第一次见到埃比和欧文鸟瞰雪中的杰克逊小镇时
And even in the first chapter when we originally met Abby and Owen
when their overlooking snow-crested Jackson,
我们可能已经感觉到埃比和欧文两人间弥漫的奇怪的紧张情绪
We saw that Abby and Owen shared a strange tension.
埃比在她父亲去世后从来就没和欧文真正走到一起去过
Abby and Owen can never really get on the same page after her father died.
而且显然 乔尔死了以后也没什么改变
And quite obviously, since Joel's death, nothing has changed.
所以欧文开始粘着梅尔 即使这俩人也不怎么对付
This is lead Owen sticking with Mel, even though they're pretty clearly not compatible
甚至看起来彼此不那么喜欢对方
and even don't seem to particularly like each other.
我不能完全确定这是否是故意安排的
I'm not entirely sure if this was intentional or not,
但对我来说欧文和梅尔之间完全没有化学反应是肯定的
but the fact that there's zero chemistry between Owen and Mel seems pretty obvious to me.
如果编剧想让玩家感觉到俩人有感情 那以顽皮狗的实力肯定是能做到的
And if the writers are even somewhat competent, as I believe they are over at Naughty Dog,
surely somebody noticed this.
所以要么是演员的完美表演和编剧的刻意安排
So either it was masterful performance on the part of the actors and the writers to make sure that
让角色们看起来就是没有共同点 就是聊不到一起去
these characters didn't seem to have that much in common didn't seem to get along particularly well,
两人之间就是有很深的紧张情绪在里面发酵
and that they had an immense amount of tension brewing between them.
要么就完全是游戏制作上和编剧策划上的失误
Either that was completely intentional or it was an accident,
and it was the result of a misfire and the writing.
我个人倾向于前一种
I think it's the former personally.
我认为梅尔和欧文就是要给人一种怪怪的感觉
I think that Mel and Owen are supposed to come off as a little strange.
队伍里其他人看起来都知道他们两人之间奇怪的氛围
Everyone else in the group seems to be aware that their relationship is a little bizarre
同时欧文和埃比看起来互相对对方有感觉
and that Owen and Abby seem to have feelings for each other
但玩家却不明白为何俩人没走到一起
and they're confused as to why they are not just together.
而这种紧张的情绪总会得到解决……等就好了
But that tension will eventually be resolved, just… just wait.
离开水族馆后 埃比和勒弗要前往一座大楼 爬到顶端
After leaving the aquarium, Abby and Lev head to the tower
that they need to climb all the way to the top of
才能登上勒弗之前说的“桥”
in order to gain access to the aforementioned "bridge".
真的老高了 而且刚好顶端还被云雾挡住了
It's pretty damn high up there, and it happens to be covered by clouds and fog.
这样的安排真的很巧妙 提升了这种场景下的紧张感
This is a nice and coincidentally thing because it adds to the tension of the situation.
但这还是没有解释为什么WLF至今都没发现这座“桥”
But it doesn't answer the question as to how the WLF weren't aware of this bridge system.
因为西雅图总不可能天天都云雾缭绕的吧
Because chances are, it's not always cloudy and foggy
总不能天天都看不见高楼大厦的楼顶
to the point where you can't see to the top of these skyscrapers.
肯定会有人在天晴的时候看到楼顶有桥
Surely somebody saw these bridges when the sky was clear.
在我看来 WLF觉得没有必要去探索这种
It seems bizarre to me that the WLF didn't feel the need to explore these bridge systems
几乎能完美沟通几座摩天大楼的桥梁系统是很奇怪的
that seemed to go perfectly between skyscrapers and buildings very high up,
尤其是在地面上你都能看到
especially when they would have been visible from the ground.
但或许只有我会这么较真吧
But I guess that's just me.
现在 埃比和勒弗一点点向那座高楼推进
Now, as Abby and Lev are heading to the top of this tower,
爬上几栋建筑 探索了很多区域
they climbed through multiple buildings, explore some different areas,
还聊了很多有趣的东西
and they share in a few interesting conversations.
没什么特别的事情 多数都是有一搭没一搭地闲聊
Now there's nothing really crazy here, it's mostly awkward small talk,
但主要是为了表现他们两人彼此越来越融洽
but it mostly serves to show that they are growing more comfortable with each other.
我最喜欢的时刻是偶然进到某间公寓里
My personal favorite moment is when they come across somebody's apartment,
公寓主人显然很喜欢玩游戏
who was clearly very into gaming.
桌面上甚至摆着《龙与地下城》的桌游
In fact, they even still have their D&D game set up
家里还摆着PlayStation的游戏机之类的设备
and they have their Playstation gear scattered throughout the apartment.
感觉挺酷的
It's kind of cool.
我个人认为这样的房子很可能就是根据某个开发者自己家建模的
And personally, I would like to think that this whole apartment is modeled
after one of the developers apartments.
我的确听说过贝塞斯达和洛克斯代迪做过类似的事情
贝塞斯达(Bethesda): 《辐射》《上古卷轴》系列制作商
洛克斯代迪(Rocksteady): 《蝙蝠侠》系列制作商
I've heard stories of developers from Bethesda and Rocksteady doing this type of thing
他们把自家员工的工作环境建模成游戏里的场景
where they take an environment model it after their own personal environment
毕竟 这就是他们身边的事物
because after all, that's what they know.
这是游戏这个虚拟世界中来自真实世界的影子
It's a little piece of the real world in this imaginary world,
我觉得这太酷了
and I just think that it's super cool.
而且我觉得这个房间的细节也很丰富
And I thought that this particular building was especially detailed.
两人继续穿过很多建筑
The two travel through a plethora of buildings,
越过一些急流
they push through some rapids,
来到了目标大楼旁边的一处建筑工地
and they eventually land on a construction site that's next to the target building.
这个建筑工地是我认为整个游戏里最有趣的战斗场景之一
Now it just so happens that in this construction site
is one of the most interesting combat arenas of the entire game.
有大范围的垂直空间 到处都有赛拉菲特帮
There's a ton of verticality here and there's a lot of Seraphites scattered throughout.
有野蛮人 有些拿近战武器
Some of them are Brutes, some of them have short range weapons,
还有些拿远程武器的
and some of them have long range weapons.
在较高难度下这些敌人的布局真的很有意思
It's really interesting how they laid all of this out and on harder difficulties.
我承认我玩的时候可被整惨了
Let me just tell you it kicked my ass a few times.
但重要的是 游戏这里仍然感觉很平衡
But it's important to say that it felt fair.
我没有感觉游戏在故意刁难人 或者说是在轻视玩家
It wasn't as though I was getting my ass handed to me, and I felt like I was being slighted
没有搞什么无脑设计的那种比如能穿墙的逆天boss
like a poorly designed boss that's able to clip through walls or something.
这段关卡平衡做的很好
This level feels completely fair.
这给人的感觉单纯是局面很困难 需要两人的配合
It just seems like a difficult situation where Lev and Abby have to work perfectly in tandem.
而俩人的配合上道了 事情就简单了
And when that happens, things work out.
清空这部分区域后
But after clearing this area,
两人登上工地用的电梯 送他们直接到大楼的顶端然后上桥
the two get into an industrial elevator that they can take all the way to the top to reach the bridge.
如果大家还记得的话 其实埃比特别恐高
Now, if you remember from earlier Abby's worst nightmare is heights.
而这里勒弗还给她分享了一下忘掉恐惧的小建议
Here, Lev actually shares a bit of sweet advice to try and take out his mind off of the terror
让她能把注意力从位置变高带来的恐惧中转移出来
that she feels due to the enormous and ever increasing heights.
勒弗：能给你一些建议吗？
埃比：天哪……
勒弗：就……想想关于恐惧的好的一面。
埃比：好的一面？
勒弗：比如说……你会跑得更快。
你的注意力会更集中。
埃比：他妈的。
勒弗：你不会感觉到疼痛。
所有的负面感觉……
手心冒汗，心跳加速……
都是你变得更强的信号。
所以当你感到害怕时，你应该想想你的身体
是如何为即将到来的事情做好准备。
“虚弱时我们才会发现自己真正的力量。”
来到大楼顶端 他们开始过桥了
Now, at the top of the skyscraper, they begin crossing the bridge,
而“桥”实际上只是一个倒塌的起重机
which is actually just a partially collapsed crane.
这还是证明了WLF应该是可以在晴天看到这架起重机的
This again reaffirms the point that the WLF probably should have seen this crane on a clear day
这足以让他们发现点什么 让他们去调查了
and been intrigued enough to go and investigate it.
甚至可以霸占为己有
Maybe even claiming it for themselves.
也许有一句话或其他东西提到了为什么WLF没有使用这座桥
Maybe there's a line or something that mentions why the WLF haven't used this bridge,
而我只是错过了 或者我在写脚本时想不起来或忘了
and I just missed it or I couldn't think of it or remember it when writing the script.
但总之如果有什么漏掉的 请告诉我
But either way, if there is something, let me know.
现在大家都能猜到 埃比过桥的时候人都吓懵了
Now, understandably, Abby starts crossing the bridge and begins to completely freak out.
而且说实话 这地方谁来谁都得腿软
To be honest, any normal person would probably be freaking out at this point,
我觉得这已经不是恐不恐高的问题了
I don't think it's just people who are afraid of heights.
埃比这时候被吓成这个德行也说明了她过这座桥有多么艰难
But the fact that Abby is completely and utterly petrified by heights,
I think just proves the point that this is not a good time for her.
而且实际上在过这座临时桥的时候
And it's actually while crossing this makeshift bridge,
勒弗讲出了全游戏最搞笑的一句话
that Lev throws out one of the funniest lines of the entire game,
至少我感觉太逗了 因为这句就这么凭空冒出来
at least as far as I'm concerned, because it comes out of absolutely nowhere.
勒弗：你和你的朋友欧文怎么了？
埃比：天哪，勒弗！！一定要现在说吗？
勒弗：你们看起来真的很尴尬！
埃比：赶紧走吧！
哈哈哈 可太逗了
Hah… I love it!
过完第一作桥后
Now after crossing the first bridge,
似乎他们终于通过了最困难的部分
it seems as though they've finished and gotten through the hardest part.
但……并没有
But… NO.
埃比：天哪，勒弗！
勒弗：你不会有事的。看着我。
埃比：可恶。
这可能是少数我能记起的
Now this is one of the few times I really remember
被游戏的背景设定深深惊到的地方了
being completely blown away by a set piece in this game.
整座桥是那么优美 又危机四伏
The bridge is beautiful and yet creepy at the same time.
远处的医院又是那么催人向前 令人振奋
and the hospital in the distance is also all inspiring,
还能非常好地告诉玩家他们在西雅图的什么地方
and serves its purpose very well in informing the player of where they are within Seattle.
但我还是要说一个令人失望的点
I will say, though it was a little disappointing
就是我第一次玩的时候发现远处模型贴图会出现Z-fighting的问题
Z-fighting是三维渲染时浮点精度不够时产生的贴图闪烁的bug
because there was some artifacting in Z-fighting on the textures when I first played,
但我还算能接受
but I can get over it.
顽皮狗这种秀贴图狂魔会出现这样的图像bug实在少见
It's pretty rare to see a graphical glitch like this in a Naughty Dog games
我就不追究了
so I'm letting it slide.
而事实就是如此 埃比跨越了这座桥
But just like that, Abby crosses the bridge.
她在勒弗的帮助下战胜了恐惧
She's conquered her fears with the Lev's help.
她完成了自己以为不可能完成的任务
She's achieved that which she thought was unachievable
成功跨越了这座巨大的……
that she could cross this grand expanse…
我勒个去她摔下来了！
… Oh, my God! She fell!
没错 她……掉下来了
So, yeah, she… she falls.
还好下面有个楼顶泳池
Good thing there is a penthouse pool right?
现在两人决定
Now the new dynamic duo decides
想办法到达大楼的底层
to work their way to the bottom of the tower now that they've crossed
等到了地面 他们就能直奔医院了
Once at the base, they are going to be able to head straight for the hospital.
在下楼过程中 你要面对大量的感染者
Throughout the descent, there's a few hordes that you fight through of infected.
埃比还会在这里找到喷火器 可能是游戏里最好用的范围武器
Abby also finds a flame thrower, which is probably the best hoard weapon in the entire game.
因为它喷射范围广
Because it has such a widespread.
很容易用来处理大量的人群和感染者
It makes it really easy to handle crowds and large numbers of infected.
但我不得不说这玩意燃料太稀缺了
But I will say that ammo is so limited.
很难长时间持续使用
It makes it really hard to use it in any sort of consistent way.
另外 我感觉这座大楼的关卡让我很兴奋
I'll also say that this tower actually excited me.
我本来以为这样的环境是设计包含垂直空间的战斗的大好机会
I thought there would be some really cool opportunities for
different combat sequences with a lot of verticality.
有些平台可能还会有一些用到绳索的元素
And maybe some platforming with the rope mechanic… some thing,
但其实这些内容真的不多
but really there's not much here.
玩家其实单纯是在找路下楼 仅此而已
You just kind of make your way to the bottom of the tower, and that's it.
在杀了几波感染者之后 总感觉这样大好机会就错过了
After fighting through a few rooms of infected, seems like a missed opportunity.
但总之 他们成功回到地面 出来后发现就在医院旁边
But regardless, they get to the bottom, and they come out right by the hospital.
而这也正是艾莉来到医院后到达的相同区域
And this is actually the same exact area that Ellie entered the hospital earlier
或者应该说是埃比先来 艾莉后来的
or in continuity I guess after this.
借着这个机会 我们可以聊聊游戏里大量使用重复区域这件事
Then this is probably a good time to bring up the fact that there are a lot of reused areas in the game.
很多人批评过这一点
This has been something that a lot of people have criticized.
他们认为顽皮狗只是在用不同角色重复使用相同的地图关卡
That Naughty Dog seems to just be recycling the same maps and levels with different characters,
在这个例子里就是埃比和艾莉
or in this case just between Abby and Ellie.
但我觉得单纯因为顽皮狗复用了关卡就批评他们是不公平的
But I don't think it's actually fair to criticize them purely because they reuse levels.
在我看来 游戏里的一个关卡至少应该是
A level in a video game at least seems to be, in my estimation,
一组不同物品的集合、一种布局的地图
a collection of different items, a lay out of a map,
以及一般来讲的各种可能性的组合
and in general, a pool of possibilities.
玩家可以做很多不同的事情来与这个关卡进行互动
Different things that the player can do to interact with that level to achieve a set goal.
一个简单的关卡可能就是一个带门的房间
A really simple level would just be a room with a door.
你走向门 开门 出去 你就完成这个关卡了
You walked to the door, open it and leave, you've completed the level.
但一个复杂的关卡可以有一个很复杂的目标
However, a complicated level would be one in which you have a complicated goal,
比如活着离开这片区域
such as making it out of this area alive.
然后制作者再让实现这个目标的过程复杂化
And then the developer complicates the achieving of that goal
比如引入许多不同的敌人 你必须解决他们才行
by introducing many different enemies that you could fight complicated traversal,
或者甚至设计一个谜题 你必须解决它 打开这扇门才行
or maybe even a puzzle that you have to solve in order to get through the door.
这就是你如何把一个关卡从走过一扇门这样简单的事情
This is how you take a level from something as simple as walking through a door
变成更复杂、吸引玩家的事情
into something more complicated and engaging for the player.
因此
For this reason,
我认为说顽皮狗在这里完全是在复用关卡是不公平的
I don't think it's completely fair to say that Naughty Dog is purely reusing levels here.
因为埃比和艾莉是在用完全不同的方式与这个关卡进行互动
Because Abby and Ellie interact with these levels in completely different ways.
埃比走进医院最终找到诺拉的过程中
When Abby's walking through the hospital here and eventually finds Nora,
她并没有这这些人进行战斗
she's not actually fighting these people.
她不会向他们开枪
She's not shooting them,
不会向他们扔炸弹 扔燃烧瓶
she's not throwing bombs and molotovs on them.
她只是路过 和路人们唠嗑
She's just walking and talking,
更不用说你还进了医院 看到了很多艾莉没看到的地方
not to mention that you also go to areas of the hospital that were unseen by Ellie.
拿这和艾莉在这部分的关卡相比的话
And when you compare this to Ellie traverse this level,
区别大了去了
well, it's pretty different.
如果你的观点是 制作者在游戏开发上走捷径
Now if your point is that they are clearly taking short cuts in terms of development
他们把这些角色放在相同的关卡场景内 然后以这种方式安排故事
by putting these characters in the same levels and structuring the story in that way,
那我觉得这样的观点是合理的
I think you can make that point, and perhaps that's fair.
如果这个场景在故事中是有意义的 或者安排的故事是有意义的
I don't see the inherent problem with reusing a level if it makes sense in the story
那我不觉得重复使用一个关卡有什么原则上的问题
or if you write the story in a way where that makes sense
因为一个高质量的游戏完全可以把所有场景设置在几条走廊这样小的地方
because a quality game can be set in something as small as a couple of hallways.
比如《P.T.》这款游戏 它只是一款试玩版游戏
Look at something like P.T., which was technically just a playable teaser,
但却能获得如此巨大的成功
but even that was considered to be wildly successful,
而它所有的场景只有两条走廊 一个里屋 一个浴室
and it only really took place in two hallways, a back room and a bathroom I suppose.
它全部内容就这些 但它的品质却是惊人的高
That's really all there was to it, and yet it was phenomenal.
你可以找一些简单的东西
You can knit pick something as simple as
比如一个模型在整个游戏里用了多少次
how many times a particular mesh is used throughout a game,
或者根据游戏如何使用这些资源来论证你的观点
or you can argue your point based on how the game uses that asset.
我认为后者听上去更合情合理一些
I think the latter is much more reasonable and much more defensible.
但我扯远了
But I digress.
埃比自己进了医院 留下勒弗在外面等着
Abby heads into the hospital alone, leaving Lev behind
原因很显然 要是有人在医院附近看到勒弗 那咱谁也甭想活了
because quite obviously, if Lev were seen anywhere near the hospital, we wouldn't survive for very long.
埃比和WLF的成员很聊得来
Abby plays it cool with all of the WLF members.
但大家发现埃比违抗了伊萨克的命令只是时间问题
But it's only a matter of time before everybody finds out that Abby's disobeyed Isaac's orders.
我觉得埃比自己是清楚的 所以她在这关才表现得如此着急
I think Abby knows this, which is why she's moving through the level pretty quickly,
想赶紧找到所需物资然后马上跑路
trying to find the materials that she needs and leave.
我的意思是 当然还有一部分原因是她要救的那个女孩
I mean not to mention also that the girl that she's getting the materials for
现在还在鬼门关呢 这可能对她也有鼓励
is on death's door that probably motivates her,
让她想动作快点 但……你们懂的
her rushing a little bit, but by who am I to say.
你进入医院 和几个人聊天 然后……哎呦这不巧了吗！
You walk through here, talking a few people and… oh look!
这不是之前艾莉捅死的玩PSV摸鱼的女孩吗？
It's the Vita girl that Ellie stabbed and crap out of earlier,
或者应该叫“之后”？因为她现在还活着 这可真……真奇妙
or I guess later, because he or she is still alive, that's… that's funny.
埃比进医院没蹦跶多久
Now Abby doesn't make it far into the hospital though.
有人向伊萨克报告后埃比就被人发现她从昨天开始一直在擅离职守
She's arrested once they check in with Isaac
and find out that she has actually been AWOL since the day before,
所以她就被锁在电梯栏杆上了
so she's locked up in the elevator.
她基本上会一直被关到所有人把东西搬回前线基地以后
She's basically gonna held until they transport everything back to the front base with Isaac,
到时候伊萨克再来处理她的事
where she'll be dealt with.
又是这件多次被提及的事情
Again this is something that was mentioned several times,
不止埃比听到过 艾莉也听说WLF有事情要发生
not just to Abby, but also that Ellie overheard there is something going on with WLF
他们在把所有物资运往前线基地
where they need all of their supplies at the front base.
他们还集结了所有的WLF士兵也前往前线基地
And they're also collecting all of the WLF members to that same front base.
感觉要发生什么事了 伊萨克在动员所有人
There's something happening, Isaac's mobilizing everybody.
大的要来了
Something's about to go down.
伊萨克之前提到要对赛拉菲特岛屿发起总攻
Isaac mentioned earlier that he's planning on doing one final push into the Seraphites' island
让这场战争做个了结
that they have to finish the war once and for all.
这不是个小事 因为这显然会牺牲成百上千条生命
It's a pretty big deal because without a doubt,
many hundreds or even thousands of people are about to die.
我甚至能想象到在另一个平行世界里
I could have seen an alternative timeline or storyline
埃比到这里没有继续为雅拉寻找救命的材料
where Abby instead of going after just materials to save Yara
而是决定去阻止这次侵略行动 拯救无数在这场战争中丧命的
decides to go and try and stop this invasion to save all of the lives of the Seraphites
赛拉菲特帮和WLF士兵的生命
and the lives of the WLF that will be wasted in this endeavor.
但我明白当前的剧情可能更有亲和力
But I understand that this is probably a little more relatable,
特别是当玩家能在情感上与一个角色产生联系的时候
especially because when you can emotionally attached the player to one character,
在这个例子里是雅拉 在另一个例子里是勒弗
in this case, Yara, and in another instance Lev.
相比于让玩家在情感上与WLF或赛拉菲特那样的邪教产生联系
You can do a lot more compared to if you are trying to make the player
feel emotionally engaged and attached to an organization
这样的安排能让编剧有更好的发挥空间
such as the WLF, or a cult, such as the Seraphites.
在埃比被锁在电梯栏杆上时 诺拉刚好经过
Now, while Abby's locked up in the elevator, Nora I just happened to come by.
她来的正是时候 把埃比放了
And she comes in clutch, and let's Abby go.
这也是之前艾莉爬通风管道的时候她与WLF成员发生小冲突的时候
This is actually why she was in trouble with the WLF members
back in Ellie section when she was climbing through the vent.
因为他们认为是诺拉把埃比放走的 因为的确是她干的
It's because they think that Nora let Abby go, because well, she did.
我真的感觉站在另一个视角明白一切发生了什么是一件很酷的事情
Again I think it's really cool to get a fresh understanding of
everything that was going on with this new perspective.
诚然 玩家不需要知道一切就能有很好的游戏体验或叙事体验
Yeah, you don't need to know everything
that was going on to have an enjoyable game, play experience or narrative experience.
很多小说中的故事都没有完全解释到底发生了什么
There's plenty of examples of books that don't really explain much of anything of what's going on.
它们只是可以选择留白 给读者无限的想象空间
They just cannot leave it there and leave it for your personal interpretation.
然而在TLOU2里 一切都是深思熟虑的
In TLOU2, however, everything's been thought through,
至少在某种程度上 你能够以这种新的视角回到过去
at least to a certain extent such that you're able to go back through with this new perspective,
了解更多东西 弄清楚为什么这些角色当时会这样做
learn more and figure out why these characters were doing what they were doing.
WLF不是为了游戏故事方便才一拍脑门决定把物资转移到别的地方
They weren't just moving materials from one location to the other to be convenient for the game story.
而是背后有一个宏大的侵略计划
But rather there is an overarching theme and idea behind it,
即使伊萨克的这个侵略与艾莉完全无关
even though that invasion has nothing to do with Ellie
即使就算艾莉的故事结束她也不知道有这样一回事
and really would never have been brought up if Ellie's story is where the game ended.
现在 诺拉领埃比去地下室收集雅拉胳膊手术需要的东西
Now, Nora leads Abby to the basement to let her collect the stuff that she needs for Yara's arm.
她不知道埃比在帮谁 也不知道她为什么需要这些东西
She doesn't know exactly who she's helping out or why she needs everything that she needs.
但她知道这些手术器具
But what she does know is that these surgical materials
很可能会用来救死扶伤
are probably going to be used for the betterment of somebody's life.
她还知道医院里其他地方所有物资都已经被清理走了
And she knows also that all of the other materials in the rest of the hospital have been picked clean
全都按照伊萨克的要求送到前线基地去了
and are being brought to the forward base where Isaac wants them.
所以埃比还能搜刮这些东西的地方只剩没清理的地下室了
And so the only place that's left for Abby to collect these items would be the basement.
问题是 疫情最初在2013年爆发的那一天
Problem being, when the outbreak initially happened in 2013, on outbreak day,
很多人都涌入了医院
everybody was brought to the hospital.
因此 当时在医院院内肯定会有相当大规模的传染
With this obviously, there was a massive outbreak within the hospital itself
直到最后整个医院都被隔离
and eventually everything was quarantined off.
锁上所有门 破坏掉所有楼梯 让感染者都上不来
The doors were locked and the stairs destroyed such that the infected couldn't reach the upper levels
把它们永久困在地下室里
and would be trapped in the basement indefinitely.
如果你玩过初代的TLOU
Now, if you played the original TLOU,
你就知道感染者不是葡萄酒越陈越香
you know that zombies don't tend to age like a fine wine.
实际上在TLOU的世界里感染越久的感染者就越可怕
The more serious and severe zombies in the world of TLOU come with age.
也就是说你接下来即将在地下室看到的感染者
This means that all of the zombies and infected that you're going to see in the basement
很可能已经被关在那里25年了
have likely been there for a quarter century.
里面很可能隐藏着整个这座城市最最危险的感染者
That makes them some of the most dangerous and severe infected in this entire city.
其他人我不清楚 但在我想通这一点的一瞬间
Now I don't know about you guys, but the second that I figured this out,
我就知道我们可能即将面对全新的感染者 或者至少是新boss
I knew that we are probably going to end up finding
a new type of infected or at the very least a new boss.
我他妈可老期待了
And I was damn ready for that.
TLOU2里的感染者一般比较后知后觉
The infected in TLOU2 seemed to be a bit of an afterthought.
游戏对它们的关注不是很多 我也理解 游戏里要做的事情太多了
There's not a whole lot of focus on them, and I get it, there's a lot more going on.
但我还是有点怀念一代游戏里感染者的重要地位
But I kind of miss how central the zombies were in the original game.
所以一想到自己马上要面对全新的感染者
So the idea of having a brand new type of infected introduce that we have to go up against
我就感觉非常有趣 摩拳擦掌
was pretty interesting and I was damn ready for it.
于是诺拉带埃比来到了医院地下室
And so Nora leads Abby to the basement
让她自己去搜寻治疗雅拉胳膊的医疗用品
to let her collect everything that she's going to need for Yara's arm.
就在这个时间点 前脚她送埃比去了地下室
And it's at this point that she leaves Abby to it,
大家当然都清楚 后脚她就上楼遇到艾莉了
and of course, as we know, she heads back upstairs to be confronted by Ellie.
埃比此时进入的这个关卡区域 顽皮狗起名为“原爆点”
Now it's at this point that Abby enters with Naughty Dog labeled this level as which is Ground Zero.
事实上 她进入地下室后看到的一切东西
She heads into the basement where all of these, in fact,
都是从虫草菌疫情爆发后保留到现在的
that have just been sitting since the initial outbreak.
甚至埃比也知道 这里可能会发生非常可怕的事情
And even Abby knows that there's probably going to be something pretty serious in here.
而这一点在她听到一些奇怪的声响后就立刻得到了验证
And it's only verified and reaffirmed
by the fact that she starts seeing and hearing strange things almost immediately.
埃比继续在整个区域里探索 寻找想要的物资
Now Abby pushes on and explores the area, trying to find the stuff that she needs,
最终她启动了发电机 打开了一些锁上的大门
and eventually she reconnects the power and pushes through some locked doors,
结果却发现……
only to find…
谁干的？
没错 走廊的门都被撑开了
Yeah, the door has been ripped open.
埃比心里明白这里有个超级巨大的东西
There's something really big here, and Abby knows it.
然而她哪也去不了
However, there is nowhere else to go.
所以埃比只能在地下室里到处找 最后在一辆救护车上找到了需要的物资
So Abby pushes through the tunnel and eventually finds the tools that she needs in an ambulance.
但是当然了 恐惧来得也恰是时候
But of course, because timing is perfect in every horror situation,
这一坨感染者出现了
this guy comes along.
埃比：来吧！
快打开，你这个破玩意！
没错 这个超级吓人的感染者的出现带领玩家进入到了下一场Boss战
Yeah, this horrific monstrosity comes out and poses the next boss fight to the player.
它长得就跟一群感染者循声者紧急集合一样
It's a coagulation of multiple infected and Clickers,
可老磕碜了
and it's pretty disgusting looking,
怎么想都感觉这设计太让人印象深刻了
and I actually think that it's pretty impressive all things considered.
我真没料到会是这样的怪物
Something I did not see coming to be honest.
然而很遗憾的说 这只长相恶心的怪物并没有那么难
However, I'm sorry to report that this disgusting creature
is not actually that difficult all things considered.
它移动速度慢 如果不是绝地难度的话 对抗它的难度并不大
He moved so slowly that he can't be considered a major difficulty
unless you're on, for instance, grounded.
它的速度慢到我甚至没把它当成一个威胁
He moves so slowly that I wouldn't even really consider him much of a threat.
当然 这玩意子弹打进去好像不痛不痒
He is a bullet sponge to be completely honest,
但如果你弹药充足 就可以在建筑里和它绕
but if you have enough ammo, you're just going to run around the building,
伤害全都灌出去
eventually hurling things item,
尤其是这一层还散落很多动态生成的制造材料
especially since they have dynamically generated crafting materials scattered throughout this floor.
所以你随时都可以捡东西 跑到角落 制造物品
This means that you can always collect items, run to a corner, craft,
跑到另一个地方 装备好
run to another corner, equip it,
然后在需要的时候给它扔个爆破管或者燃烧瓶
and then throw pipe bombs and molotovs item if you need to.
而且我认为往大了说
And I think more broadly,
整个游戏的难度其实更偏向于敌人的数量
difficulty in this game tends to come from the quantity of enemies.
所以……我操你……
And ah…  Motherfu…
好吧 可太恶心了
Yeah, it's real nasty.
所以你把身上所有家伙事都喂给了这俩怪物 直到把它们都解决掉
So you unload absolutely everything that you have into these two until they are eventually killed.
接着埃比带着所有要找的东西 从地下室回到了底面
And so Abby heads back up to the surface with all of the gear that she came for,
重新和勒弗汇合 一起回到了水族馆
she reconnects with Lev, and they head back to the aquarium.
梅尔用这些新拿的医疗物资成功给雅拉的胳膊做了截肢手术
It's with these new-found tools that Mel is able to successfully amputate Yara's arm,
而她也挺过来了
and she does survive it.
看起来埃比的新家庭要过上幸福美满的生活了
It seems as though Abby's new family is going to be okay after all.
可拉倒吧！ 这游戏里的故事可不是这么讲的
Except totally not! That's not how anything in this game works.
玩家心里应该早就清楚了
You should have known that by now.
但是在「西雅图 第2天」结束后 画面给到了埃比又一个梦境的闪回
But of course, to finish out Seattle Day 2 there's another flashback slashed dream
埃比又一次来到她父亲遇害的医院
where Abby is in the hospital where her father died
进入发现她父亲尸体的那个房间
heads into the room where her father was found dead,
而这次 她看到他还活着 满脸笑容
except this time she sees him alive, and smiling,
我认为这里游戏在传达非常非常重要的一点
which to me actually represent something very significant.
一个大家都不能低估的点
Something that I do not think you can understate.
真的 我认为这个很快的闪回片段 这片梦境的内容
Seriously I think this one little flashback slash, flash sideways, slashed dream.
是整个埃比章节里最最重要的时刻
I think this is probably the most important moment of Abby's entire character.
整个埃比章节的核心 一言以蔽之 就是这个片段了 请听我细说
If you listen to anything in Abby sections, it's this, allow me to make my point.
在我看来 这一刻似乎代表了艾比
This moment to me seems to represent Abby,
终于为自己的罪孽和乔尔的死亡做了赎罪
having finally made atonement for her sins and the death of Joel,
同时她也终于能平静地面对父亲的死了
while at the same time coming to complete peace with her father's death.
我的意思是说 至少她现在能睡个安稳觉了
I mean, at the very least, she doesn't seem to be struggling with sleep any more,
因为她不会再做噩梦了
because she's not having nightmares.
她梦见了她再一次和父亲产生了思想上的连接 这是一个好梦
She's actually having a good dream where she reconnects with her father.
如果这都不算好梦 那天底下就全都是噩梦了
That's not a good dream, I don't know what is.
此外 上次埃比的梦境中 她冲进房间 看到的是她父亲的死
Furthermore, the last time we saw Abby, rushing into the room, where her father was found dead,
她还看到了雅拉和勒弗被吊起来开肠破肚
she witnessed Yara and Lev strung up and disemboweled.
正如我们在那场梦境中所说的那样
As we established back when that scene took place,
游戏在暗示我们
it seemed as though that was implying that
雅拉和勒弗开始对埃比的心理产生了重大影响
Yara and Lev were starting to have a significant impact on her psyche.
而当前就是弱化后的版本
And that's the tone down version.
我想说的是 他们似乎开始在她的思想和生活中占据了以前她父亲的位置
I would argue that they seem to be starting to take a place in her mind and life
that was previously occupied by her father.
这是一个家庭的位置 只保留给那些你真正关心的人
It's a familial place that only is reserved for those that you truly care about.
无论这是否有意义 无论这是否合理
And whether it makes sense, whether it's justified or not,
埃比的确是感受到了与雅拉和勒弗的强烈联系
Abby does feel that intense connection to Yara and Lev.
可能是因为他们在本不必要的时候救了埃比一命
Maybe it's just because they saved her life when they didn't need to.
也许是因为还发生了别的事情 让彼此有了兴趣
Or maybe it's because there is something more going on,
an actual interest and appreciation of each other.
但总之 他们走到这步了
But regardless it's there.
埃比在这个场景中看到她父亲 满脸和蔼地看着她
Abby, seeing her father in this setting, looking at her with a caring face,
满脸写着一些都会好起来的
a face that says everything's going to be okay,
我觉得这里的意义太重大了
I think is incredibly significant.
她刚刚救了雅拉
She just saved Yara,
同时也间接地拯救了勒弗
and in turn, seems to have saved Lev at the same time,
一切的心结都解开了
everything seems to have worked out.
据他们所知 明天他们要一起登上欧文的船
And as far as they know, the next day they're going to be able to load up in Owen's boat
前往圣塔芭芭拉
and head off to Santa Barbara.
看起来真的要有一个美满的结局了
It really does seem as though we're going to have a happy ending.
这样 「西雅图 第2天」结束了
And with that, Seattle Day 2, ends.
西雅图 第3天
「西雅图 第3天」 剧情从埃比睡觉醒来开始
Seattle Day 3, Abby wakes up to drama brewing.
她睡得挺好 但梅尔生气了
She slept well, but Mel is pissed.
她基本上只是想让埃比离开她的欧文和那些新来的孩子
And basically she just wants Abby to leave her Owen and the new kids alone.
梅尔还说如果埃比继续这样坚持下去 迟早会搞砸一切
She says that if Abby sticks along for any longer than she's going to screw everything up.
所以埃比还不如让其他人去圣塔芭芭拉 自己继续留在WLF这里
So she might as well leave them to go to Santa Barbara by themselves and remain here with the WLF.
我认为考虑到埃比刚刚和梅尔的孩子父亲搞过 这样的戏剧性变化还算合理
I mean the drama kind of makes sense, considering that Abby just slept with Mel's baby daddy.
我不知道梅尔是否知道这些 或者她是否知道并谈论过这些
And I don't know if she knows this, or if she know and talked about it.
但无论如何 这让埃比非常伤心 她都哭了
But either way, it upsets Abby pretty significantly, and Abby actually starts to cry,
这是我们第一次看到这个外表如此坚强的人流泪
one of the first times we see a crack in this facade that she puts forward,
我觉得埃比的确受到打击了
and I think this hits hard for Abby,
因为她可能也感觉梅尔说的某种程度上是有道理的
because she probably knows that it's true, at least to some extent.
我跟你们说 埃比这人就有毒
I mean she is kind of toxic,
拽着一伙自己最好的朋友 横穿半个国家 只为杀一个人
she literally dragged a group of her closest friends halfway across the country,
just to murder a dude.
同时雅拉还在处理勒弗的事情 勒弗天真的以为
Meanwhile, Yara is dealing with Lev, who's come to the naive conclusion
自己能说服母亲放弃邪教加入他们
that he can convince their mother to join them in abandoning the cult.
雅拉显然知道这种对他们母亲的看法简直又天真又愚蠢
Yara, of course, realizes that this is a naive and stupid estimation
of what they could do with their mother.
但勒弗还是认为总有办法能做到
But nonetheless Lev is convinced that there is a way.
所以埃比和雅拉决定去找个小礼物安慰一下勒弗 让他心情好了以后能留下
So Abby and Yara look for a gift that they can give to Lev, to make him feel better and stay.
现在 有一个不得不提的问题渐渐显现出来了
Now it's during this chapter that the elephant in the room comes out,
我决定可能很多玩家都发现了这点
and it's something that I'm sure many of us saw coming,
尤其如果你注意到了过去几小时游戏中的对话
especially if you've been listening to the passive dialogue for the last few hours of gameplay.
即勒弗是一位跨性别者
You see, Lev is trans.
在之前你和勒弗一同进行的一些战斗场景中
In some of the previous combat sequences when you're moving with Lev through,
比如之前在建筑工地大楼里对抗大量赛拉菲特帮那段
for instance, the construction site in fighting a lot of Seraphites,
赛拉菲特帮偶尔会管勒弗叫莉莉
there's times when the Seraphites will actually call out to Lev, referring to him as Lily.
现在 如果你在游戏的大部分时间都有注意过这些
Now if you've been kind of mentally checked out for the majority of the game,
那你可能对此感觉或震惊或疑惑
this might come as a total shock, or it might just be confusing
为什么他们会管这个角色叫莉莉而不是叫勒弗
as to why they're referring to this character as Lily and not Lev.
而也正是这个原因才导致雅拉和勒弗背离了他们的宗教组织
But it's for that very reason that Yara and Lev left the group.
勒弗本来会成为一位长老的妻子
Lev was to be married off to one of the elders.
勒弗自然不喜欢这个决定、不同意
Naturally, Lev did not agree with this or like the idea,
所以最后他剃光了头发
and so started acting out eventually, cutting his hair,
并希望别人以男性赛拉菲特教徒来看待他
and fully transitioning, wanting to be referred to entreated as a male Seraphite,
出去巡逻、接受训练、成为一名战士
going out on patrols being trained and used as a soldier.
而相信大家都能预料到
And in what comes as absolutely no surprise to anybody,
赛拉菲特帮肯定对这样的转变极其不满
the Seraphites weren't exactly the most supportive of this transition.
所以他们决定要严厉惩罚勒弗
So they decided that they were going to severely punish Lev,
或者至少他们不会允许这样另类的生活方式的存在
or at the very least, we're not going to allow this alternative lifestyle, shall we say.
所以雅拉这位坚定支持他的姐姐决定和勒弗一起出逃
And so Yara being a supportive and strong sister decided to come out with Lev and help them escape.
因此 赛拉菲特人不停称这两个人是“叛徒”
This is, of course, why they're constantly referred to as apostate by the Seraphites,
同时也解释了为什么在很多和赛拉菲特帮的战斗中
and why so many of the Seraphites in combat sequences
对面会不停问雅拉和勒弗为什么要做这样的事
will call out and ask Yara and Lev why they're doing what they're doing.
因为不久前他们俩明明还“好好的”
Because as far as they knew up until very recently, they were just fine.
现在关于这个情节上出现了很多争论
Now there's been a lot of hubbub about this plot point.
四面八方的玩家对这个话题是否处理得当都有很激烈的讨论
There has been a lot of debate,
both left and right of center as to whether or not this was handled well.
而说实话
And to be honest,
我觉得自己并没有资格在这一点上做出判断
I'm not really qualified to come to a determination on that point.
但对我来说 似乎处理得相对不错
But to me it seemed to be handled relatively well.
尽管在水族馆的这个特定场景中
Though in this particular scene in the aquarium
雅拉和埃比谈论到这件事时
when Yara and Abby are talking about it,
气氛看起来有点沉重
it does seem a little heavy handed.
我第一次明白这件事是在几小时之前
When I first figured it out for sure was a few hours before this,
两人在电梯井里的时候 勒弗亲自问过埃比
when Lev and Abby were exploring the tower together and Lev actually asks Abby,
是否听到过其他赛拉菲特人怎么称呼他
whether or not she heard what the other Seraphites were calling him.
这显然就是在指赛拉菲特帮管他叫“莉莉”“叛徒”这个事情
This, of course, was referencing the fact
that the Seraphites constantly referred to Lev as Lily, or as the apostate.
埃比说自己好像听说过 但她觉得这个话题不需要讨论
Abby said she was aware of this, but that she didn't need to talk about it.
我认为这是一种相当谨慎的处理方式
That I thought was a pretty discreet way of handling something
勒弗可能并不太愿意谈论这个问题
that Lev probably isn't too excited to talk about,
而且坦率地讲 这对他们的最终目标并不那么重要
and that frankly, isn't that important to what their end goal is.
这也是为什么我一直很喜欢顽皮狗之前的作品
And this is one of the things that I've liked about Naughty Dog's work in the past
他们的故事中会有很多各种各样的角色
when they have more diverse cast members or characters within their stories,
而这方面的内容通常并不是评判这个角色的点
it's usually not the defining point of that character.
如果一代TLOU里有一个同性恋角色
If there's a gay character in the original TLOU,
那么这个角色就在那里 你要是注意到了就注意到了
it's there for you to see and you can put it together if you're paying any attention whatsoever.
而这并不会成为那个角色决定性的标签
But it's not the defining point of that character.
当一个人完全被自己的一些特征所评判的时候
When somebody is purely defined by one trait of themselves,
无论是性认同、信仰或是外表
whether that something like sexual identity or their religion or their appearance,
都是不好的 因为人远比这些表面的东西复杂
it's always a bad thing because people are far more complicated than that,
你也不应该把你自己单纯归结为某一个特征
and you shouldn't boil yourself down to just one trait.
因为你远比这一点有内涵得多
You're far more interesting than that.
这就是为什么一般来说 我觉得顽皮狗处理这类事情的方法是不错的
This is why generally, I feel that Naughty Dog's approach to these types of things is good
因为他们没有以此来评判某个角色
because they don't make it the defining characteristic.
然而在TLOU2和他们之前的作品《神秘海域：失落的遗产》中
However, in this most recent gained TLOU2 and in their previous title, Uncharted: The Lost Legacy,
顽皮狗开始陷入角色特征的怪圈里了
they fall prey much more to these heavy handed traits
他们开始让一个角色纯粹以外部特征来定义自己
where they make a character define themselves purely by an external trait.
虽然我对这个特点本身没有意见
And while I have no problem with whatever that trait may be by itself,
但我认为仅仅通过一个特征来定义你正在制作的角色并将其放入故事中
I think that defining a character that you are crafting
and putting it into a story by just that one trait
是在创作上偷懒
is lazy writing.
并且我认为这对那些在现实中有相同特征的人来说是一种不尊重
And I think it does a disservice to the people who actually share that trait in reality.
尽管如此 我仍认为这个问题处理得相对不错 如果不是写得太沉重就更好了
But nonetheless, I think it's handled relatively well, if not a little heavy handed.
这也不是在爆料什么关键性的秘密
But it doesn't seem to be that crucial of a reveal,
而且据我所知 多数人根本不在乎这件事
and as far as I can tell, most people don't particularly care.
我也难免会认为
I also can't help recognized
顽皮狗把这样的“爆料”放在游戏的后期进行
that Naughty Dog saved this reveal quote-unquote for much later in the game.
很可能是考虑到如果玩家已经玩到这里 那很可能会更加理解这个事情
Chances are, if you've made it this far, you're going to be much more understanding
相反如果过早地就敞开了说这个话题
whereas if they put this reveal much earlier on in the game,
那它很容易会变成舆论的焦点了
it would be troll fodder without a doubt.
可能是明智的考虑 也可能单纯是怂
Maybe that's smart, maybe it's cowardly,
也可能在游戏后期说这个只是因为巧合
maybe it's just a coincidence that its revealed later in the game.
我也不清楚 我也不在乎
I'm not sure, either way, I don't particularly care,
我觉得这也不重要
and I don't think it matters.
在他们给勒弗选好礼物后
Well, after they find a nice gift for Lev,
他们来到水族馆外面 结果却看到勒弗自己开船跑了
they eventually push out to the edge of the aquarium and realized that Lev's taken a boat
他直奔赛拉菲特的大本营所在的小岛
and is headed straight for the island that the Scars are based out of.
勒弗想去救他的妈妈
Lev's going to try to save his mom,
但这真是……真的蠢死了
But it really is…  it's just stupid to do this.
这一刻我真的感觉有点迷惑
This was one moment where I was a little confused,
因为勒弗看着也挺成熟的 也不傻啊
just because Lev doesn't seem like a naive or stupid person.
是 他是年轻 但这跟年纪没啥直接关系
Yeah, Lev's young, but that isn't necessarily directly correlative.
你完全可以有与你年纪不相仿的智慧
You can be young and wise beyond your years.
比如一代里的艾莉 一样很年轻
Look at Ellie, for instance, in the first game she was young,
但从来不会干这么幼稚的事情
but she was not naive whatsoever.
我觉得换作是艾莉 她就不会这么冲动
I do not think that Ellie would have made this same rash decision.
至少会花一点时间好好想想解决办法
At the very least, you would have taken some time to plan out some way
来处理这个可能永远离开她母亲的潜在问题
of dealing with this potential problem of leaving her mother forever potentially.
然而因为顽皮狗需要一个理由来向玩家展示赛拉菲特岛
However, because Naughty Dog needs a reason to show the player that Seraphites' island
和WLF对这座岛即将发动的突袭
and this huge raid that the WLF are going to be carrying out on the island.
他们只好把这些事件草草拼凑起来说“你看 勒弗奔那个岛去了”
They just put this together and say, "well, we'll have Lev race to the island".
然后玩家就会跟着勒弗 到那里看到所有疯狂的东西
And then you follow Lev and you'll get to see all of this crazy stuff.
我觉得这又有点强凑巧合
I think that this one is again a little bit of a coincidence and
似乎编剧有点想把人物强行塞进一个没有预先设定好上下文的环境中去
seems to reek a little bit of the writer's trying to force characters into a situation
that hasn't naturally percolated through the circumstances of what's going on.
这就是为什么这里的时机是如此重要
And that's why this timing here is so important.
因为埃比的团队要尽量在风暴来临之前离开西雅图
It's because Abby's group is going to try to leave Seattle before the storm picks up.
而那场风暴将用来掩护伊萨克向塞拉特特岛的最后突袭
That storm is going to be used as cover for Isaac's final push on to the Seraphites' Island,
而伊萨克无论如何都不会放弃这次突袭的机会
and Isaac is not going to be delaying this push whatsoever at all.
就像在游戏早期说的 他已经受够了打打杀杀
He's done with fighting as he told us earlier in the game.
这就是为什么他把所有装备都投入了前线
That's why all of this gear has been moved to the front base.
因为他们要破釜沉舟 和疤脸帮决一死战
It's because they're going to have one last, wipe-out fight
to finish the Scars for good and be done with them.
而与此同时 埃比可以利用这场风暴作为掩护 逃到圣塔芭芭拉
And at the same time, Abby can use this storm as cover to make her escape to Santa Barbara.
然而这个问题好像没那么重要
However, this is much more of a lesser point.
因为实际上 埃比、欧文、梅尔、雅拉和勒弗
Because realistically, Abby and Owen, Mel, Yara and Lev
并不需要那么多的掩护就能逃走
don't really need that much cover to escape.
船在他们手里 开走就完事了
If they have a boat, they can just leave.
就我对游戏中WLF的了解 他们并不会主动在水面上巡逻
The WLF as far as I've seen in this game, don't actively patrolled the water.
他们的确有船
They do have boats that they use,
几分钟后就能看到埃比和雅拉去码头弄船
which is after all, where Abby and Yara are going to grab a boat here in just a minute,
但WLF并不会主动去海上巡逻
but they don't seem to patrol it actively.
我也不清楚 如果他们真的会在水域上巡逻
I don't know, if they do patrol it actively,
那这些人可能的确需要风暴的掩护才能出逃
and that's why all of these people need the storm to cover their tracks.
那就有意思了 但我并没有看到游戏在哪里明显提到过这一点
That would be interesting, but I'm not aware of any time when that's directly referenced.
如果大家有看到 欢迎在评论区指出
If you know, please let me know in the comments section below.
所以埃比和雅拉自然就决定要去把勒弗追回来
And so Abby and Yara naturally decide that they need to go and get Lev,
因为勒弗上岛以后
because if Lev steps foot on the island,
一旦被其他赛拉菲特帮的人看到 就很可能会被立刻杀掉
chances are he will be killed within the first twenty seconds
of being witnessed by any of the other Seraphites.
所以埃比和雅拉两人一起前往船坞
And so Abby in Yara start to push for the marina.
她们最后听到了狙击枪响 埃比让雅拉留在下面
They eventually hear some sniper shots and Yara determines that she needs to stay behind.
毕竟她这时候只剩一条胳膊了
She, after all, only has one arm at this time,
所以让她在船坞里到处乱跑实在是有点为难人
so it's a little harder for her to navigate these complex passageways
of latter stairs and rafters that she has to jump across.
玩家最后来到一处开阔地带
You eventually cross into a wide open inner state
然后突然有个人冲出来把你扑倒……竟然是曼尼
and are instantly tackled right as you pop out by… who else but Manny.
狙击手就在对面
This is where the sniper is.
他一直瞄着你 而且已经解决掉好多曼尼的手下
He's got to pin down and has apparently killed all of Manny's guys.
所以埃比和曼尼一起向前推进 想要干掉这个狙击手
And so Abby and Manny worked together to push up and take out this sniper.
这段游戏内容其实很爽 细节拉满
It's actually pretty crazy sequence, it's very detailed too.
大家可以看看埃比在这块掩体后匍匐前行时狙击手射击的细节
I mean just look at how the snipers shooting at Abby here as she advances through this ditch,
打到上面尸体的脑袋甚至还会崩出脑浆
even shoots the body that's laying right on it and part of the body's head blows off,
让这段内容非常扣人心弦
which made all of this way more intense for me.
我不知道这个画面是每次都会发生
I don't know if this happens every time for everybody,
还是我视频中这段是巧合打到那个尸体的脑袋了
or if it was just a coincidental thing that the bullet happened to land right here.
但无论如何
But either way,
这个画面让我很震撼 临场感非常强
this spooked me and made me feel as though I was right in the thick of it.
现在快速回顾一下 大家还记得几小时前杰西和艾莉分开
这段在本视频1:57:50左右
Now quick sidebar, remember why Jesse and Ellie separated just a few hours ago
因为他们听说码头那边有狙击手
was because they heard that there was a sniper at the marina,
然后他们认为那个人一定是汤米吗？
and they assumed that this sniper had to be Tommy.
所以杰西和艾莉分开了
So Jesse and Ellie separated.
所以杰西可以去找汤米 艾莉可以去水族馆
So Jesse could go and find Tommie and Ellie could leave and go to the aquarium.
另外 大家还记得之前艾莉闪回中的狙击课程吗？
这段在本视频1:30:10左右
Also remember the previous sniping section that we had with Ellie in the flashback.
我当时说这并不是单纯的狙击课程
Remember, I said that that wasn't just a one off sniping tutorial,
即使狙击枪在游戏其他部分再也不会用到
even though it wasn't really going to be used at any other point in the game?
你看 就是为了这里而铺垫的
Well, it was for this very reason.
游戏要给玩家建立一种 汤米是个神枪手的概念
They needed to establish that Tommy has sniping experience and is good at what he does.
不然你以为这个神枪手能是谁？
And sure enough, who do you think this sniper is?
无论玩家在这个特定的时刻是否意识到这一点
Whether or not the player realizes this in this particular moment,
我认为并不太重要 因为无论如何你都要继续向前推进
I don't think is too important because either way you the way you push up.
但我觉得如果你没意识到这个人是汤米的话剧情反而可能会更酷
But I think it's actually probably a cooler moment,
if you don't realize it's Tommy handling the sniper rifle.
当你以为这个狙击手只是一个普通NPC的时候
When you're thinking of it purely as an NPC sniping at you,
你去追击、朝他射击、尝试解决他的时候可能内心感受会更轻松一点
you have a much easier time just plowing through chasing him,
shooting at him, trying to kill him.
而当你意识到这个人可能是你有点喜欢的角色
But once you realize it's a character that you also know and kind of love,
但他却在主动威胁另一个你开始喜欢、关心的角色的生命的时候
but is actively threatening the life of another character that you're starting to enjoy and care about,
才造就了这样有趣的戏剧冲突 造就了TLOU2这样奇怪诡异的故事
it's that interesting conflict that makes TLOU2 such a strange and bizarre story.
埃比和曼尼把狙击手逼到了角落
Abby and Manny push up and eventually get the sniper cornered.
然而当他们以为自己马上就要解决掉他的时候……
However, right as they reached the point,
when they feel as though they've got him, this happens…
埃比：曼尼。
曼尼：好。
去他的，直接——
就这样 曼尼死了
Just like that, Manny is dead.
埃比吓疯了
And now Abby is mad.
这里给我的感觉就像杰西突然领盒饭一样
This is in my mind, just like the sudden death of Jesse.
一切是如此突然 毫无预兆
It comes out of nowhere and is a total shock.
这样的类比再一次出现了
Again, similes all over the place.
艾莉毫无预兆地突然就失去了一位亲密的朋友
Ellie lost a close friend out of nowhere very suddenly,
玩家也要应付这样突如其来的打击
and the player has to also deal with it suddenly and shockingly.
现在埃比也失去了她的好朋友 也要面对完全相同的境地
And now Abby is losing a close friend of hers and is forced to deal with it in the same way.
于是你稍微绕了一下
So you start around a little bit.
然后埃比穿过了这扇门……
And Abby pushes through the door.
雅拉：你没事吧？
埃比？
埃比：没事。
你呢？
雅拉：没事。
他是谁？
埃比：可恶。
无所谓了。
我们去找勒弗，然后回水族馆。
走。我们去坐那艘船。
如果你注意到她的就表情就能明白 埃比知道那个人是谁
If you just look on her face, you know, Abby knows who this was.
她知道汤米来了 而这非常非常糟糕
She knows that Tommy is here and that that is very bad.
有多糟糕？刚刚你和曼尼在上面公路上的时候他说过
This is especially bad because Manny just said a few moments ago
when you were in the interstate,
有不止一个闯入者在乱杀WLF的成员
that there's more than one trespassers in town, killing WLF members.
曼尼：该死的入侵者！
埃比：什么入侵者？
曼尼：几天前他们不知道从哪儿冒出来。
彻底痛宰了我们！
这意味这就算她能秒了汤米 当然这显然不可能
This means that even if she killed Tommy just now, which is a stretch,
外面还有很多人在屠杀WLF的成员
there's a lot more people that are in town, killing WLF members.
而汤米在这 很可能说明杰克逊小镇的一帮人
And if Tommy's here, chances are it's other people from Jackson
来找她为乔尔复仇了
coming to get revenge for what she did to Joel.
但埃比现在没那么多功夫为这件事感到害怕了
Regardless, Abby doesn't really have the time to freak out about this.
她把这个问题放在一边 坐上她们从码头弄来的船前往岛上
She puts it out of her mind and heads to the island in a boat which they take from the pier,
显然 WLF成员偶尔也会使用这些船
the same boat and peer that the WLF members use, apparently, occasionally.
她的目标很简单 需要找到勒弗然后离开
Her goal is simple, she needs to find Lev and get out.
如果能速战速决 应该可以避开艾莉和她的整个复仇团队
If she can do that quickly, shall avoid Ellie and her entire revenge crew completely.
埃比和雅拉来到了疤脸帮的岛屿
Abby and Yara reach the Scars' island.
雅拉带路 把埃比领进了她的营地的核心区域
Yara takes the lead, and brings Abby into the heart of one of their major camps.
这里一个有趣的事情是 雅拉和勒弗仍然保有对邪教的信仰
And the most interesting thing about this actually is that Yara and Lev still buy into the cult,
即使他们已和组织里的领导者站在对立面
even though they've rejected the leadership.
雅拉：愿她的光芒指引我们穿越风暴。
埃比：“当你迷失在黑暗中时……就寻找光明。”
雅拉：什么意思？
埃比：我爸爸以前常说的话。
说实话我真不太理解这个地方
And to be honest, I don't really know what to make of this.
我听过这类故事 邪教的人出来后仍然对其半信半疑
I've heard stories of people that were involved in cults that get out and still partially believe it,
尽管他们认为宗教内部已经有些腐败
even though they feel as though it was corrupted somewhat.
但他们好像还是会相信这些
They feel as though they're still truth to it.
我不太确定 但我觉得还是挺有意思的
I am not totally sure, but I thought it was interesting
因为毕竟这些孩子们出生就在这样的邪教团体里
because after all, these kids were raised in this cult from the time that they were born.
所以他们因为死亡的威胁而离开这里
So it makes sense that just because they decided to leave under threat of death,
但仍然对邪教的精神偶像有所崇拜 或至少是尊重 还是说得通的
they still have some adoration, or at least respect for the cult leaders.
总之 她们一进入岛屿腹地
But nonetheless, once in the belly of the island
埃比和雅拉就看到了赛拉菲特人涌入军械库
Abby and Yara witnessed the Seraphites heading into their armories
准备应对WLF开始对他们进行的突袭
to prepare for the incoming WLF attack, which is beginning.
他们看到WLF的成员正在登陆岛屿 打了一个措手不及
They see WLF members heading into the island and are taken by complete surprise by this.
说实话 我对赛拉菲特帮没有预料到此事感觉有一点惊讶
Honestly it's little surprising to me that the Seraphites didn't see this coming in at least a little bit.
他们在城里有如此宏伟的基建
They have a huge infrastructure throughout the city,
就像之前看到的 几座大楼屋顶之间有通行的“桥梁” 他们自己也都很机敏
as we've seen with bridges that co from rooftop to rooftop and they're very sneaky,
所以似乎应该能够意识到
So it seems as though they should have been able to realize
WLF正在动员某种突袭行动
that the WLF was mobilizing for some sort of offensive.
毕竟他们刚把全部物资全部兵力都集中到了中心区域
After all, they were bringing all of their supplies in all of their soldiers into one central area.
如果这都没让赛拉菲特的首领警觉的话 那他是干什么吃的
If that doesn't spook you as the leader of the Seraphites, I don't know what will.
但总之 他们现在开始准备防守了
But regardless, they're preparing for the offensive.
这为你在这座岛屿上探索留出了空间 也让你能推进到勒弗和雅拉的房子
This gives you a little bit of space to explore the island and push through to Abby and Yara's house.
在这个过程中你会发现很多有赛拉菲特帮的区域 以潜行通过为主
While you're doing this, you find through multiple arenas of Seraphites, all fairly stealth oriented.
算是让你在去他们家的路上不那么无聊 不用单纯坐着看播片了
But nonetheless it gives you something to do
to shake up the monotony of just walking through sequences in watching small cut scenes.
终于你们来到了房子前 开门进去后 看到了这样的场景
Eventually you come upon the house, and the following scene plays out.
雅拉：勒弗？
妈妈……
哦，谢天谢地。
这是她干的？
勒弗：我只是想跟她谈谈。
我想让她理解我，可是……
她不停大叫。
然后她开始追我。
我想让她停下来。
我只是想把她推开……
雅拉：嘿、嘿、嘿
勒弗：然后她撞到了桌子。
雅拉：听着。
勒弗：雅拉……
雅拉：你是在自卫。
你没有做错。
不会有事的，我保证。
勒弗：我想离开。
雅拉：嗯，我也是。
走吧
埃比：嗨，小家伙。
雅拉：走吧。
这段真没什么好震惊的 他妈肯定永远不会理解的
And this doesn't really surprise anyone, she was never going to understand.
但同样重要的是 勒弗现在已经无所挂念了
But it's also important to note that this severs all ties for Lev,
这点提醒了我 即游戏希望他们离开西雅图的时候能完全不带任何包袱
which signal to me that they were actually being set up to leave Seattle completely
without leaving any baggage behind.
每当一个游戏或故事开始切断一个角色的家庭和友好关系时
Whenever a game or a story starts to sever familial and friendly ties to a character
通常意味着他们正准备进行某种大的过渡
usually it means that they are preparing to make some sort of big transition
这样他们就不会留下包袱 也不用费劲去解释这个包袱了
so that they aren't left with the baggage or having to explain that baggage way.
然而我个人认为这样有点多此一举
I, however, don't think that this was particularly necessary.
我认为把勒弗和雅拉的母亲留在这里没什么问题
I think leaving Lev and Yara's mom behind really wouldn't have been that big of deal.
毕竟她已经深陷一个想要杀死他们两人的邪教组织
After all, she's a member of a cult, a cult that wants to kill them.
总之 埃比、雅拉和勒弗一起向码头推进
Regardless, Abby, Yara and Lev pushed together to the docks
他们要在码头找船 再开回水族馆
where they want to find a boat and take that boat back to the aquarium.
我到现在都没整明白为什么他们不去找来岛时的那条船
I was never super clear on why
these characters couldn't just return to the boat that they had just taken to shore.
无论如何他们都要去码头再另找一条船逃回去
But nonetheless, they want you to push to the docks,
grab a separate different boat and escape using that one.
我不知道是来岛的时候船坏了
I'm not sure if there was damage to the boat when you reached the island
还是什么原因导致他们不能用从WLF那弄来的船
or why they can't use the boat they just took from the peer from the WLF.
总之就是不能用
But nonetheless they can't for some reason.
我觉得这单纯就是想让角色去看看岛上镇子的核心区域
To me, it seems like more of an excuse
just to get these characters to push into the main center of town
从而看看WLF和赛拉菲特帮大战时一片混乱的场景
so that they can see a new set piece as the WLF and Seraphites' clash.
用意我能理解 但这前后逻辑还是没接上
I get it, it makes sense, but it just doesn't seem to logically follow
因为俩人刚把一条船开上岛
considering that they just took a boat to the island
比他们之后要去拿的船近多了
that's much closer than the boat they are trying to push to.
我不明白
I don't know.
如果他们有什么更好的理由不去取来时的那条船
If there's some really good excuse as to why they can't go back to that original boat,
请告诉我 谢谢
just let me know.
于是三人穿过一个完全被遗弃的镇子
So the three star pushing through an old town that's been completely abandoned,
看起来赛拉菲特帮完全没有在这里巡逻的意思
and it looks as though the Seraphites don't even actively patrol it
因为这些都是旧世界的糟粕
since it's from the old world.
一切都是那么安静 直到……
Everything's quiet, until…
雅拉：这边。
WLF士兵：抓到一个了！
埃比：雅拉！
WLF士兵：埃比？
勒弗：雅拉！
雅拉，起来——
WLF士兵：有枪声！来吧！
勒弗：雅拉，求你了。
埃比：勒弗，我们要走了。
勒弗：不。
埃比：快点！
勒弗：不行！
WLF士兵：我看见人了！
勒弗：我不能把她留在这里！
埃比：别过来！
WLF士兵：放下枪！快！
WLF士兵：该死。
WLF士兵：是埃比。
埃比：我说别过来！
伊萨克：退下！
埃比：伊萨克。
伊萨克：你到底在干嘛？
埃比：我需要你听我说完。
伊萨克：你身后是谁？
埃比：他救了我的命。
伊萨克：让开。
我们回去再找你算账。
埃比：他不是他们的人。拜托了。
伊萨克：埃比，走开——
埃比：该死的，他只是一个孩子！
伊萨克：你有三秒钟离开那个疤脸帮的人。
一。
埃比：你真的要朝我开枪吗？
伊萨克：二。
埃比：我他妈不会走。
WLF士兵：不！
WLF士兵：搞什么？
WLF士兵：打死她！
WLF士兵：阻止他们！
WLF士兵：别让他们跑了！
埃比：来吧。
勒弗，我们要走了。
勒弗：她死了。
天哪。她死了。
埃比：勒弗，快点！
勒弗：那些他妈的都是你的人！
埃比：嘿，我现在站在你这边！
听我说。
我们要战斗才能离开这里，懂吗？
我需要你带我们找到那些船。
任何人都不能阻止我们，明白吗？
勒弗：好。
埃比：好。
跟我来。
于是现在开始我们和勒弗搭档对抗我们曾经的队友——WLF成员
So now we're paired with Lev against the WLF members
we previously considered our friends.
但说实话 这段实在是游戏中情感上的一大困惑点
Be honest, it's a really emotionally confusing chunk of the game,
因为相当多的人都在争论埃比为什么要这样做
since there are so many people constantly yelling at Abby asking why she is doing this.
我们可能不认识WLF的这些人 但埃比认识啊
Now we may not know these characters, but Abby does.
她在戕害曾经和她一起工作过的 她所了解的
She's killing people that she worked with, that she knows,
并没有做错任何事情的人啊
who haven't really done anything wrong themselves,
而这一切只是为了勒弗 一个跟她没有任何关系的人
all for the sake of Lev, somebody that she's not even related to,
她根本没有任何理由要去关心他
and for whom she has really no reason to care.
这太离谱了 兄弟们 这是人干的事吗？
And that's pretty crazy, I mean, who would do that?
谁会为了某个不相干的人而杀死自己以前曾一起共事的人
Who would kill people that they've previously worked with
for somebody that are not related to
只是因为你俩建立了某种羁绊所以你关心他？
and just care because they've built a connection to them?
哦对
Oh.
于是埃比和勒弗看到了伊萨克他们干的好事
So Abby and Lev come upon a view of what Isaac's group has done.
WLF在对岛屿施行焦土政策
They're torturing the whole place, they're literally going scorched earth.
我们一边前往码头获取离岛的船
And so as we push to the marina to get the boat that we need to escape,
一边同时和几波疤脸帮与WLF士兵作战
we fight multiple waves of Scars and WLF members at the same time,
有时是是遇到两伙人正在掐架 我们只是想路过 结果也被卷进去了
sometimes coming across them, fighting each other when we interrupt just trying to pass through.
真的 感觉挺帅的
Really, it's kind of cool,
看这些敌人互相打架互相杀 自己在旁边看戏
to see all of these enemies interacting with each other and just wiping each other out.
太爽了
It's kind of crazy.
但这些场景里比较糟糕的一点是这里一只感染者都没有
Now the sequence has actually got a fair amount of crap because there's no infected here,
当然作为评测这样的话没什么意义
but that to me doesn't make any sense as an accusation or criticism.
因为这是一座赛拉菲特帮生活了很久的岛
This is an island, and it's an island that the Seraphites have lived on for a long time.
他们很可能早就清空了岛上的感染者 保持疫情常态化防控
They likely cleared out the infected on the island very early on and have kept it contained.
当然了 很多人认为这一个打僵尸的游戏
Sure, it's a little weird to play what many people thought was just going to be a zombie game
玩了几小时一个感染者都没看到感觉有点怪
and to not see zombies for hours and hours on end.
但我觉得还是合理的 至少在他们构建的这样一个世界里
But I think it makes sense, at least in the world that they've built.
TLOU比以往普通打僵尸游戏的世界观要复杂得多
TLOU is far more complicated than just a story about zombies.
把TLOU和那些普通的打僵尸游戏去对比实在有点让人不爽
It's really upsetting to hear boiled down to that basic and estimation.
最后 埃比和勒弗找到了一匹马
Now, eventually, Abby and Lev find a horse,
骑上它 直扎赛拉菲特帮的都城部分
hop on it and ride into the heart of the Seraphites' capital.
这里的视觉效果真的非常震撼 我真的要好好表扬一下
This really is a visually stunning sequence and I really can't complemented enough.
光影是如此酷炫
The lighting is ridiculously good.
这段场景可能是整个游戏里在视觉效果上给我留下印象最深的部分了
It's probably the most impressed I was visually across the entire game, just this one sequence.
埃比骑马沿着码头边缘前行
So Abby rides the horse all the way through to the edge of the docks.
杀了越来越多的WLF士兵和赛拉菲特帮
After killing more and more WLF members, more Seraphites,
爬上一座着火的房子
climbing through a burning house.
你终于来到了这章最后一个boss面前
You eventually find one last many boss in this chapter.
这次还是和海尔格那样的野蛮人
He's a Brute in the same style as Helga.
实际上游戏这里的模型网格变形系统非常厉害
And there's actually some pretty impressive mesh deformation systems at play here.
随着他身体出现割伤 他的人物模型的确会跟着有损伤变化
As he gets cut on his body, it actually becomes more and more mutilated.
皮肤会外翻
The skin flays open.
效果真的很震撼
It's pretty impressive.
遗憾的是这种特性不能以这样的真实度应用到整个游戏里的全部角色上
And it's unfortunate that this type of feature couldn't be applied to absolutely every character
at this fidelity level as you attack them throughout the course of the game.
我觉得TLOU2里的模型网格变形系统和断肢系统本来就够牛逼了
I will grant you the mesh deformation system and the gore system in TLOU2 was pretty incredible.
但如果人人都能到这个角色的程度 那就逆天了
But if it was on this level it would be another world.
希望能在下一代主机上能看到这样程度的模型质量
Hopefully we get to see this level of quality in the next generation of consoles.
我总感觉如果真能做到的话 那这游戏可老爽了
I have a feeling as though we're going to get it, and it's going to be pretty bad ass.
可能这个特性最好的应用就是你用镰刀把他的脸割开的时候
Probably the best example of this system working is when you use a scythe to gash his mouth open.
在我看来划出的伤口刚好在那个地方不可能只是巧合
Now it seems to me that this can't be just a coincidence that the gash occurs at this place,
毕竟“疤脸帮”的名字摆在那
considering that the Scars got their name "the Scars"
因为他们会刻意、心甘情愿地在脸上划出这样的疤痕
because they actively and willingly mutilate their mouths with this type of scar intentionally.
我现在把这当成了埃比和勒弗对赛拉菲特帮
Now I took this as a way for Abby and Lev to in essence repay the Seraphites
给勒弗和雅拉造成肉体和心灵上伤害的一种反击
for all of the physical and mental damage that they've applied upon Lev and Yara.
换句话说 用疤脸帮眼中神圣的行为
In other words, taking what the Scars, considered a sacred right,
去以牙还牙 血债血偿
and turning it into a way to strike back.
当然也可能是我自己过度解读了
Or maybe I'm just reading way too much into this.
总之 在打败这个野蛮人后 埃比和勒弗上了一条划艇
Regardless, after defeating this Brute, Abby and Lev grab a rowboat
两人从燃着熊熊烈火的岛屿返回了水族馆
and they head back to the aquarium with the island burning in the background.
我们不清楚这之后发生了什么 这场战斗结果如何
We don't really find out what happened after this or how this battle resolved itself,
但我觉得这不重要
but I don't really think it's important.
我们知道的是 伊萨克死了
But we do know is that Isaac is dead.
WLF群龙无首 溃不成军
And so the WLF began crumbling upon realizing that their leader was gone.
所以我觉得他们的突袭失败了 赛拉菲特守住了自己的领地
I would therefore assume that they lost the fight and the Seraphites held their ground.
但管他呢 不重要
But I don't think it matters.
回到水族馆 埃比看到了欧文、梅尔，和那条叫爱丽丝的狗的尸体
Back at the aquarium, Abby comes across the bodies of Owen, Mel and Alice, the dog.
她精神完全崩溃了 看起来编剧的任务也完成了
She's absolutely devastated, and it seems as though the writer's job has worked.
几小时的游戏之前 我们根本毫不关心的游戏角色
These characters that we didn't really care about just a few hours of gameplay ago,
被艾莉残忍杀害后
when Ellie came in and killed them,
现在在我们心中有了一席之地
now actually have a place in our hearts.
我们认识这些角色
We know these characters.
你可能不那么关心梅尔 不那么在意欧文
You don't care that much about Mel, you don't really care that much about Owen,
但你真的开始在乎埃比和勒弗
but you have started to care about Abby and Lev.
看着她悲痛欲绝的样子 我也难免感觉很伤心
Abby is devastated by this, and I couldn't help but feel bad.
而更惨的是在此时
And the crazy thing is that at this point,
埃比甚至不知道她的很多其他成员也都已经死了
She doesn't even really know that a lot of the other crew members are also dead.
据我所知 她应该还不知道诺拉已经被艾莉残忍杀害
She doesn't know, as far as I am aware, that Nora was brutally bashed by Ellie;
她不知道艾莉为了追杀埃比一路过来杀死的其他人
She doesn't know about all of the others that Ellie came across and killed on her way to find Abby.
而且说实话
And to be honest,
我甚至觉得埃比可能到最后都不知道其他人的死
I'm not sure if Abby ever found out about those characters deaths
因为据我所知 在之后的剧情结束后 她直接离开了
because as far as I can tell, after the following sequence, she left.
他们前往圣塔芭芭拉开始了新的生活
They went to Santa Barbara and started a new life.
重点是 埃比此时悲愤至极 她开启了狂怒模式
The point is, Abby is devastated, and she starts to go into a rage driven mode.
还记得杰西和汤米把艾莉带走时她落在这里的地图吗
Remember that map that Ellie dropped and left behind
when Tommy and Jesse took her out of the aquarium?
被埃比找到了
Well, Abby finds it.
她捡起地图 发现艾莉很贴心的在他们的所在地画了个大圆圈
She picks it up and conveniently Ellie has marked in a huge circle exactly where they're staying.
于是 埃比和勒弗前往了杰克逊四人帮的藏身处 想要把汤米揪出来
And so, Abby and Lev go to the Jackson-Knights' hideout, expecting to find Tommy alone.
别忘了 据埃比这边所了解 那边只有汤米和他的几个帮手
Again, as far as they know, it's just Tommy here and some other helpers he has.
他们唯一了解的事实是汤米在那里
They do know for a fact, though, that Tommy's here.
所以我估计埃比可能真的认为自己只会找到汤米
So my assumption would be that Abby really only expects to find Tommy.
结果他们进入剧院后 找到了所有人
After breaking in, they find everyone.
先是在剧院前台的汤米 然后是杰西 然后艾莉也破门而出
First Tommy at the counter in the lobby, then Jesse, and Ellie as they come through the door.
汤米：去你的，杰西……
以为我不知道金子长什么样么……
等你看到这个，小混蛋。
她会喜欢的。
埃比：举起手来。
离你的东西远点。
我说了离远点！
汤米：你犯了个大错——
埃比：别他妈的转身。
勒弗，弓箭继续瞄准他。
趴到地上。
汤米：你要像个懦夫一样杀了我？
埃比：你们这群混蛋。
站起来！
举起手来，不然我开枪把他也打死！
汤米：别听她的，艾莉！快离开这里！
埃比：站起来！
汤米：你他妈敢试试——
埃比：你他妈闭嘴！
好吧——
艾莉：快停下！
埃比：扔掉你的武器。
扔掉你的武器！
艾莉：妈的！
汤米：不……不……
艾莉：我知道你为什么要杀了乔尔。
他那样做是为了救我。
因为我才无法做出疫苗。我就是你要找的人。
放他走。
埃比：你杀死了我的朋友……
我们放了你们一条生路……
但你们浪费了机会！
艾莉：等等！
勒弗：放开她！
艾莉：汤米！
埃比：跟上！
此时游戏来到了高潮
This is when the game reaches its climax.
你操控埃比追杀艾莉 一路来到了剧院里面、后台和道具间
You play as Abby as you chase Ellie deep into the depths of the theaters, props and storage room.
到这里 我们开始操控我们游戏开始时憎恨的、想要杀死的角色
And it's here that we have to play as the character we initially hated and tried to defeat,
把双方位置互换
and then flip that on its head,
开始追杀我们喜欢了近十年的一位角色——艾莉
trying to hunt down and kill someone that we fell in love with almost a decade ago,
that character being Ellie.
根据大家在那份调查里给出的回复
Though based on the pole and the responses that you guys wrote to that survey,
实际上有相当多的人在游戏玩到这里时放弃了
there is actually a fair number of people that reached this point in the game and refused to continue.
他们玩了二三十小时的游戏
They'd played 20, 25, 30 hours of this game,
玩到这里发现游戏竟然让你去杀艾莉 于是拒绝继续玩下去了
got to this point and realized that they were being asked to kill Ellie, and they refused to do it.
我觉得这在某种程度上证明了这些角色在玩家心中有着多么重要的地位
Now at one point, I think that that's a testament
to just how phenomenally well connected these characters are, to us, the players.
我们关心他们 我们不希望看到他们遭遇不公
We care about them, and we don't want to see them mistreated.
这里没有第二种选择感觉真的很难受
Now it's really too bad that there wasn't some alternative state
你本来不想打这场仗 原谅艾莉 继续活下去
where you could actually choose not to continue this fight, forgive Ellie, and move on.
对于手握操控权的玩家来说这本是可以和平解决这场矛盾的光辉时刻
Thing that could have been a cool moment in terms of player agency
to resolve this dispute peacefully.
但对于像这样的线性叙事游戏来说 这种处理并不合适
But with a linear narrative game such as this, that doesn't really work too well.
于是 你只能去打这样Boss战
And so, you're forced to engage in this boss fight,
埃比当前作为主角
where Abby, the protagonist in this instance,
要去追杀艾莉这个反派
is chasing after the antagonist, which is Ellie.
这里不是在说谁对谁错
It's not to say one is right or wrong,
因为谁是主角谁是反派单纯要看作者的叙事角度
because protagonist and antagonist are purely based on the perspective of the author.
至于这点游戏设计是否可行 我觉得首先有一个问题
Now as to whether or not this point in the game works, I think there's an active question here.
即每个玩家看法可能是不一样的
It's probably going to be a little different for everybody.
一些玩家可能和埃比和勒弗产生情感上的连接
Some people probably are going to connect to Abby and Lev
在玩了TLOU2后远超与他们与艾莉的连接
far more than they connected to Ellie over the course of TLOU2.
当然 如果你玩过初代游戏
Now of course, if you played the original game,
那你很可能还有很多初代游戏建立起来的情感包袱
you're probably still going to have a lot of that baggage built up from the original game,
认为艾莉更讨人喜欢
when Ellie was far more likable.
但可悲的是这代游戏里的艾莉并没有那么令人喜爱
The sad truth is that Ellie isn't very likable in this game
这点我在本篇游戏评测中已经提过很多次了
as I've said multiple times throughout this critique.
但对于我来说 当我意识到游戏在让我做什么的时候
But for me I found myself just sitting and staring at my screen for a moment
我呆坐着盯着屏幕愣了一小会
when I realized what I was being asked to do here.
然后我感觉到这是因为在一周目时 游戏可能并没有完成它的使命
And I think it was because the game didn't completely succeed in what it was trying to do
the first time I played the game.
即顽皮狗希望玩家觉得杀死艾莉是合理的
Namely, Naughty Dog, wanted to make the player feel as though killing Ellie was justified
至少应该和艾莉杀死埃比一样合理
at the very least, just as justifiable as Ellie killing Abby.
但我认为游戏并没有做到这点
But the reason I don't think this has worked too well
因为艾莉杀死的埃比那边的人实际上都是配角
is because the people that Ellie has taken from Abby
were all effectively B-Class characters.
欧文？人的确不错 但仍然是配角 而且也不是特别有魅力
Owen? Yeah, he's great, but he's supporting and he's not particularly charismatic.
显然不是一个主导角色
Definitely not a leading character.
但是如果艾莉在勒弗和埃比进入剧院的时候杀死勒弗
However, on the other hand, if Ellie shot and killed Lev right as they enter the theater,
我觉得可能剧情导向的效果会更好
I can't help but feel as though this would have worked much better.
这样玩家在操控埃比游玩这段的时候
Likely the player playing as Abby in this case
可能会感觉追杀艾莉会更加有合理性
would feel much more justified in chasing down Ellie if this had happened.
总之 埃比还是在Boss战中追杀艾莉
But nonetheless, Abby hunts Ellie down in a boss fight
这场战斗与第一部中冬季篇结束时对抗大家最喜欢的食人魔王的战斗基本相同
that's basically identical to the one that ended the winter chapter in the first game
against everybody's favorite cannibal king.
不知道是制作组犯懒 完全复制了战斗内容
I don't know if it's just lazy, repetitive game design,
还是本身就是想让你模仿那场战斗的类似操作
or if this is meant to be an actual reversal and similarly in and of itself.
我不清楚
I don't know.
但从它的布局和这场Boss战的结构来看 两者确实惊人地相似
But it does seem shockingly similar in terms of how it's laid out
and the structure of this boss fight.
也许是巧合 也许是刻意为之 我不确定
Maybe it's a coincidence, maybe it's something very intentional, I'm not sure.
但至少我个人认为是完全相同的战斗
But at the very least, I thought that it was a direct parallel.
整个故事以我所知的所有游戏中观看体验最难受的场景之一收尾
The whole thing wraps up with one of the hardest to watch cut scenes
in all of gaming as far as I'm concerned.
艾莉：住手。
住手！
她跟这一切无关。
她怀孕了。
埃比：好极了。
勒弗：埃比！
埃比：别让我再看到你。
她在勒弗叫住她几秒后停手了
She stopped short… after Lev calls out to her,
走吧
她意识到这样没有任何帮助
She realizes that this isn't going to help anything.
就像杀死乔尔并不会让她能够面对父亲的死
Just like killing Joel didn't help her get over her father's death,
她从父亲去世这件事中解脱的时刻 或者至少是接受的时刻
the moment she moved on from her father's death, or at the very least accepted,
是她遇到勒弗和雅拉的那个雨夜
was that first night after she met Lev and Yara
她发现自己还是可以重新有一个家庭的
when she realized that she could have a family again.
相遇不再是靠恶意与复仇 而是靠爱与和谐
United not in hate and vengeance, but in love and unity.
所以她放她们走了
So she lets them go.
埃比和勒弗离开了 留下艾莉和蒂娜在地板上 血流得到处都是
Abby and Lev leave, and Ellie and Dina are left, bleeding out on the floor.
画面一黑 来到了游戏最后一个章节
We cut to black and the game moves into the final chapter.
我觉得根本无法形容玩家玩到这里的时候内心感受有多奇怪
Now I don't think I can stress enough just how weird the player likely feels at this point.
这感觉就像女神躺在你身边结果自己是个太监一样
原文有点隐♂晦 这里采用意译
It's a mixture of a let-down with being blue balled all at the same time,
真的 说实话我完全不知道该如何评价
and if I'm being honest, I really didn't know what to make of it.
还有不少玩家指出
There are a lot of other people also pointed out
这与《荒野大镖客：救赎2》收束结尾的方式很像
that this was somewhat similar to how Red Dead Redemption 2 started to wrap up its story,
当中亚瑟的死显然是主要故事内容的结尾
with Arthur's death coming seemingly wrapping up the main story.
然后玩家进入了一个似乎很重要 但并不关键的尾声
And then the player entering into an epilogue that seemed important, but not crucial.
事实上我问过我的几个朋友
In fact, I asked several friends of mine,
在他们看完《荒野大镖客：救赎2》的主线故事后他们是否玩了尾声部分
whether or not they actually played the epilogue or not,
after they got through the main story of Red Dead redemption 2,
你会惊讶地发现他们中有多少人说在亚瑟死后就不玩了
and you'd be surprised how many of them said that they stopped playing after Arthur died.
一方面我能理解他们
On the one hand, I get it.
你在游戏的整个过程中一直跟随着那个角色
You've been following one character for the entire length of the game,
而这个角色的故事似乎已经结束了
and that character's story has seemingly come to an end.
如果你觉得没有必要
So why do you need to continue playing through
那为何还要继续游玩客观上相对无趣的几个小时的游戏内容呢？
what is objectively a much more boring sequence for multiple hours at a time
if you don't feel as though it's necessary?
当游戏发布的时候
And when that game came out,
我不禁认为这种把尾声与主线明显分开的决策要么是R星再三考虑下的决策
I couldn't help but feel as though it was either a very conscious decision on the part of Rockstar
to have this epilogue so clearly separate from the main story,
要么就是彻底的失误
or it was a complete and total oversight.
对于TLOU2来说
In the case of TLOU2,
我觉得没法直接比较 但也的确有相似之处
I don't think it's direct comparison, but I do think there are similarities.
据我的估计
In my estimation,
绝大多数玩家都希望TLOU2
most players have been going through TLOU2
结尾能是艾莉和埃比的一段高潮场景
with the hope that it will end in a climactic scene between Ellie and Abby,
当中把所有问题都解决掉 最好是一个杀了另一个
where everything gets resolved, preferably where one kills the other,
或者至少有所清算
or at the very least, there are some sort of reckoning.
但我觉得游戏这段并没有解决这个问题 满足两人的诉求
But I wouldn't say that this scratches that itch or satisfies that demand.
诚然 说埃比明显赢得了这场战斗是没什么争议的
I don't think it's controversial to say that Abby, pretty clearly won this exchange.
如果她想 她轻松就能杀掉艾莉和蒂娜
And if she wanted to, could have killed Ellie and Dina easily.
但出于内心某种尊严或风度 还有宽恕、自尊等等
But out of some sense of dignity or grace and forgiveness, pride,
无论是哪种 她决定放她们一马
whatever it may be, she decided to spare them.
因此虽然从埃比的角度看 这场冲突可能已经解决了
So while this may be a resolution of the conflict from Abby's perspective,
她决定继续向前看 想要忘掉这一切
she's moving on and wants to forget about all of this.
但对艾莉、汤米还是蒂娜来说都没有解决
It's not a resolution for Ellie, for Tommy, or for Dina,
就像我们即将看到的场景中那样
as we'll see in the following scenes.
我觉得真正令玩家感到沮丧的
And I think the really frustrating thing for the player
在整个游戏时间内 整个故事一直在为这个时刻、这样的一场战斗做准备
is that the entire story has been building to this moment, this exchange, this fight,
throughout the entirety of the game play time.
现在我们玩到这里 结果却什么都没解决
And now that we've reached it, it doesn't resolve itself at all.
不但没解决 我们还看到艾莉、蒂娜、汤米躺地上浑身是血
And instead, Ellie, Dina and Tommy are left bleeding out on the floor,
杰西还领盒饭了
and in the case of Jesse, he's dead.
特别是考虑到玩家游玩这段时情感上已经心力交瘁了
And especially considering how emotionally exhausting the scheme is to play,
真的很难强求玩家再花多少个小时来继续游玩游戏的尾声部分
it's really difficult to ask the player to buckle down for another
however many hours it's going to take to get through what is effectively the epilogue.
而且我知道理论上这算是尾声 因为故事矛盾根本还没解决
And I know it's not technically an epilogue because the story hasn't resolved itself.
下一章节仍然属于主线故事的内容
It's still part of the main story as we move into this next chapter.
但只是看起来和主线故事很割裂
But still it feels as though it separate from the main game.
我思考了很久都不确定顽皮狗是希望如此
And after a lot of contemplation, I am not sure if Naughty Dog wanted this to be the case,
或者甚至说他们刻意让之后的故事和西雅图的主线内容如此不同
or if they even meant for this to feel so different from the core body of the game in Seattle.
而有一点是很清楚的 就是在核心游戏内容结束后节奏上的这种急剧转变
It seems to be pretty clear that shifting pace very sharply after all of the events of the core game,
会在很大程度上打击玩家的游戏感受 让他们感受到明显的差异感
is going to hit the player in a fairly significant way such that they're going to feel very differently.
很多游戏开发者曾在开发者大会、演讲之类的场合提到过
It's something a good number of developers have spoken of
in GDC conference, speeches, and things like that,
在一个项目上连续干很多年后慢慢失去焦点的这种困扰
where they express this frustration with working on a project for years and years and years
and losing perspective on it,
他们会因此忘记第一次玩这个游戏应该是什么样的体验
such that they forget how it would actually feel to play it for the first time.
换句话说 当你在某个项目上忘我地拼命时
In other words, when you're working really hard on something,
你的视角就会慢慢缩窄 你会慢慢进入当局者迷的境地
you develop a sort of tunnel vision and you lose perspective on what it looks like from the outside.
对你来说可能看起来很棒
It may seem great to you,
但由于你过于专注于小细节
but just because you're so focused on the little details,
导致丧失了整体上的视野
you might have lost sight of the overall picture.
或者反过来 你可能过于专注于全局 结果忽略了细节
Or vice versa, you are focused on the broader picture, so you lose sight of the minutiae.
无论怎么说 最后这段战斗都让玩家感觉到了奇怪
Regardless, this final fight leaves the player feeling kind of strange,
至少我是这样认为的
at least it did for me;
而基于大家很多人在调查中的回复
and based on a lot of your responses to the survey,
很多人也感觉到了奇怪
it left a lot of you feeling very strange as well.
我不知道你怎样想
And I don't know about you,
我是感觉太多人有同样想法的话我就会联想到游戏品质问题
but often strangers into feeling I would associate with quality.
说了这么多 游戏核心内容结束后
But with all that said after this initial chunk of the game is over,
玩家留下了很多悬而未决的问题
the player's left with a lot of questions unresolved.
比如 蒂娜还好吗？
For instance, is Dina okay?
脑袋咣咣咣砸了那么多下水泥地没事吗？
Is she going to survive having her face bashed into cement multiple times?
不过实际上应该不是水泥地 好像有块木板垫着
While it's technically it wasn't cement, they put down a particle board
这样活下来也好解释 细节很棒
so that they could have an excuse as to why she survived, its good detail.
他们能放几块木板我很欣慰
I'm glad that they put this in there
这样颅骨骨折还没死也能解释得通
so that it's not totally unbelievable that she survived a cracked skull.
但挺着大肚子能活下来也真是命硬
But still this is a pretty rough thing to go through, especially when you're pregnant.
所以玩家此时并不知道她会不会有事
So the player's left wondering whether or not she's going to be okay.
你还想知道 尚未出生的孩子父亲杰西已经死了 那这两人的未来会怎样
You also have to ask yourself what's going to happen to this couple
when the incoming baby comes along now that Jesse's gone.
杰克逊小镇要怎样处理
How is Jackson going to handle
他们的精英小队几乎被州外的一个小团体灭了这件事？
having so many of their best and brightest, decimated by an out of state group?
他们能、或者会接受此事吗？
Can, or will they ever be able to adjust?
我们甚至永远不会知道答案
I mean, we don't ever really get to know.
因为之后的游戏我们再也没有回到杰克逊小镇
Because in the following sequences, we never return back to Jackson.
另外 可能现在最重要的问题是 艾莉怎么样了？
And perhaps the most important question is what does Ellie do now?
她能放下一切吗？
Is she capable of moving on?
这是艾莉想要的结果吗？
Is that something that Ellie would even want?
这是玩家想要的结果吗？
Is that something that would even satisfy the player?
还是说我们最后还要准备再大干一票 一举了解此事
Or are we setting ourselves up for one last hurrah to try and resolve everything
拼命为游戏核心内容本身的合理性而辩护？
in a desperate attempt to justify the events of the core game itself?
就像《荒野大镖客：救赎2》那样 答案是后者
Just like Red Dead Redemption 2, it's gonna end up being the latter.
这些问题的答案大多会出现 但现在我们还被蒙在鼓里
Answers to these questions will mostly come, but for now we're left in the dark.
战斗过后的黑场结束后 我们来到一片农场
After cut to black, after this fight, we open up on a farm.
有一片广阔的麦田 远处有一座农舍 后面有一个谷仓
There's an expansive wheat field with a farm house off in the distance and a barn behind it.
一切宁静如画
It's very calm and picturesque.
房子里面我们看到了艾莉
Inside we see Ellie,
她看起来已经痊愈 状况好了不少
she seems, healed up and relatively healthy,
拿着乔尔在第一部作品开头莎拉送给他的手表
and she's holding Joel's old broken watch that he got from Sarah in the first game.
游戏在以一种不那么微妙的方式提醒玩家 艾莉还在惦记着乔尔
This is a not so subtle way of reminding the player that Ellie is still thinking about Joel,
她还没有放下此事
and that she hasn't moved on.
另外 现在还有个小宝宝了
Also, there's a baby now.
这再次证实了自上一场景的事件发生以来已经过去了好长一段时间
This reaffirms that it's been a good long while since the events of the previous scene.
接着我们在厨房见到了蒂娜
Furthermore, we see Dina in the kitchen,
看起来她也恢复得不错
and it seems as though she's recovered just fine,
还穿着家庭主妇一样的裤子
and she also has her mom jeans coming in clutch.
好吧其实我真不知道那应该叫啥
I mean maybe, it's stupid, I'm honestly not sure what it is.
但这个场景我第一眼见到蒂娜就感觉她太有当妈的感觉了
But when I saw Dina in this scene, I thought that she just she looked like a mom.
我也不知道为什么 可能是画了眉毛
I don't know what it is, maybe they bushed up her eyebrows, and that did it.
也可能是她奇怪的装束 也可能是因为她在洗碗
Maybe it's the strange outfit she has on or the fact that she's doing dishes.
我不知道怎么回事
I don't know what it is.
但他们的确成功让蒂娜看上去很像一位妈妈
But they seemingly did a good job of making her appear as a mother,
这点应该为顽皮狗点赞
I guess props to Naughty Dog.
而且说实话 一切都显得宁静愉快
And to be honest, everything seems calm and relatively happy,
但这个世界里不会有什么幸福的结局
but nothing ever ends happily in this world.
所以这当然也不会持续很久
So of course this won't last for long.
艾莉干了点日常杂活 和蒂娜跳了个舞 玩家参观了一下房间
Ellie does some routine chores, you dance with Dina a little bit, and you explore the house.
这里有趣的一点是艾莉家里有很多从乔尔家里拿过来的艺术画
Fun little note here is that Ellie actually has a good amount of art in the house
that was taken from Joel's house.
这是个很好的提示
It's a nice touch,
这同样能说明艾莉仍想抓住乔尔的一些影子
and it makes sense since she would likely want to hold on to parts of him,
就像刚刚我们看她在把玩乔尔的手表一样
as we just saw earlier when she had his watch.
而这方面的细节真的很甜
It's just a really sweet little detail,
尤其是考虑到玩家很可能根本不会注意到这点
especially considering the fact that the player will likely not notice this,
至少一周目游戏的时候肯定不会
at least on their first run through the game.
我发现此事还是因为我为了做这个视频剪辑了很多游戏片段
I only noticed it once I spent a lot of time recording footage for this video
反复认真切换场景才发现的
going back through environments very carefully.
我先是发现乔尔的房间里有很多好看的挂图 我很喜欢
I noticed that in Joel's house there are a lot of really nice looking paintings that I liked.
实际上这事我在视频前半部分就提到过
In fact, I even reference those earlier in this very video.
但之后我来到这段场景时 我发现这些画看着很眼熟
But then when I went back through this section, I noticed that those paintings looked similar.
我一开始以为制作者只是在重复使用贴图罢了 这种操作在游戏开发中很常见
And I initially thought that they were just reusing assets which is pretty common in game development.
但更进一步的观察后
But upon further inspection and deliberation,
我发现这其实是美术设计上的安排
I realized that this was actually an artistic choice,
因为艾莉一直在想着把乔尔生活中的一些事物带到她的生活中去
because Ellie is trying to keep and bring parts of Joel into her life even still.
现在 在探索了房子并与蒂娜寒暄了一会儿后
Now, after exploring the house and chilling with Dina for a little bit,
蒂娜要艾莉把外面的羊招回谷仓
Dina asks Ellie to bring in the sheep from outside and put them into the barn.
所以艾莉抱着孩子一起去干活
So Ellie goes, and does this with the baby.
然后艾莉发现了一只落单的小羊
And after doing it, Ellie spots one little straggler.
诶！
接下来可能是整个游戏里最快速的情绪转变——
And there's probably leads to the fastest mood shift of the whole game.
你怎么出来的？
来吧，小家伙。
啊！
好。
快点，小家伙……
你不想吃东西吗……？
乔尔：艾莉！
艾莉：不，不，不……
乔尔：救我！！
艾莉：乔尔！
乔尔：啊！！
艾莉：求你了，不要！！
蒂娜：艾莉？
我真的感觉这一刻吓了玩家一跳 就像艾莉一样
I really think that this moment is meant to hit the player just as hard as it hits Ellie.
诶，艾莉。
看着我。
没事了，你到家了，你在家里。
本来一切是那么轻松愉悦
Everything seems fine, calm and relaxed.
调整呼吸，好好呼吸。
看起来她们已经从游戏核心部分的很多烂事中走出来
It seems as though they've moved on from a lot of the struggles of the core game
艾莉：我做不到，我做不到！
蒂娜：没事。我来抱他，好么？
过上幸福美满的生活了
and that their living a happy, satisfied life together.
来这里，小家伙。
嘘嘘嘘……
但现在一切都崩塌了
But now everything is falling apart.
艾莉还是无法忘记乔尔身上发生的一切
Ellie's mind won't let her forget what happened to Joel,
嘘……嘘……没事了……
她明显没法放下此事
and she's clearly been unable to move on.
艾莉：对不起。
蒂娜也明白此事 并表示理解 因为她知道艾莉自己也无能为力
Dina knows this and is understanding because she knows that Ellie can't help this.
我不知道怎么了……
我刚刚才在赶……
这不是她能控制的
It's something beyond her control,
就像其他患有类似问题的人无法控制自己的惊恐发作一样
just like anybody else who suffers from panic attacks can't really control it.
蒂娜：没事。我们办到了。
它就是这样会突然到来
It just happens when it happens.
而游戏还在匆匆继续它的故事
But the game keeps carrying along, relatively quickly.
我们来到第二天 家里来客人了
We jump to the next day and there is a guest in the house.
是汤米
It's Tommy.
没错 他头部中枪却活下来了
Yeah, he's survived the shot to the head.
而他现在伤还没好利索 甚至连走路都困难
He's currently got a lot of damage that he's dealing with and he even struggles walking.
毕竟脑袋中了一枪……可以理解
I mean, he took a bullet to the head, so… it's understandable.
显然他身体条件不太好
Clearly he's not in good shape,
但他对埃比所做的事情还是耿耿于怀
but he does not want to let Abby get away with what she's done.
他说他追踪到埃比在圣塔芭芭拉
He says that he's tracked her to a location in Santa Barbara.
现在 他虽然没有明说
Now, even though he doesn't state it outright,
但他自己肯定是去不了了
it's pretty clear that he's unable to go and chase her himself.
毕竟汤米现在走路都不方便 还瞎了一只眼睛
He can barely walk after all, and he's missing an eye now,
所以他就算去也帮不上什么忙
so he wouldn't exactly be much help if he were to go.
于是他找到艾莉帮忙完成他的复仇计划
And so he's come to Ellie to proposition her for this revenge plot.
最开始看感觉这地方有点牵强
Now initially, this might seem relatively far fetched
汤米竟然能追踪到离他的城市那么远的地方的一个人
that Tommy was able to track her down to a city that is very far away from where they are at.
艾莉和蒂娜显然在杰克逊以外附近某处
Apparently they're just outside of Jackson in the surrounding area,
所以她们俩还在这 只是搬离了小镇的核心区
so they're local, but they have moved out away from the core group.
然后我认为这里倒没有最初看来那样牵强
However, I don't think this is as far as stretch as it might initially seem.
汤米和火萤组织有着千丝万缕的联系
Tommy has a ton of connections to the Fireflies.
如果你还有印象的话
If you remember from earlier,
欧文说过他想坐船一起和梅尔、埃比、雅拉和勒弗去圣塔芭芭拉
Owen said that he wanted to go to Santa Barbara on the boat with Mel, Abby, Yara and Lev,
因为他认为那边还有大量火萤组织残党
because he thought that there were going to be a lot of Fireflies there
可以过去投靠他们
that they could connect and join up with.
同样的方法 汤米应该也能够追踪到那片区域里带着一个亚裔的某个女性
Using the same contacts, it seems Tommy was able to track
a very buff woman with a small young Asian individual by her side to this area.
因此 他们能够追踪她到这一点似乎是相对合理的
So it seems relatively plausible that they would be able to track her to this point,
特别是如果让汤米直接对外公告说全境通缉埃比的情况下
especially if Tommy were to put out an APB on this individual trying to find her,
而他显然已经这样做了
which he's clearly done.
然而听到他的提议后 艾莉和蒂娜表示强烈反对
However, after hearing his proposition, Ellie and Dina strongly reject the idea.
她们已经放弃这事了
They are done with that.
或者说至少蒂娜已经放弃了 艾莉还有所挂念
Or at the very least, Dina is, and Ellie going along with it.
她们现在已经失去了太多东西
Now they have too much to lose.
她们有了一个家庭 有了彼此
They have a house of family and of course each other.
她们曾经尝试过
They've been there, done that.
上次她们追杀埃比的结果并不好
In the last time they tried to chase Abby down, it didn't end well.
汤米在对她们的无动于衷表示愤怒后离开了
Tommy leaves furious that they're not going to do anything.
他觉得自己遭到了背叛 甚至还提起艾莉曾对他说会不惜一起代价复仇
He feels betrayed, and even calls Ellie out,
since she told him that she was going to do whatever it took to get revenge.
这种反应倒是能理解 毕竟汤米仍在为他哥哥的死而愤怒
It's an understandable reaction, considering that Tommy is still furious about his brother's death,
而且埃比还给他留下了永久的创伤
and that she has now permanently scarred him.
但看到汤米对艾莉如此激烈的反应还是有点令人吃惊
But it is a little startling to see Tommy react in such a sharp way towards Ellie.
事实上我甚至想不出汤米在整个TLOU系列里有哪次是以这种态度与人交流的
In fact, I can't think of a time when we've ever seen Tommy
react or talk to somebody in this way throughout the entirety of this franchise.
最接近的例子应该是乔尔第一次去汤米的水电站时双方发生点小矛盾的时候
The closest example would be in the first game when Joel and Tommy got frustrated with each other
when they initially visited the power plant.
但那也没这次这样激烈、直接
But even that wasn't this sharp or direct.
蒂娜拉汤米出去说 俩人在外面吵了一会
Dina asks that Tommy leaves and then yells at him for a brief moment outside
声音大到屋里的艾莉都能听见
where it can still be overheard by Ellie.
但艾莉还是被卷入了进来
But Ellie is still caught up in all of this.
她明白蒂娜不同意她去找埃比了结此事
She knows that Dina is not OK with her going and trying to end this once and for all,
但她还是惦记这件事
but she's still pondering everything.
实际上 接下来的场景
In fact, in the next scene,
我们就看到艾莉深夜在家中踱步
we see her walking aimlessly through the house in the middle of the night,
她夜不能寐 辗转反侧
unable to sleep and unsure of what to do.
她想复仇 但又知道这可能让她失去一切
She wants revenge but knows that it may cost her everything.
她用乔尔的旧吉他弹着小调 想让自己忘掉一切
She plays a little ditty and Joel's old guitar to take her mind off of everything.
但这看上去没有一点用处
But it doesn't seem to do anything.
实际上 这反而让一切变得更糟
In fact, it seems to make everything worse.
镜头接着来到了杰克逊小镇的冬季舞会
We then jumped to the scene of the Jackson Winter Ball
这段我们之前只在言语中讨论过的场景
that we have only heard discussed up to this point.
内容和发售前的预告片一样
It plays out just like we saw in the trailer before launch,
而这次我们知道了游戏开头艾莉说的那件事
except that now we see the events described in the first hours of the game.
在预告片的内容——艾莉和蒂娜亲吻了彼此之后
After the happenings of the trailer, culminating in the kiss between Ellie and Dina,
一位长者对二人的亲吻行为说了一些不好听的话
an old man makes a disparaging comments about Dina and Ellie kissing.
乔尔上来推了他一把 让艾莉不知为何很不高兴
Joel steps in and pushes them which upsets Ellie for some reason.
可能因为她觉得乔尔又一次插手了本来属于她自己的事情
Likely because she feels as though Joel is once again keeping her from fighting her own fights.
不要急 我们稍后会说到此事
But don't worry, we'll talk about this more in just a little bit.
于是回到现在 艾莉下定决心去追杀埃比
So, back in the present, Ellie has decided that she has to take Abby on,
这次要让一切做个了结
to finish this once, and for all,
也许是她想起了与那个偏执的老人对峙的事情
Perhaps reminded of this confrontation with the old, bigoted man,
她明白她应该为属于她自己的事情去战斗
she realizes that she needs to fight her own fights and finish this,
否则她将永远无法为自己而活
otherwise she won't be able to live with herself.
但这次 她的离开不是抛下杰克逊小镇那么简单了
However, this time she's not just leaving Jackson behind,
她在抛弃她辛苦建立的整个家庭
she's abandoning her entire family, this whole thing that she's built up.
这里我再一次感到很难去同情艾莉
Once again it's hard to feel sorry for Ellie here,
尤其我觉得很多人会希望
especially since most people I think
她应该放下这一切 不要再去找埃比了
would say that she should have left well enough alone and not chased Abby again.
和我聊过艾莉最后这个抛弃一切、要去再次追杀埃比的决定的每一个人
Literally every single person I've talked to about this final decision by Ellie
to leave everything, and Chase Abby down again
都说这是一个错误的决定 都不想艾莉这样做
has said that this was the wrong decision, and that they didn't want her to do it.
他们希望她能原谅埃比 继续生活下去
They wanted her to forgive Abby to move on.
这又是一个在情感上令人感到心力交瘁的安排
It's yet another example of how emotionally exhausting the scheme can be to play,
因为当你不同意角色所做事情的时候
because when you don't agree with what the characters are doing,
你就会对角色失去同情心
you start to lose sympathy with them.
使得你更难同情其所经历的一切
And that makes it harder to empathize with everything that they're going through.
艾莉收拾东西的时候 蒂娜发现了她
Ellie starts packing up her things when Dina finds her.
蒂娜很清楚艾莉一直在想这件事
Dina clearly knows that Ellie's been considering this
但看到她真的付诸实践还是很害怕
but is terrified to see her actually going through with it.
蒂娜恳求她回来继续睡觉
Dina begs her to come back to bed,
恳求她放下这件事 忘掉这一切 不要抛弃她的家庭 不要去复仇
to move on, to forget about everything, to stay with the family and not do this.
但艾莉说她别无选择 只能这样做
But Ellie says she has no choice and has to.
蒂娜明确表示自己不会再去干这样的事了
Dina makes it very clear that she's not going to do this whole thing again.
她不会和艾莉一起去
She's not going to go and help her.
如果艾莉决定这对她来说是最重要的
And if Ellie decides that this is what's most important to her,
那等她活着回家就甭想再去找蒂娜和孩子了
she shouldn't expect to find her and the baby there when or if she gets back alive.
她实际上是在给艾莉下最后通牒
She is effectively giving Ellie an ultimatum.
去找埃比 或者和蒂娜留下来
Choose Abby, or choose Dina,
留在这个她亲手建立起的整个家庭里
and the family, and everything that she's built up with her.
艾莉选择了前者
Ellie chooses Abby.
她再一次让玩家感觉她一点都不可怜
Again, giving the player very little reason to feel bad or sorry for her,
——她会失去蒂娜 以及接下来几小时游戏中她将遇到的所有痛苦
Losing Dina, and for all of the pain that she's likely to encounter
in the next few hours as the game wraps up.
于是艾莉离开了 留下了悲痛的蒂娜
So Ellie leaves, Dina's left devastated.
顽皮狗在这玩了个假动作
And Naughty Dog pulls a fake out.
画面给到加利福尼亚
We jumped to California.
景色和之前完全不同 一切都很干燥、死寂
It's a market set difference, everything's very dry and dead.
本章开篇镜头给到一双帆布鞋
The chapter opens up with the camera focused on a pair of Converse.
玩过一代游戏的都知道这肯定是艾莉标志性的打扮
Anyone who's played the first game knows that this is Ellie signature shoe.
结果镜头一拉远
But the camera pans up,
结果发现竟然是勒弗 旁边和他一起走的是埃比
and we see that it's Lev wearing the shoes and Abby's walking alongside him.
现在这对我来说有点明显
Now this is a bit obvious for me,
但这显然是在为埃比和乔尔以及艾莉和勒弗之间的平行关系做铺垫
but it's clearly setting up the parallel between Abby and Joel and Ellie and Lev.
这种平行关系的类比是否合理取决于你
Whether you think those are fair to draw as comparisons or similes is up to you,
但这显示就是编剧想表达的内容
but that's clearly what the writers are doing.
艾莉的帆布鞋是她的标志
Ellie is known for her Converse,
这就是她在第一部作品中的标准打扮之一
and in fact it's one of the staples of her outfit in the first game,
甚至在本作大部分时间里也是如此
and even throughout most of the second game.
如此明确地向玩家展示这双鞋 就是在向玩家明示两组人的平行关系
To so clearly show these shoes to me is hitting the player over the head with this simile.
现在埃比和勒弗在寻找火萤组织
Now Abby and Lev are looking for the Fireflies
希望能找到一个他们可以归属的新的大家庭
hoping to find a new home to which they can belong.
还记得欧文之前提到的圣塔芭芭拉吧
Again, remembering that Owen suggested Santa Barbara way back when.
他们得到线索说在圣塔芭芭拉的康斯坦斯街2425号
Now they had a tip that 2425 Constance in Santa Barbara
有一个火萤组织网络的地下据点
was a hideout for the underground Firefly network.
因此在埃比和勒弗解决几个感染者之后
And so after Abby and Lev fight through a few infected,
他们终于来到了这座房子的地下室
they worked their way to the basement of the house,
并发现了无线电装置
and the pair discovers a radio.
一番尝试后 他们终于联系上了某人
And after a few attempts they connect with somebody.
看起来埃比和勒弗终于找到了新家 终于安全了
And it seems as though Abby and Lev have found their new home and will be safe after all.
拉倒吧 悲剧很快就到你家门口
But again, no, everything is sad and terrible.
哪有什么美满结局 准备好吧 坏事要来了
Nothing's gonna end happily, so just get ready, everything is going to go terribly wrong.
于是两人确定了一个会合点 他们将前往那里与火萤组织会合
So the two set up a meet up point where they're gonna head to meet up with the Fireflies.
当两人离开房子的时候
As the pair leaves the house,
一个小团伙在门口把他们截住了
they are intercepted by a small gang as they exit out the front of the house.
这些人似乎正在进行某种奴隶贸易
It seems that these people are involved in the slave trade,
说实话 游戏玩了这么久才出现这种组织挺令我惊讶的
which, to be honest, I'm stunned took this long to be featured in the game.
两人被揍了一顿 捆上 然后被带走了
They're beaten, tied up and taken away,
可能会卖身为奴 当劳工去了
presumably to be entered into the slave trade and used for manual labor.
画面来到艾莉 她很快就跟上来了
We then cut to Ellie, who was closing in quickly.
她发现了他们的船就扎在那
She's found their boat and begins pushing into their location
船上还找到一张地图 上面圈起了康斯坦斯街2425号这个地方
after finding a map that has 2425 Constance marked on it.
你一路推进穿越各种街道和房屋
As you push through multiple houses and streets,
这里是整部游戏里最后一次和感染者的战斗了
this is the last zombie hurrah combat in the entire game.
好好享受吧
So be sure to enjoy it.
因为之后顽皮狗安排的战斗将是完全和人类敌人作战
Because after this Naughty Dog is going to be sticking with human enemies exclusively.
只不过有个小例外 这点之后会提到
Except for one small exception, which I'll point out in a moment.
总之 这之后会有很多很多人类敌人就是了
But still, it's going to be pretty much all humans after this.
艾莉继续在街坊里推进 爬下一座小丘
Ellie pushes her way through an initial neighborhood and starts climbing down a hill.
然后……
When this happens.
艾莉：啊！可恶！
拜托。
不！坏了，坏了，坏了！
妈的！
妈的。
艾莉：埃比？
埃比！
我找到你了！
我找到……
男子：看到没？抓到一个活的。
男子：这娘们被整惨了。
艾莉：啊！
妈的！
男子：如果她能活一个月，我们就走运了。
我们今天能不能就到此为止？
男子：好。把那东西放下来，重新布置陷阱。
男子：你认真的？我说，值得为她再跑一趟吗？
又不是——
啊！妈的！
男子：咬到你了吗？
男子：没，没有。我没事。
我没事。
妈的。
有什么好笑的？
艾莉：你吓得尿裤子了。
男子：你他妈说什么？
艾莉：真是个小孬种。
男子：哦，你觉得好笑是吗？
起来。
男子：快点。没必要这样。
男子：不，反正她早晚都得死。起来！
艾莉：不要——！
男子：对啊，真好笑，是不是？
男子：你来真的——？
男子：快！笑啊！
啊！
男子：该死！
俩人唠着唠着就白给了
Now these guys are obviously super dome.
该死！
而作为玩家 你应该经常问自己 你玩游戏的动力何在？
But you have to ask yourself as the player, what's keeping you going?
妈的！
不是说游戏让你干啥你就干啥 就叫有游戏动力了
Other than just going through the motions of continuing to do what the game asks you to do.
等等！等等！你刚才提到了埃比？
你在找埃比，对不对？
我们几个月前发现了一个人。
TLOU2前几个小时很不错的一点就是
One of the best things about the early hours of TLOU2
艾莉：对，最好是。
玩家会完全体会到艾莉的想法 和她一样想找埃比复仇
is that the player is completely on board with Ellie's drive and mission to take out Abby.
男子：大个子！
金发！胳膊像我的一样粗。
她带着一个骨瘦如柴、嘴角有割伤的小孩。
而随着游戏的进行
And as the game goes on,
你也会随着自己开始同情埃比和她的伙伴而开始慢慢失去这样的动力
you also start to lose that motivation once you start to sympathize with Abby and her crew.
对，就是她。
所以在那场Boss战中你会感觉内心非常矛盾
So you end up very conflicted in that final boss fight
你什么都不想做 哪个角色也不想伤害
where you don't want to do anything or hurt either one of these characters.
你放我走，我就告诉你她在哪里。
而现在玩家的感觉还是那样
But now the players still feels like that.
你变异之前就能找到她了。
游戏设计者让你操控艾莉继续追杀埃比
And yet the game designers are asking Ellie to chase down Abby,
尽管此时她已经为此失去了一切
even though it's caused her to lose everything at this point
而且很可能不会得到玩家或者艾莉都满意的结果
and will likely not result in the conclusion
艾莉：说。
而且很可能不会得到玩家或者艾莉都满意的结果
that either the player or Ellie he would be satisfied with.
男子：她在我们营地的牢房里。
一些玩家认为这属于游戏节奏把控问题
Some people have said that this is a pacing issue,
艾莉：牢房在哪？
我觉得这样讲不太恰当
but I don't think that that's the right way to phrase it.
男子：朝那边一直走，你会看到铁轨。
真要说的话 我觉得这是游戏动力上的问题
If anything, I think that this is a motivational issue.
沿着铁轨可以走到一个度假村。
我觉得玩家在玩这关的时候会感觉没有继续做游戏要求的事情的动力
I think the player doesn't feel motivated to continue on this mission
我们把他们关在又高又圆的建筑里
that they're being asked to embark on.
当然 有很多游戏就是让玩家单纯跟着游玩内容去走的
Now of course, you could have a game
that motivates the player to continue playing purely by way of its game play,
不用去管任何叙事的内容
and there is no narrative reason to continue at all.
我发誓。
但顽皮狗的游戏不是这样的
However, that's not how Naughty Dog games work.
顽皮狗的游戏完全都是靠叙事来推动玩家继续游玩下去的
Naughty Dog games are entirely about motivating the player by way of this narrative drive.
而且我说实话 我看这里做得如此平平无奇感觉实在糟糕
And I'll be honest, it's really too bad that this falls so flat
因为这里本应是游戏高潮所在
because this should be the climax of the game.
结果却是这种单调乏味的任务
But instead it feels as though it's a total chore,
因为玩家认为艾莉的行为是完全不合理的
because the player doesn't feel as though Ellie is justified in what she's doing.
甚至艾莉也因自己的决定而感到纠结
And certainly Ellie is even frustrated with her own decision.
艾莉还继续想着复仇 因为她觉得自己对乔尔有一份责任
The only reason Ellie is continuing on it is because she feels an obligation to Joel,
这份责任稍后就会解释
an obligation that's going to be resolved very shortly.
说是这样说 玩家还是继续推进到一个叫“度假村”的奴隶贩子营地
But even so, the player pushes on into the slave trader camped known as "the Resort".
这不是什么故意搞笑的名字
It's not a sassy or funny name,
只是这地方以前是个度假区 所以就这样叫了 就这么简单
it's just that it's an old resort, so they call it "the Resort", it's pretty simple.
这里可以解锁整个游戏里我最喜欢的枪
Now this section does feature my favorite gun of the entire game,
但它实在是太强了 完全不需要有手就能玩
but it's so damn powerful that it removes any need for any finesse whatsoever.
有了这把逆天武器
So with this new found super weapon,
你一路杀到了度假区里关着奴隶的主体建筑里
you fight your way through the Resorts main building where all of the slaves are housed.
说实话 这这关做得真挺烂
And to be honest, the section is actually pretty bad,
尤其想到这都已经是游戏里的结尾部分了
especially when considering that it is the final section of the game.
这已经是除了最终boss“战”以外的最后一场战斗内容了
This is the final game play section of the game other than the final boss quote-unquote, "fight",
无趣到令人咂舌
and its painfully uninteresting.
要说唯一有意思的点
The only thing that shakes it up a little bit
就是几个被锁链固定住的感染者了 可以把它们放了去咬敌人
is having zombies chained up that you can release on the human NPCs.
但除此之外 这关就真没什么有意思的内容了
But other than that, there's really nothing that's interesting about this level.
而即使你可以解开感染者的锁链
And even though zombies, you shoot off their chains or disconnect them,
让它们去攻击其他人类敌人
and they started attacking the other people, the other NPCs
那么如果人类敌人没有杀光感染者 你就得在感染者发现你之前解决它们
and then you just end up having to kill zombies before they come to you
if they are not already killed by those human NPCs.
所以游戏内容本身并没啥特别新奇不同的地方
So it even by itself doesn't do anything new or different.
只是空洞的杀杀杀
It's just bland.
而且很不幸的是这里本应是游戏的高潮
And it's unfortunate because it really should be the climax,
结果却是这样平平无奇
but instead it just lands super flat.
看到这样的内容我还是挺惊讶的
I was really surprised to see this
因为通常顽皮狗是很擅长抓住游戏重点的
because usually Naughty Dog is pretty good about sticking the landing.
他们会在游戏结尾部分有各种天马行空的关卡
They go crazy, big and elaborate in the final sections of the game,
不管是《神海》系列还是上一代的TLOU
whether you're looking at Uncharted or even the original TLOU game
他们真的会把游戏的难度拉满
where they really push the boundary of difficulty.
到这个游戏里却不那样了
But here it just doesn't work.
即便如此 艾莉在杀了无数奴隶主后 还是找到了去沙滩的路
But even so, after killing countless slavers, Ellie finds her way to the beach.
几个被关起来的人告诉她
She's told by several other prisoners
这里就是埃比和勒弗在试图逃跑后被带到的地方
that this is where Abby and Lev have been moved after they tried to escape.
通常奴隶们会被带到这吊起来直到死
And usually the slaves are left here hung up until they die.
我得说到海滩之后这画面挺离谱的
And I gotta say it's pretty surreal once you reach this beach
艾莉看到的画面很令人不适
and what Ellie finds there is pretty upsetting.
艾莉：天……
埃比！
这里其实有个迷惑选项 就是这个有辫子的女孩
Now there's actually a fake out with the girl in the center that has the braid.
她看着很像埃比 尤其像我们上次见到她的样子
It looks like Abby, especially Abby the last time that we saw her.
但她并不是埃比
But it's not Abby.
真正的埃比其实你刚刚从她身边走过
Abby in fact, you just walked past.
她瘦得不成样子
And she's in much worse shape.
埃比：救我。
拜托了……
是你。
真的 看着像变了一个人一样
Truely, she doesn't even look like the same person.
埃比还花了一点时间才反应过来面前的是艾莉
Now it took a moment that Abby recognizes Ellie here,
但她完全没力气打架了
but she's not interested in fighting.
实际上 艾莉放下她之后 她就马上去救勒弗了
Instead, the moment that Ellie cuts her down, she goes to help Lev.
之后她拖着虚弱的身子抱着勒弗走向远方
Abby then carries Lev into the distance despite her weakness.
三人来到了每次打开游戏就能看到的那条船旁边
And they come up on the same boat
that we've seen in the title screen every time we booted up the game to this point.
即使到了现在 埃比也还一直在关心勒弗
Even now, Abby is purely concerned with taking care of Lev,
确保他们能逃到安全的地方
making sure that they are able to get out safely.
她还带艾莉来到了船边 帮助她逃离此处
She even leads Ellie to the boats to help her escape.
我知道艾莉是来杀她并实施最初的报仇的
I'm aware that Ellie has come to kill her
and enact the revenge that she sought out initially.
据我们所知 埃比应该以为艾莉也被抓去当奴隶
As far as we know, Abby may think that Ellie was being housed as a slave herself,
然后逃跑到这里来的
and has escaped to this point.
但无论如何
But whatever it may be,
埃比走到船边
Abby gets down to the boat area
艾莉身上还有树枝的刺伤
and Ellie still wounded from the tree branch that she was impaled with,
埃比则是经历了几周、几个月的折磨
and Abby, wounded from the weeks or months of torture,
在最后一刻 她们不得不在痛苦中进行这场最后的决战
at their very end, have to face off in one final painful battle.
艾莉：不，你会。
艾莉想要和埃比决斗 了结这一切
Ellie demands to fight with Abby to finish this once and for all.
她甚至拿她的弹簧刀威胁说如果埃比不和她打就杀死勒弗
She even takes out her switch blade and threatens to kill Lev if Abby doesn't engage with her.
埃比：他和这一切无关。
所以埃比别无选择
And so left with no choice,
艾莉：是你把他牵扯了进来。
只能和艾莉打 不为她自己 也不是为了艾莉 而是为了勒弗
Abby decides that she'll fight Ellie, not for her, not for Ellie, but for Lev.
埃比：好。
如果这段战斗给刚玩游戏的玩家看
If you show to player this fight scene at the very start of the game,
好
他们可能会感觉很爽
it would probably give them a lot of pleasure.
对玩家来说 把杀死乔尔的人砍成碎片的感觉很愉悦
It would feel good for the player to literally hack and slash the person that killed Joel to pieces.
但现在恰恰相反 感觉很糟糕、很可悲
But instead, it's absolutely horrible, it's pathetic.
我没有感觉到任何像是报应、或是正义之类的东西
And no part of this feels like a comeuppance or like justice.
真要说的话 这只能是游戏的叙事起作用了
And I think if anything, this means that the game's arc worked.
游戏的故事真的让我从想找杀死乔尔的凶手报仇
It actually went from me wanting to kill Joel's killer
变成想原谅她、想继续前进下去了
to wanting to forgive her and move on.
简单 但又有力
It's simple, but it's powerful.
随着这场战斗的继续 我唯一祈求的就是她们能停下来
And as this fight continued on, all I could ask for was that they would just stop.
但战斗仍在继续
But the fight continues,
两人都变得逐渐虚弱 直到战斗到了这必然的结局
each growing weaker and weaker until the fight comes to its inevitable conclusion.
艾莉：走。
带他走。
我们回到了农场的房子
We're now back at the farm house.
看上去已经过了好一阵 一切都显得荒凉不堪
It seems to have been quite a while, since everything is so dilapidated.
房子里空荡荡的 外墙漆也剥落了 木材也变形了
The house's empty, the paint chipping, the woods warped,
这一些都在告诉你 蒂娜已经和孩子搬走了
and I think all of this is meant to show that Dina moved out with the baby
艾莉现在孤身一人了
and that Ellie is now alone.
总之 这里已经很久没人来过了
But regardless, it's been quite a while since anyone's been here.
但是虽然现在艾莉看起来已经孤身一人
And so while it may be meant to show that Ellie is alone
而且她的行为造成的后果也比失去几根手指要严重得多
and that the ramifications for her actions
have taken much more of a toll than just the loss of a couple fingers.
但我觉得事情没那么简单
I think it might not be that simple,
相反 实际上我觉得这可能是比乍看起来更美好的结局
and this might actually be a happier ending than it might initially seem to be.
而我们之后会细讲这件事
But we'll get to that in just a few minutes.
艾莉走进空荡荡的房子
Ellie walks through the empty house,
最终来到应该是堆放艾莉旧物的房间
eventually coming into one room that has what seems to be most of Ellie's old things,
还有很多房子里整理来的乔尔的物品
and a lot of Joel's items that were collected throughout the house.
她拿起乔尔的吉他
She takes up Joel's guitar
蹩脚地弹起了乔尔在开场给她弹的那首歌
and plays a strained version of the song that he played for her in the beginning.
她那几根缺失的手指 现在成了她和乔尔之间再也无法触及的距离
Her missing fingers, now a permanent example of the distance between Joel and Ellie
两人的那份联系已荡然无存
and their inability to truly connect,
她甚至无法完整正确地弹出那首曲子了
she can't even play the song properly or fully now.
然后来到了整个游戏中最重要的画面
We then cut to the most important scene of the whole game.
一幅我花了几周字斟句酌也无法形容的场景
A scene that I couldn't do justice
even if I were to spend weeks riding it outward for word.
所以我还是直接放给大家看吧
So instead, I'm just going to let it play.
乔尔：嗨。
艾莉：你在喝什么？
乔尔：咖啡。
艾莉：哪里来的？
乔尔：哦，上周来的那些人给的。
艾莉：哦。
乔尔：虽然得用点东西才能换到这个颇尴尬的，但是……
味道不错。
艾莉：我能应付赛斯的。
乔尔：嗯，我知道。
艾莉：你也别再拿我巡逻的事去烦杰西了。
乔尔：好。
蒂娜。
她是你的女朋友吗？
艾莉：不是！
不是，她——
那只是一个吻而已。
不含任何意义。她只是……
我不知道她为什么要这样。
乔尔：你喜欢她。
艾莉：我太蠢了。
乔尔：听着，我不知道那个女孩有何意图，但是……
我知道如果她拥有你的话，她就太幸运了。
艾莉：你真是个混蛋！
乔尔：我的意思不是——
艾莉：我应该在那家医院里死掉才对。
那样我的生命才有意义。
但你剥夺了我的权利。
乔尔：如果上天给我第二次机会……
我还是会这么做。
艾莉：是啊……
我只是……
我想我永远都不会原谅你。
但我愿意试一试。
乔尔：我很高兴。
艾莉：好吧。
回头见。
乔尔：嗯。
游戏就这样结束了
And just like that, the game is over.
和游戏开场时的镜头一样
Closing in on the same shot that the game opened up with,
那时镜头聚焦在乔尔正在清洁的吉他
a focus on Joel's guitar as he was cleaning it at the very start,
一边清洁一边描述一代作品结尾在医院发生了什么
describing what happened the hospital at the end of the first game.
而游戏结尾则是艾莉将如何尝试去原谅乔尔
The last scene demonstrating how Ellie was going to try and forgive Joel
并度过未来没有乔尔的每个漫漫长夜
and move on the very night before his passing.
这段结尾也让玩家恍然大悟
The story reaches a surprising conclusion.
这也是为什么在视频开头
This is why, back at the beginning of the video,
我跟大家讲过 艾莉晚上要和乔尔看电影这件事是何其重要
I told you that Ellie wanting to have a movie night with Joel was so very important.
因为这将是两人重新建立感情的第一步
It was going to be their first step towards healing.
他们本打算冰释前嫌
They were going to try and bury the hatchet,
这也是为什么艾莉在失去乔尔后会如此悲痛欲绝
which is why Ellie was so unbelievably distraught
因为那晚她本该迈出与乔尔和好的第一步
when she lost Joel before this healing could take place.
但是看起来
But it seems as though,
在经过所有的沉思 所有的紧张
after all of this contemplation, all of this nervousness,
所有的压力 所有几个月来积累起来的仇恨过后
all of this stress, all of this hatred that had built up over months,
以及此时 经历了多年因失去乔尔所带来的痛苦后
and at this point, years of struggling with Joel's demise
艾莉意识到战胜这种悲伤的最好方式就是接受乔尔的离去 继续快乐地生活
that she's realized the best way to deal with that grief
is to accept that he's gone and to move on, living her life happily,
不是去整天寻求报仇
not seeking revenge,
而是与像乔尔一样爱她、在意她的人一起好好生活下去
but living it with people like Joel, who loved her, for her,
这样 她才能将她这份感受到的爱继续实践、传递下去
and where she could enact and practice that very same love and affection that she received.
随着艾莉慢慢走远
And as she walks off into the distance,
她终于放下了这一切 放下了所有乔尔留给她的物品
she's leaving everything behind, all of Joel's old items, everything that he left her.
她学会了往前看
She has moved on.
在经历了如此漫长的旅途过后
And it seems as though, after a very long journey,
乔尔和艾莉的故事 终于结束了
Joel and Ellie story has finally come to an end.
就这样 游戏结束了
And just like that the game is over.
真的 我在看结尾制作人员名单的时候我的思路完全是迷茫的
I mean, I really don't know
how to break down where my mind was when I first saw these credits roll.
我觉得总结这一切的最好方式就是与你们交谈
And I feel as though the best way to kind of wrap all of this up is by talking with you guys,
面对面不打草稿地交流 一边唠嗑一边总结
one on one in an unscripted way, or I can just wrap up all of my thoughts.
因为我觉得这个游戏太非同寻常了
Because I think that this game is truly exceptional,
真的是字面意义上的 超乎大家对游戏认知的非同寻常
again in the purest sense of the word, where it's an exception to the rule.
绝大多数游戏你可以轻松给出好评或者差评
Most games, you can give a thumbs up or thumbs down,
你可以说它很好 也可以说它很烂
you can say it's really good or it's really bad.
而我认为TLOU2是一款非常非常好的游戏
And TLOU2 is a game I think is very, very good.
我认为游戏性上体验很棒
It's an enjoyable game play experience, I think.
除了一点节奏问题外 大部分内容做得很好
For the most part, it works really well, except for some pacing issues.
但其中很多节奏上的问题主要是由叙事引起的
But a lot of those pacing issues are problematic, primarily because of the narrative
因为你又想专注于一个角色 又要在两个角色之间不断交换
because you want to focus on one character and you're having to keep swap between the two.
同时还有一些其他游戏内容上的节奏问题
But even so, there're some gameplay pacing issues,
比如游戏高潮内容的构建
such as having problems with climax building
最终Boss战的沉浸感和有趣程度的方面是有问题的
and making sure that the final boss fights are really intriguing and interesting, and things like that.
但对于游玩部分来讲 它仍然是个好游戏
But all told, as far as the game is concerned, it's very well done as a game,
很多对TLOU2不满的人
and most people who have a problem with TLOU2
也并不会否认这方面的问题
don't deny that they accepted and agree with it.
所以许多批评内容并不是指向这里的
So that doesn't seem to be where the criticisms tend to come out.
我发现我们很多人的批评最后都来自于……
I think we're most criticisms find themselves presented…
顽皮狗对于剧情方向上做出的选择
our with regards to the direction Naughty Dog chose to go in.
因为编剧们当然是有很多选择的
Because the writers, of course, had the option,
他们不需要非得做出某些选择
they didn't have to go the direction that they did.
他们不用非得让乔尔领便当
They didn't have to kill Joel off for one,
他们不用非得让你和埃比产生共鸣
they didn't have to make you empathize with Abby,
他们不用非得让你在游戏后半去操控埃比
they didn't have to make you play as Abby for the second half of the game,
很多都不是一定这样做才行的
they didn't have to do any of that.
但他们还是选择这样做了
But that's the direction they chose to go in.
而且我自己也能看得出
And I think as far as I can tell,
很多玩家最开始都以为、都期待游戏是完全关于艾莉的
most people were hoping and expecting that the game would be about Ellie,
确实如此
and that's it.
他们并不想去认识新的角色
They weren't interested in playing and getting to know this new character.
我想这正是大家的困扰所在
And I think that that's just the frustrating thing about it
许多玩家都期待着
is that a lot of people were hoping and expecting to
能够有更多和艾莉在一起的 不只是悲伤与绝望的经历
have exposure and experience with Ellie
that was not just dreadful through and through.
结果却发现玩家要陪着艾莉一起经历这种令人沮丧到心累的漫漫旅程
But instead they were forced to go through this very frustrating and
very emotionally taxing journey with her,
我觉得这正是我的观点的落脚点
which I think is probably where I land.
因为我真的非常非常喜爱艾莉这个角色 我关心她
Because I really cherish Ellie as a character, I care about her,
我觉得我和她产生了很深的羁绊
and I connected with her on a level,
我之前都没想到我会和一个游戏中的角色产生这种联系
I didn't realize I could connect with the character in the first game.
而她在第二部作品中的表现也是在实在让人心疼不起来
And her actions in the second game make her very difficult to sympathize with.
因为客观来看她的行为很愚蠢
Because she's doing things that are objectively pretty dumb and stupid
丝毫不为她自己和周围的人着想
that aren't for the betterment of her and the people around her.
她做的事情相当自私
She's being fairly selfish in what she's doing,
而且她对继续进行乔尔的复仇之旅有……有一种执念
and she does feel a… an obligation of sorts to Joel to continue on in her revenge journey.
但要注意 这和前作里乔尔的行为是不同的
But still, it's not the same as the actions of Joel in the first game
乔尔去救艾莉
where he goes after Ellie,
把她从火萤组织手里救出来的时候同样也杀了很多人
even though he's killing a lot of people to get to her and to save her from the Fireflies
and everything they are about to do to her.
至少大家能够明白乔尔在做什么 甚至会认同他的做法
At least there you can understand why he's doing it and you might even agreed
因为大家也很爱艾莉
because you care about Ellie too.
玩家可能会说自己太关心艾莉了
And you might say I care about her so much,
换我是乔尔 我也会做同样的事
I would probably do the same thing if I was in his shoes.
而在这个游戏中操控艾莉的时候 很多次我都在跟自己说
With Ellie in this game, many times, I found myself saying
“我肯定不会这样做”“这是错误的”“我可不敢苟同”
I would not have done that. That was the wrong choice, I don't agree with that.
正因为我关心艾莉 所以我才不同意她的行为
I care about you Ellie, and that's why I disagree with what you're doing.
她整个游戏都在进行自我毁灭、边缘人格化的、自杀式的任务
She's on a self destructive, borderline suicide mission throughout the entire game,
这让人很难同情她 甚至根本不会同情她
and that just makes it so hard to sympathize with her, if not impossible.
而当你不同情某个人的时候
And when you don't sympathize with somebody,
和那个人产生不了情感上的羁绊就不奇怪了
you shouldn't be surprised when people don't connect with them,
也因此 对于很多人来说
which is why, for a lot of people,
他们觉得自己玩的不是一款《最后生还者》游戏 甚至可以说它本身就不是
they found themselves feeling as though that this wasn't a TLOU game, even by itself.
这算不上是续作 而是一个独立出来的故事
It wasn't a sequel, it was a completely separate story.
艾莉已经长大了 已经不是之前那个她了
Ellie had grown up and become a different person,
已经无法与第一部里那个她相提并论了
and she was almost unrecognisable from the character she was in the first game,
所以顽皮狗才一直插入闪回剧情
which is why Naughty Dog keep springing up all these flashbacks
不断提醒大家 原来的艾莉是什么样的
to kind of remind you of what Ellie used to be like.
但那是不够的 因为你主要玩的还是当前的时间线
But that isn't enough, because you're playing in the current timeline.
如果当前时间线的艾莉不好玩 不值得同情 那你就不会关心她
And if that Ellie is not enjoyable, isn't sympathetic, and you don't care about her,
你就是不会关心她
you don't care about her.
于是问题来了
So when we bring up the question,
艾莉这个人物在本作中描写得够好吗？
whether or not Ellie is is a well written character in this story.
我认为就他们想要讲述的故事而言 写得很好
I think for the story they were trying to tell she was well written,
这个角色达成了顽皮狗的目的
and it accomplish the purpose which for Naughty Dog
即让你同情杀害你所爱所关心的角色的人
was to make you sympathize with somebody that killed a character you loved and cared about,
让你看到故事的另一面
to make you see the other side of the story,
看清不同的视角下的故事
to understand all the perspectives,
并明白有时暴力并不是答案
and to get that sometimes violence isn't the answer.
而有时可怕的事情换个角度看就变得合理了
And sometimes, terrible things happen and are somewhat justified.
或者当你被置于某种类似情境下的时候
Or that you could even find yourself in the shoes of that character doing that thing
你甚至可以发现自己有时也变成了那个角色 做着那样的事请
if you were put into some sort of like different circumstances, you know.
也因此我认为游戏的故事是有趣的
And I think that that's a really interesting story to tell.
而且我认为故事内容也是恰当的
And I think that's a fair story to tell.
而这就……每当我这样去思考这个游戏的时候
And that's… when I think of the game that way,
我就发现这个游戏竟然给我留下如此深刻的印象 感觉它绝对是个神作
I find myself much more impressed with it and thinking that it's absolutely a masterpiece.
但我觉得我的纠结之处在于 这是一款《最后生还者》系列的游戏
But I think my frustration is that it was a TLOU game.
他们为了这个故事不但牺牲了乔尔 还牺牲了艾莉
And that they sacrifice not just Joel but also Ellie at the altar of that story.
因为我认为他们搬上来一个新的故事
Because I don't think that creating new characters
从头到尾讲一个新角色的故事并不会达到前作那样的高度
and telling the story from start to finish with new characters would have been as successful.
这也是游戏的故事线——“原谅不可饶恕之事” 也是视频标题——的部分由来
”I think part of what makes that story arc of "Forgiving the Unforgivable", the title of this video.
我认为这也是使它令人印象深刻的部分原因
I think that's part… of what of what makes it so impressive is that
因为在玩游戏的时候 你面对的是你已经认识了近十年的人物
you are dealing with characters you've known effectively for a decade at this point.
到录制视频的时候是七年多
You've known for seven plus years,
等大家在看这个视频的时候肯定更久了
by the time you're watching this magnum for… for longer than that.
我认为这才是真正令人郁闷的
And I think that that's just what's really frustrating,
我能理解大家 制作组为了讲这个故事而牺牲了两个你喜欢的角色
but understandable is that they sacrifice these two characters that you love
for the sake of telling this story,
而且他们在发售前就保证过
when they reassured us prior to launch
他们正在做对这些角色最好的事情 他们不会抹黑这些角色
that they were doing what was best for the characters that they weren't going to do them dirty,
这是对乔尔和艾莉最好的安排
that this was what was best for Joel and Ellie,
如果他们觉得这个故事不合适 他们就不会制作这个游戏
and they wouldn't be making the game if they didn't feel as though it was the right story to tell.
所以我也能理解大家在这方面的沮丧
So I can understand the frustration on that end.
很多人也感到沮丧的是游戏似乎没有一个圆满的结局
A lot of people also are frustrated that the game doesn't seem to have a happy ending
艾莉失去了一切 然后继续前行下去
that Ellie lost everything then moves on.
她忘记了乔尔 忘记了蒂娜
Forgets Joel and forgets Dina,
抛弃了一切
and leaves everything behind and
也失去了一切
seemingly has lost everything hasn't gained, anything other than
把乔尔的东西留在农场的房子里 坦然面对乔尔的事情 继续向前看
maybe coming to grips and peace with what happened with Joel moving on,
leaving all of his stuff behind in the farmhouse.
但实际上我觉得这里隐藏着一个好结局
But I actually think that there's remnants of a happy ending here,
原因出自一个小细节
and it's something that's a small detail,
小到有很多人在推特和Discord上告诉我之后 我才真正发觉
and it's something I didn't really consider until a good number of people had tweeted it at me
and… had… mentioned it on Discord.
而且当我真的深入研究以后 简直都惊呆了
And it's something that once I started to investigate it, I was kind of blown away,
我觉得这套解释非常有意思
and I thought that it's actually really interesting theory.
在TLOU2核心故事的结尾 也就是艾莉和埃比对打那段
Because you see at the end of the core story of TLOU2 after Ellie and Abby have their fight out,
艾莉身上没有穿戴任何装饰品 她是赤手空拳被埃比拿下的
Ellie is not wearing any sort of adornment, she is bare arrested.
但再看她在游戏结尾的农场里时
But when you see her back at the farmhouse, in the final scene of the game,
她却戴着这样的一条手链
she's actually wearing this very bracelet,
有趣的是这条手链竟然还作为周边被收录在游戏的典藏版里
which is why it's interesting that they included it as part of the Collector's Edition.
但这其实是蒂娜的手链
This is actually Dina's bracelet that she has.
我刚说“竟然”是因为这只是一个很不起眼的小玩意 却被纳入典藏版里
And the one that they include here, I mean, it's just it's a crappy little Collector's Edition.
你们懂的 小饰品罢了 但还挺有意思的
You know, trinket, but it's still it's still fun.
问题在于 艾莉戴着它
But Ellie is wearing that.
艾莉还戴着它 即使艾莉看上去已经和蒂娜分道扬镳
And Ellie wearing it even though seemingly she's split up with Dina,
即使蒂娜已经远走他乡 和艾莉断了联系
And Dina moved away and has completely cut ties.
所以一种解释是
And the theory basically goes that
两人在很久以后又回到了这个房子 或者至少艾莉回来了
they've returned to the house after a good amount of time, at least Ellie has.
房子已经被被搬空了 而两人决定彻底搬离杰克逊小镇
The house is cleared out, and they've decided to completely move on from Jackson.
她们要搬走了 所以房子才看上去破烂不堪
They're moving out, which is why the house is much more dilapidated.
而艾莉决定把所有乔尔的东西留下 因为她决定要向前看
And Ellie has decided to leave all of Joel's things behind because she needs to move on,
所以她不想继续把这些东西留在身边
and she needs to stop bringing this with her.
因此 她戴着手链并不仅仅是意味着
And so her wearing of the bracelet isn't just meant
象征她仍然觉得与蒂娜有所羁绊
to symbolise that she still feels a connection with Dina,
或者她想念蒂娜 或者希望她反悔之类的
or that she misses Dina or wishes she had made a different decision.
而是在直接向玩家传达一个消息 即两人已经重新在一起了
But that it's actually a direct message that she and Dina are back together.
而她们决定一起继续抛弃过去 向前看
And that they've decided to move on together.
蒂娜已经原谅了艾莉 而且之后两人也幸福地生活在一起了
Dina has forgiven Ellie, and that they are effectively living happily ever after.
好吧 听着有点……可能有点离谱
Now is that a stretch, perhaps… perhaps.
TLOU的世界观里可没什么好结局的故事
Not many things in TLOU, at the world of TLOU, have happy endings.
但我还是认为游戏结束时的感情基调应该是令人振奋 阳光向上的
But I think the tone of the end of the game is very uplifting,
very bright and sunny.
而且游戏结束后回到标题画面 度假村也变成了阳光明媚的海滩
And the title screen at the end of the game goes back to a sunny beach right outside the Resort,
游戏到达了它的高潮
where the game reaches its climax,
我觉得也是在暗示同样的事情
which I think symbolizes the same thing.
这是一个阳光 美满的结局 天已经亮了
It's a bright, happy ending, morning has come.
黑暗之后总有光明 黑夜之后太阳总会升起
The light is always after the darkness, the sun has risen after night.
随便你想怎么比喻……
Use any analogy or simply you want.
所以
So,
我选择相信游戏结尾其实是个好结局
I'd like to think that the story actually has a happy ending,
艾莉、蒂娜和小宝宝最后幸福地在一起
and that Ellie and Dina and the baby all got back together.
隐居在某个小木屋里
And they're off living in some cabin in the middle of nowhere.
离开杰克逊小镇 继续生活
They've left Jackson and they've moved on
不再为这一切所困扰 拖累
and they're just not going to be burdened by any of this anymore.
至少我选择相信这样的解释
That's at least what I choose to believe,
因为我认为艾莉在经历这些后 值得有这样的生活
because I think Ellie deserves that ending after all of this,
因此我在了解到这样不同的解释后选择了相信
and so that's what I'm going to go with until I learn differently.
而且我觉得在最后的农场场景中给艾莉的手链一个镜头
And I think the fact that the designers included the bracelet on Ellie's wrist at that ending farm scene
也是在明摆着想告诉大家发生了什么
is directly indicative of that being what happened.
我觉得这可能是一个小小的暗示 想告诉大家其实结局还是美好的
I think it's a little nod, maybe a little hint-hint that things actually ended happily,
但谁知道呢？我倾向于好结局
but who knows? I'd like to think that things ended happily.
但总的来说 这个游戏是非常……
But all told, the game is very…
让人难顶的
difficult to come to terms with.
因为游戏内容完全不是玩家所期待甚至所希望的
Because it wasn't what I was expecting and perhaps even hoping for.
但即便如此 我认为他们也完成了我在视频之前所说的目标
But even so, I think it succeeded in what it was trying to do as I said earlier in the video.
即让玩家慢慢学会站在埃比这边
I think the mission was to get you to sympathize with Abby
通过翻转剧本 让玩家能从原来憎恨埃比变成后来开始关心她
and to flip the script so that you went from hating Abby to caring about her.
于是当你等到你曾咬牙切齿期盼的那个时刻
And so when you reach this conclusion that you initially had hoped for,
当你可以操控艾莉杀死埃比的时候 你的感受只剩空虚与失落
for Ellie to take on Abby and kill her, it feels empty and hollow and unsatisfying.
因为你意识到这已经不是简单的复仇的问题了
Because you realize that this isn't as simple as just revenge.
我认为这样一个叙事上的安排决策真的很了不起
And I think that that in and of itself as a narrative decision is truly remarkable.
真的 无论你喜欢与否 都应该为顽皮狗这如此大胆、风险极高决策点赞
It really is, whether you love it or hate it, you've got to give Naughty Dog credit
for having the balls to do something so unbelievably risky
风险高到会让无数粉丝出现两极分化的局面 会激怒无数人
that has obviously polarized the fan base, pissed off a lot of people.
我都能想象到游戏发售时他们收到了多少刀片
I can only imagine the hate mail that they've received since this went live,
但他们其实都知道 他们其实早有准备
but they knew that it would, they knew that it would.
但他们还是选择去做这样的事
And… they chose to do it anyways, when they didn't need to.
他们本可以制作一部内容烂大街的续作
They could have done just an obligatory, you know, sequel
让乔尔和艾莉踏上一段新的旅程
where Joel and Ellie embark on some new journey
或许安排让埃比杀死汤米 然后埃比被一路追杀
maybe Tommy gets murdered by Abby, and then they chase him down.
然后在结尾之前 埃比杀死了乔尔
And maybe right before the final scene, Abby kills Joel,
然后艾莉找埃比复仇 血债血偿
and then Ellie gets revenge on Abby, wipes her out.
就像《神秘海域》系列那样 最终一切都得到了清算
and it's kind of the Uncharted style ending where everything wraps up,
但某个角色领便当了
but a character died in it.
然后游戏让你更加珍惜现在所拥有的的一切
It makes you feel more appreciative of what you have,
顽皮狗完全可以做一个这样的剧情
and they could have done that.
他们完全可以走这条轻松的路
That would have been the easy way to go, though.
我觉得那样评价会更高 游戏体验也会更扎实
And while I think it would have been received well, the gameplay would have been really solid.
但我觉得这并不会让更多的人去思考
I don't think it would have challenged so many of us to think about
游戏中剧情的另一种叙述方式
video game narratives in a different way.
因为我曾经在这方面讲过很多年了
Because as I've said for many many years at this point
很多年大概指两到三年
and by many many years and be like two or three,
我认为游戏是叙述故事的一种进化
I think video games are the evolution of narrative storytelling.
我认为游戏是讲故事的一个非凡的工具
I think gaming is a remarkable tool, for storytelling.
我不禁觉得TLOU2这款游戏
And I can't help but feel as though TLOU2
让在游戏这个平台上讲故事的方式上有了巨大的飞跃
takes a huge leap forward in the types of stories that can and will be told on the platform,
尤其在迈向次时代的时期
especially moving into the next generation.
有些人可能会想那这也太惨了
Now some people think that that's terrible,
有些人听了会问 难道以后的故事都不能有一个幸福美满的结局了吗？
some people hear that, and they think why can't stories just end happily ever after nowadays?
以后所有游戏都要变得如此黑暗 如此沉闷 如此令人悲伤吗？
Everything's going to be so dark, everything so dreary, everything so sad.
然而对于某些故事来说的确就是这样
And while that's true for some stories,
而且我认为更多的是
I think more than anything,
应该尽量把叙事推到能发人深省的高度
it's just trying to push narratives to the point where they can be… thought provoking
只是很少有结局美满的故事能做到
in a way that very few happy go lucky stories are.
我很喜欢神秘海域系列
I enjoy Uncharted.
我给神海全系列都做过评测
I'm making a whole series of Uncharted critiques,
TLOU2发售之前我就在做这件事
and that's what I was doing before TLOU2 launched.
然后就又是一期期这样长的视频
And this whole video experience began.
但那些游戏故事并没有引人深思
But those stories don't really make you ponder, they don't make you think.
我玩神秘海域通关后 自己从来没有呆在那就……
I've never played an Uncharted game and then sat back and just…
“哇……刚刚那段是什么意思？我该怎么理解？”
Wow, what does this mean? What do I think of this?
我想不通 我脑中有太多矛盾在里面 想法情绪乱成一锅粥
I don't even know, I'm so conflicted, I have so many thoughts and emotions going on.
神海系列的情感部分主要是刺激的动作戏
Usually Uncharted's emotional repertoire consists of action and excitement,
偶尔会穿插一些你喜欢的两个角色之间轻佻戏谑的暖心时刻
and then maybe some light heartwarming moments
with some witty banter back and forth between two characters you like,
它就是这样的游戏
and that's kind of it.
我认为顽皮狗为了讲述一个更有意义的故事而在不断试探极限
I think Naughty Dog is trying to push the boundary, and tell a story that does a lot more than that.
而我觉得他们很成功
And I think they're successful,
我认为他们取得的成就相当了不起
and I think it's pretty remarkable what they've managed to accomplish.
因此尽管我对TLOU2的游戏节奏方面有所质疑
So while I am frustrated with TLOU2 for pacing issues,
因为游戏在两个角色的内容之间切换会让玩家失去游玩重心
for flip flopping back and forth between character so frequently that you start to lose focus,
但我仍然认为这是一款非凡的游戏
I do think that it's truly a remarkable game,
我认为这款游戏瑕不掩瑜
and I think it does far more good than it does bad.
偶尔一些内容的处理可能显得平淡无奇
And while a couple of things are handled kinda clinically
导致有些角色在我看来没有给玩家带来应有的触动
and I think some characters aren't as relatable as they were hoping,
比如欧文和梅尔
for instance, Owen and Mel.
他们遇害时 我能看出游戏希望我们能感受悲伤与自责
When they get killed, you're supposed to feel really bad as far as I can tell,
但我直到玩过埃比的部分后才切身感受到这一点
and I just even after playing through Abby sections, it just didn't really hit me hard.
我是在看到埃比的反应后才感觉悲伤与自责
What hit me hard with seeing Abby so upset about it,
并不是看到欧文和梅尔遇害才这样
it wasn't saying Owen and Mel killed that upset me.
我个人觉得顽皮狗在这块内容上是一个败笔
And I think that that's more a failure of Naughty Dogs writing than a success.
但我觉得他们不是有意的
I don't think that was intentional
就像我之前提到的那样
as I said earlier in the video.
但……总的来说
But… all told,
我觉得游戏仍然是很震撼的
I think the game is pretty amazing.
得出这个结论就花了我几个月、几周目的游玩时间
And it's taken me months of playing through it multiple times to come to that conclusion,
而且我跟大家说实话 我第一次通关以后完全不是……
and I'll tell you right now when I finished the game the first time I was not…
完全不是像我现在这样
I was not in the same place I am now.
我当时绝对不会说这是一个神作
I would not have said that I thought it was a masterpiece.
我绝对不会说这个游戏很震撼或者多么了不起
I would not have said that I thought it was amazing and remarkable.
我当时非常沮丧 思绪也很乱
I was pretty frustrated and emotionally torn apart,
但通关了几次之后 就像品味慢慢变了一样
but after playing through the game a couple more times it really is kind of like an acquired taste.
就像一款陈年老酒
It's like a fine wine or caviar or something.
这个游戏是那种……你越是投入进去
It's… it's something where the more that you engage with it,
就越能感受并欣赏到它所有小细节、所有情节和人物特点的游戏
the more you realize and appreciate all of the little details,
all of the interweaving plot lines and character arcs.
因此我觉得TLOU2这个游戏仍然是非凡的
And for that reason I think the game is truly remarkable.
它会是我心中的年度游戏吗？……不好说
Will it take my game of the year? I… I don't know.
我真心希望赛博朋克2077出来以后能震惊四座
原视频发布于2020年9月14日
I'm really hoping that Cyberpunk 2077 comes out and just blows us all away.
我真的很喜欢CDPR
I love CD Projekt Red,
而且从我看到的他们去年（2019年）E3上的闭门演示中来看
and from what I saw behind closed doors at E3 last year of Cyberpunk,
我觉得这个游戏有火的潜力
I think it has the possibility of being really impressive,
但我还是担心它会被宣发抬得太高
but I'm also worried that hype is getting out of control,
很可能会在这方面翻车
which is very possible with that game.
到时候再看吧 谁知道呢
But we'll see, who knows,
等大家看到这个视频的时候可能已经通关2077了
by the time you're watching this video, you've probably played through Cyberpunk,
而且可能通关了之后看这视频然后笑话我被打脸了
or you might have played through Cyberpunk, and you'll be laughing at what I'm saying,
或者这样那样……太可怕了 我什么都不知道！
or maybe they'll be like… Yeah, no, it is terrible, It's awful.
我可什么都不知道！
I have no idea, I have no idea.
但我可以肯定的是 TLOU系列为整个游戏行业的进步做了很多贡献
But what I can say is that I think TLOU does a lot to move the industry forward.
我认为他们所承担的风险真的是
I think that the risks that they took are truly…
“值得鼓掌的” 如果有这样的词的话
"applautable", if that's even a word.
我很欣赏他们敢于冒险的勇气
I appreciate that they took those risks that they didn't play it safe.
虽然我觉得可能很多人都希望他们去走另一条更好走的路
And while I think a lot of us probably wish, they had gone a different direction,
但我真的尊敬他们所作的一切 而且做的很棒
I respect the hell out of them for what they did, and I think it worked.
虽然换做是我我肯定不会这样做
And while I wouldn't have thought to go this direction,
但我很高兴他们做了
I'm… in the end, I think glad that they did.
但即使是现在 我也……非常矛盾
But even now, I am… I'm very conflicted.
我认为艺术的重点是激发人们的思考
And I think the point of art is to make you think to make you ponder.
在故事中发生的一切都在让你思考你在这个世界上的位置和正在发生的一切
Everything that went on in the story that was being told to ponder your place in this world
and everything that's going on.
而我认为TLOU2做到了其他游戏都没有做到的这一点
And I think TLOU2 does that, in a way that literally no game has ever done for me.
因此我真的想说 谢谢你 顽皮狗
And for that I just have to say thank you to Naughty Dog.
你们做的真的很棒 真的
They've done something truly incredible, truly.
我想说的就是这些了
So that's all from me.
感谢大家观看这期有一点点长的视频
Thank you for watching this monstrosity of a video.
我要感谢所有与我一起完成这期视频的人
At me and everybody that I've worked with on this video we truly appreciate it.
特别要感谢Jacob 我的编辑 为这期视频付出了许多努力
A big thank to Jacob, my editor for all of the hard work he's done on this video,
他为过去几小时的视频中的大量片段做了编辑工作
he's edited a lot of sections that you've seen and been watching for the last few hours, so…
非常感谢他 还有所有的赞助者 还有所有耐心看完视频的观众们
Big thanks to him, and thanked all of the patrons, and all of the viewers who have been so patient
因为制作这期视频花了我过去几个月的时间
because this has been the video that's eaten up all my time for the last few months
这段时间我还要准备婚礼 还要开始新的工作
as I was getting ready for a wedding, as I was starting a new job.
花了我相当相当多的时间
This is consumed all of my time.
虽然我认为TLOU2还有很多做的很棒的地方
And while I think TLOU2 was incredible in a lot of ways,
但我……我觉得该瞄准下一个项目了
I'm… I am ready to move on and to tackle the next big thing, so…
到了结尾还事无巨细都讲的话就太怪了
It's bizarre to be done with everything, it's bizarre to be at the end of this video.
所以希望大家能喜欢这期视频
I hope that you enjoyed it.
如果真的喜欢 那恳请大家点个赞
If you did, please at the very least hit the like button.
或者再点个关注
If you really enjoyed it, hit the subscribe button.
我倒不是想王婆卖瓜
I don't mean to sound entitled,
但看了这么久你还是很喜欢这期视频的话
but after all of this, if you really did enjoy this video and got to this point,
那我觉得你肯定会关注的
I would like to think that you would, at the very least, subscribe
或者再点个小铃铛加个特别关注就更好了 这样每次更新会有提示
and maybe even ring the bells so to get notified of the next video.
真的 感谢大家
But truly, thank you.
感谢大家的观看
Thank you for watching.
感谢大家的分享与转发
Thank you for sharing the video.
感谢大家的赞助 感谢大家做的一切
Thank you for donating thanks for doing everything that you guys do.
你们真的很棒 感谢你们 我爱你们所有人
You're truly amazing and I love you all more than you could possibly know.
我们下期视频再见吧 下期视频可能会稍微短一点点了
I'll see you in the next video, which will probably be a fair amount, shorter.
真的 谢谢大家
Truly, thank you,
我爱你们
I love you guys,
我们下期视频见
and I'll see you in the next video.
拜拜
Bye bye.